what is the right intention with wanting to
व्हाट इज द राइट इंटेंशन विथ वांटिंग टू
do this? You should be ready to die too late.
डू दिस? यू शुड बी रेडी टू डाई टू बी देर।
No God Realization Can Happen Without You Die
नो गॉड रियलाइजेशन कैन हपेन विदाउट यू डाई
S an ego.
एस अ ईगो।
Explain what chakras and chakras mean
एक्सप्लेन व्हाट चक्रास आर चक्र मींस
Wheel. something that is moving constantly
व्हील। समथिंग दैट इज मूविंग कॉन्स्टेंटली
and propelling. so these seven chakras in our
एंड प्रपेलिंग। सो दीज़ सेवन चक्रास इन आवर
There are seven energy points in the body that are
बॉडी आर सेवन एनर्जी पॉइंट्स दैट आर
actually distributing the cosmic
एक्चुअली डिस्ट्रीब्यूटिंग द कॉस्मिक
The energy that we are receiving. it's god
एनर्जी दैट वी आर रिसीविंग। इट्स गॉड
Created.
क्रिएटेड।
Vampire is as powerful as the universe
पिशाच इज एस पावरफुल एस द यस द यूनिवर्स
is equally divided between white and black
इज इक्वली डिवाइडेड बिटवीन वाइट एंड ब्लैक
It has to be so the vampire power it's kind
इट हैज़ टू बी सो द पिशाच शक्ति इट्स काइंड
of almost like parasitic on someone it
ऑफ़ ऑलमोस्ट लाइक पैरासिटिक ऑन समवन इट
makes a person victim and to death it will
मेक्स अ पर्सन विक्टिम एंड टू डेथ इट विल
Not Leave What the Western World Calls
नॉट लीव व्हाट द वेस्टर्न वर्ल्ड कॉल्स
Vampires They Thrive and Survive on the
वैंपायर्स दे थ्राइव एंड सर्वाइव ऑन द
prana of living beings were you
प्राणा ऑफ लिविंग बीइंग्स वेयर वुड यू
Place Satan in this anywhere
प्लेस सेटन इन दिस कहीं भी डाल
The Moment You Catch Yourself Going In
द मोमेंट यू कैच योरसेल्फ गोइंग गोइंग इन
any variation of moods start immediately
एनी वेरिएशन ऑफ मूड्स इमीडिएटली स्टार्ट
Doing Japa. even if you for the one of it you
डूइंग जपा। इवन इफ यू फॉर द एक ऑफ इट यू
From Om Namah Shivay. Om Namah Shivay. even if you
से ओम नमः शिवाय। ओम नमः शिवाय। इवन इफ यू
Don't mean it. it will still connect you to the
डोंट मीन इट। इट विल स्टिल कनेक्ट यू टू द
Relm. And not allow you to fall down. So
रेलम। एंड नॉट अलाउ यू टू फॉल डाउन। सो
there are siddhis packed into each one of our
देयर आर सिद्धिस पैक्ड इंटू इच वन ऑफ़ आवर
Bodies. Yes yes. what is an understanding
बॉडीज। यस यस। व्हाट इज़ एन अंडरस्टैंडिंग
Siddhi that you can talk about. Vaakas Siddhi
सिद्धि दैट यू कैन टॉक अबाउट। वाकस सिद्धि
Is the power of speech. Manifestation Some People
इज़ द पॉवर ऑफ़ स्पीच। मैनिफेस्टेशन सम पीपल
Have no manifesting power than others. The
हैव नो मैनिफेस्टिंग पॉवर देन अदर्स। द
Tails here get activated. give gate
टेल्स हियर गेट एक्टिवेटेड। दे गेट
Divinize. whatever you say it becomes the
डिविनाइज। व्हाटएवर यू से इट बिकमस द
Power. a command that the universe to
पॉवर। अ कमांड दैट द यूनिवर्स टू
Accept.
एक्सेप्ट।
I have understood that he is this human life
आई हैव अंडरस्टुड दैट हे दिस ह्यूमन लाइफ
That we know is fully conditions. is it
दैट वी नो इज फुल्ली कंडीशन्स। इज इट्स
Redundant is fatal. it's al drama and its
रेडन्ट इज फटाइल। इट्स अल ड्रामा एंड इट्स
all a waste of
आल अ वेस्ट ऑफ़
[Laughter]
[हंसी]
Time. In the last one year. this guest has
टाइम। इन द लास्ट वन ईयर। दिस गेस्ट हैज़
Been One of Our Most Loved Spirituals
बीन वन ऑफ़ आवर मोस्ट लव्ड स्पिरिचुअल
Guests. It's all about the Ora She
गेस्ट्स। इट्स ऑल अबाउट द ओरा शी
Brings, it's all about the practical
ब्रिंग्स, इट्स ऑल अबाउट द प्रैक्टिकल
The Experience She Brings and It's All
एक्सपीरियंस शी ब्रिंग्स एंड इट्स ऑल
About the Tantric Vidya, the knowledge that she
अबाउट द तांत्रिक विद्या, द नॉलेज दैट शी
Brings to the conversations. Today We Deep
ब्रिंग्स टू दी कन्वर्सेशंस। टुडे वी डीप
Dive into ten Mahavidya concepts which
डाइव इंटू दस महाविद्या कॉन्सेप्ट व्हिच
We have it covered on the channel. Butt mother knowledge
वी हैव कवर्ड ऑन द चैनल। बट मां ज्ञान
Subra brings her own spin to it. it's
सुबरा ब्रिंग्स हर ओन स्पिन टू इट। इट्स
Always almost therapeutic talking to mother.
ऑलवेज ऑलमोस्ट थेरेपुटिक टॉकिंग टू मां।
and i hope you feel the same way by the end of
एंड आई होप यू फील द सेम वे बाई दी एंड ऑफ़
The Episode. gyan sura on TRS
द एपिसोड। ज्ञान सुरा ऑन टी आर एस
[music]
[संगीत]
Welcome back mother. Thank you Ranveer. we have
वेलकम बैक मां। थैंक यू रणवीर। वी हैव
taken an our long break since the last
टेकन एन आवर लॉन्ग ब्रेक सिंस द लास्ट
recording and people have got to know what
रिकॉर्डिंग एंड पीपल हैव गॉटन टू नो व्हाट
you are about. We are so thankful to you for being in
यू आर अबाउट। हम सो थैंक यू फॉर बीइंग इन
Our Studio. Again. Thank You We Have Created
आवर स्टूडियो। अगेन। थैंक वी हैव क्रिएटेड
Two Incredibly Deep Episodes About Dash
टू इनक्रेडिबली डीप एपिसोड्स अबाउट दश
Mahavidyas vs Dr Vineet Agarwal &
महाविद्यास वि डॉ विनीत अग्रवाल एंड
rajshree nandhi sir and both approach this
राजश्री नंदी सर एंड बोथ अप्रोच दिस
subject from two different angles or for
सब्जेक्ट फ्रॉम टू डिफरेंट एंगल्स या फॉर
The Sake of Research for Our Podcast I Went
द सेक ऑफ रिसर्च फॉर आवर पडकास्ट आई वेंट
through a speech that you have given about the
थ्रू अ स्पीच दैट यू हैव गिवेन अबाउट द
Mahavidyas. ah and you spoke about how
महाविद्यास। अह एंड यू स्पोक अबाउट हाउ
It's link to the chakras within the human
इट्स लिंक टू द चक्रस विद इन द ह्यूमन
Body as well. you also began by speaking
बॉडी एज़ वेल। यू आल्सो बिगेन बाई स्पीकिंग
About Kali Maa and Tara Maa and one more
अबाउट काली मां एंड तारा मां एंड वन मोर
Ah Shorshi Shorshish
अह शोरशी शोरशिष
That's a goddess that I have not heard about
दैट्स अ गॉडेस दैट आई हैव नॉट हर्ड अबाउट
tripura sundari ok god job under its same
त्रिपुर सुंदरी ओके गॉड जॉब अंडर इट्स सेम
Thing | Yeah | Allright | I will actually
थिंग | याह | ऑलराइट | आई विल एक्चुअली
hand it over to you because there was a lot
हैंड इट ओवर टू यू बिकॉज़ देयर वाज़ अ लॉट
of parts of diet speech which i found
ऑफ़ पार्ट्स ऑफ़ ड्याट स्पीच व्हिच आई फाउंड
Extremely Fascinating But A Lot Of
एक्सट्रीमली फैसनेटिंग बट अ लॉट ऑफ़
Places Where I Wanted to Ask You More
प्लेसेस वेर आई वांटेड टू आस्क यू मोर
Questions. so i am getting to do that
क्वेश्चन्स। सो आई एम गेटिंग टू डू दैट
Today. hoon al let you begin today's episode
टुडे। हूं अल लेट यू बिगिन टुडेज एपिसोड
bye either beginning wherever you want or a
बाय अ इदर बिगनिंग व्हेरएवर यू वांट ओर अ
Chant the mantra Ah completely up to you so sincere
मंत्र जाप अह कंप्लीटली अप टू यू सो सिंस
it is dedicated to the mahavidyas will do a
इट इज डेडिकेटेड टू द महाविद्यास विल डू अ
Small Mantras of the Mahavidyas
स्माल मंत्र ऑफ द महाविद्यास
Om Shri Mahaganap
ओम श्री महागणप
Namah Kali Tara Mahavidya Shodashi
नमः काली तारा महाविद्या शोडशी
Bhuvaneshwari Bhairavi Symbol Mastach Vidya
भुवनेश्वरी भैरवी चिन्ह मस्ताच विद्या
Dhumavati and
धूमवती तथा
Bagla Siddha Vidya Cha Matangi
बगला सिद्ध विद्या च मातंगी
Kamalatmika Yeta Dash Maha Vidya Siddha
कमलात्मिका येता दश महा विद्या सिद्ध
Knowledge
विद्या
Prakirtita Yeta Dash Maha Vidya Gupta
प्रकीर्तिता येता दश महा विद्या गुप्त
Vidya Kirtita
विद्या प्रकीर्तिता
Om
ओम
Why the Mahavidyas are Hidden
व्हाई गुप्त विद्या द महाविद्यास आर हिडन
They are fierce forces past form of
दे आर फियर्स फोर्सेस पस्ट फॉर्म ऑफ
Energy
एनर्जी
When the Creation Happened
व्हेन द क्रिएशन हैपेंड एंड
When Consciousness is the Immovable Consciousness
व्हेन कॉन्शियसनेस द इमूवेबल कॉन्शियसनेस
begin the churning the pulsation of energy and
बिगेन द चर्निंग द स्पंदन ऑफ एनर्जी एंड
Shivan Shakti Spandan Started the Force That
शिवान शक्ति स्पंदन स्टार्टेड द फोर्स दैट
came out mahashakti we call it adi shakti in
केम आउट महाशक्ति वी कॉल इट आदि शक्ति इन
The Mahavidya Tradition We Call It Adi Shakti
द महाविद्या ट्रेडिशन वी कॉल इट आदि शक्ति
So this Adi Shakti is stand alone energy
सो दिस आदि शक्ति इज़ स्टैंड अलोन एनर्जी
back by consciousness of course back by the
बैक बाय कॉन्शियसनेस ऑफ़ कोर्स बैक बाय द
The power of Shiva of course but it stands alone
पावर ऑफ़ शिवा ऑफ़ कोर्स बट इट स्टैंड अलोन
Enter it has a masculine and feminine
एनट्री इट हैज़ अ मैस्कुलाइन एंड फेमिनाइन
Polarity in one Mahavidyas are not have
पोलरिटी इन वन महाविद्यास आर डोंट हैव
Concerts in the Present Day Time in the
कॉन्सर्ट्स इन द प्रेजेंट डे टाइम इन द
present study of mahavidyas in the
प्रेजेंट स्टडी ऑफ़ महाविद्यास इन द
In present era we do have a form of shiva
प्रेजेंट एरा वी डू हैव अ फॉर्म ऑफ़ शिवा
With every mahavidya we do have a form of
विथ एव्री महाविद्या वी डू हैव अ फॉर्म ऑफ़
even vishnu in corresponding to every ah
इवन विष्णु इन करेस्पोंडिंग टू एव्री अह
Mahavidya however in the history of
महाविद्या हाउएवर इन द हिस्ट्री ऑफ़
Maha Vidyas There Are Stand Alone Powers
महाविद्यास देयर वर स्टैंड अलोन पावर्स
Without the need of a concert without the need
विदाउट द नीड ऑफ़ अ कॉन्सर्ट विदाउट द नीड
Need of another. so that means that it was a
नीड ऑफ़ अनदर। सो दैट मींस दैट इट वाज़ अ
Complete Amalgamation and Culmination of
कंप्लीट एमल्गमेशन एंड कलमिनेशन ऑफ़
The Perfect Unison of the Masculine End
परफेक्ट यूनिसोन ऑफ़ द मैस्कुलाइन एंड
Feminine Polarity. that is why they are so
फेमिनाइन पोलरिटी। दैट इज़ व्हाई दे आर सो
Am they are so filigree looking. they are so
अम दे आर सो फाइली लुकिंग। दे आर सो
Natural and raw to look at you don't see
नेचुरल एंड रॉ टू लुक एट यू डोंट सी
Mahavidyas deck up and rest up. We Do
महाविद्यास डेक अप एंड रेस्ट अप। वी डू
Them for our worship. we deck them up like
देम फॉर आवर वरशिप। वी डेक देम अप लाइक
goddess but there are huge portals of
देवीज़ बट देयर आर ह्यूज पोर्टल्स ऑफ़
Energy. Starting from Mahakali Mahakali
एनर्जी। स्टार्टिंग फ्रॉम महाकाली महाकाली
so in our tradition and if i can speak a
सो इन आवर ट्रेडिशन एंड इफ आई कैन स्पीक अ
Little about the Mahaganapati sect that I
लिटल अबाउट द महागणपति संप्रदाय दैट आई
Belong to We Have a Dasha Maha Dashabhuja Ganesha
बिलोंग टू वी हैव अ दश महा दशभुजा गणेशा
In Our Hermitage In Rishikesh 10 Dashbhuja That
इन आवर हर्मिटेड इन ऋषिकेश 10 दशभुजा दैट
means 10 arms a ganesha v 10 arms and
मींस 10 आर्म्स अ गणेशा वि 10 आर्म्स एंड
A Devi Sing in Ha Lap So The Sect
अ देवी सिंग इन ह लैप सो द संप्रदाय द
Guru and the teachers who are there in many
गुरु एंड द टीचर्स हु वर देयर इन मेनी
Life Times They Have Been Dedicated to Both
लाइफ टाइम्स दे हैव बीन डेडिकेटेड टू बोथ
The Study and Worship of Ganesha and Devi
द स्टडी एंड वरशिप ऑफ गणेशा एंड देवी
Which is why I happen to be the blessed
व्हिच इज व्हाई आई हैपन टू बी द ब्लेस्ड
one to receive both these sadhanas ah parallelly
वन टू रिसीव बोथ दीज़ साधनाज़ अह पैरेललली
you know and dasha mahavidya comes in the oral
यू नो एंड दश महाविद्या कम्स इन द ओरल
tradition we don't have much of infatuation there
ट्रेडिशन वी डोंट हैव मच ऑफ़ इनफेशन देयर
is the mythological ination which talks about the
इज़ पौराणिक इनेशन व्हिच टॉक्स अबाउट द
Shakti Manifesting Durga Manifesting
शक्ति मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग दुर्गा मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग
as this and that is a part that's a lot
एज़ दिस एंड दैट इज़ अ पार्ट दैट्स अ मच
Letter
लेटर
Inception in its origin is the ten Mahavidyas
इनेशन इन इन इट्स ओरिजिन दश महाविद्यास
Arb Absolute Crew Run Raw Energy
आरब अब्सोल्यूट क्रू रन रॉ एनर्जी
Starts with Mahakali and She Manifest
स्टार्ट्स विद महाकाली एंड शी मैनिफेस्ट
As the three gunas you know the universe
एज द थ्री गुणास यू नो द यूनिवर्स
starts the creation of the universe
स्टार्ट्स द क्रिएशन ऑफ़ द यूनिवर्स
starts with the creation of the Gunas the
स्टार्ट्स विथ द क्रिएशन ऑफ़ द गुणास द
The three Gunas are created first then the
थ्री गुणास आर क्रिएटेड फर्स्ट देन द
Panchamahabhutas and then the Punshikaran of the
पंचमहाभूताज़ एंड देन द पंशीकरण ऑफ़ द
Panchamahabhootas gives you the gross
पंचमहाभूताज़ गिव्स यू द ग्रॉस
Manifestation of this whole creation. What
मैनिफ़ेस्टेशन ऑफ़ दिस होल क्रिएशन। व्हाट
Are you the Three Mahagunas? The Three Gunas Are The Sat
आर द थ्री महागुणास? द थ्री गुणास आर द सत
Rajas and Tamas. Ok. So Mahakali Adishakti
रजस एंड तमस। ओके। सो महाकाली आदिशक्ति
Manifest as Kali the sum total of Tamas in
मैनिफेस्ट एस काली द सम टोटल ऑफ़ तमस इन
This World Parallel to Shiva and Tara
दिस वर्ल्ड पैरेलल टू शिवा एंड तारा द
Sattva Complete White. and shodshi the
सत्वा कंप्लीट वाइट। एंड शोडशी द
Red. Kali is the black, Tara is the white.
रेड। काली इज़ द ब्लैक, तारा इज़ द वाइट।
Shodashi is the red one. and they give you when
शोडशी इज़ द रेड। एंड दे व्हेन यू
understand like you said you heard a talk that
अंडरस्टैंड लाइक यू सेड यू हर्ड अ टॉक दैट
I go on chakra relationship. it's not
आई गव ऑन चक्र रिलेशनशिप। इट्स नॉट
Directly Chakra Relationship But Easier To
डायरेक्टली चक्रा रिलेशनशिप बट इज़ियर टू
Understand from that point of view. So
अंडरस्टैंड फ्रॉम दैट पॉइंट ऑफ़ व्यू। सो
when you see the seven worlds the chakras are
व्हेन यू सी दी सेवन लोकाज़ द चक्राज़ आर
Lockjaw. seven worlds beyond these seven worlds
लोकाज़। सेवन लोकाज़ बियन्ड दीज़ सेवन लोकाज़
there are these three realms where the control of
देयर आर दीज़ थ्री लोकाज़ वेयर द कंट्रोल ऑफ़
Gunas and control of all activity on
गुणास एंड कंट्रोल ऑफ़ ऑल एक्टिविटी ऑन
Earth is happening. Ok. we will we will have
अर्थ इज़ हैपेनिंग। ओके। वी विल वी विल हैव
To pause it a little. Yes. so you are saying at
टू पॉज इट अ लिटिल। यस। सो यू आर सेइंग एट
The start there were three gunas. Yes. Which
द स्टार्ट देयर वर थ्री गुणास। यस। व्हिच
can be understood to be representing the
कैन बी अंडरस्टुड टू बी रिप्रेजेंटिंग द
Three Goddesses That You Just Need. Yes. so three
थ्री देवीज़ दैट यू जस्ट नीड। यस। सो थ्री
The Mahavidya Tradition Says There Are Three
द महाविद्या ट्रेडिशन सेस देयर आर थ्री
above the crown there are three above the crown
अबव द क्राउन देयर आर थ्री अबव द क्राउन
there are three points where these three gunas
देयर आर थ्री पॉइंट्स वेयर दीज़ थ्री गुणास
are controlling all the life on earth kali
आर कंट्रोलिंग ऑल द लाइफ ऑन अर्थ काली
being the total of black tara being some
बीइंग द सम टोटल ऑफ़ ब्लैक तारा बीइंग सम
The Total of White and the Shodashi Being Some Total
टोटल ऑफ़ वाइट एंड द शोडशी बीइंग सम टोटल
of the red so there names also infact have
ऑफ़ द रेड सो देयर नेम्स आल्सो इनफैक्ट हैव
Interpretations Visavi Diz Gunas Visavi Di So
इंटरप्रिटेशंस विसवी दीज़ गुणास विसवी द सो
Kali Itself Means Dark Darkness Total
काली इटसेल्फ मींस डार्क डार्कनेस टोटल
Total darkness out of which everything was
टोटल डार्कनेस आउट ऑफ व्हिच एवरीथिंग वाज़
Born. there was total darkness out of
बोर्न। देयर वाज़ टोटल डार्कनेस आउट ऑफ
Which all has been created. so everything
व्हिच ऑल हैज़ बीन क्रिएटेड। सो एवरीथिंग
comes she is she is a keen to she is parallel
कम्स शी इज़ शी इज़ अ कीन टू शी इज़ पैरेलल
To Adi Shakti. she is adi shakti and she is the
टू आदि शक्ति। शी इज़ आदिशक्ति एंड शी इज़ द
The beginning of creation. so it's like
बिगिनिंग ऑफ़ क्रिएशन। सो इट्स लाइक
Creation, Sustenance, Resolution and
क्रिएशन, सस्टेनेंस, रेजोल्यूशन एंड
Involution. The Cycle Starts With Her
इनवोल्यूशन। द साइकिल स्टार्ट्स विद हर
And ends with her. everything emerges out
एंड एंड्स विद हर। एवरीथिंग इमर्ज आउट
From her and fun back in her. this is
फ्रॉम हर एंड मजेस बैक इनू हर। दिस इज
what the
व्हाट द
Mahavid Sadhna Teaches Us. so from kali
महाविद साधना टीचेस अस। सो फ्रॉम काली
comes out the white aspect which is
कम्स आउट द वाइट आस्पेक्ट व्हिच इज़
Education Tara which is education, beauty,
एजुकेशन तारा व्हिच इज़ एजुकेशन, ब्यूटी,
Harmony,
हार्मोनी,
Simplicity, Music, Art, Everything and
सिंपलीसिटी, म्यूजिक, आर्ट, एवरीथिंग एंड
then shodshi which is which is like
देन शोडशी व्हिच इज व्हिच इज लाइक
Absolute grandeur and royalty that
अब्सोल्यूट ग्रैंडर एंड रॉयल्टी दैट
Human beings derive their name from Earth. De Direve
ह्यूमन बीइंग्स डिर्व ऑन अर्थ। दे डिर्व
Royalty and Grand that's why she is more
रॉयल्टी एंड ग्रैंड दैट्स व्हाई शी इज मोर
Popular What We Call Sri Vidya What We
पॉपुलर व्हाट वी कॉल श्री विद्या व्हाट वी
call sri vidya s different sect and
कॉल श्री विद्या एस डिफरेंट संप्रदाय एंड
Different schools are teaching Shri Vidya is
डिफरेंट स्कूल्स आर टीचिंग श्री विद्या इज़
Nothing But The Activation Of Shodashi Shodashi
नथिंग बट द एक्टिवेशन ऑफ़ शोडशी शोडशी
Representing all the so each of the Mahavidyas
रिप्रेजेंटिंग ऑल द सो ईच ऑफ़ द महाविद्यास
Is practiced by different sects
इज़ प्रैक्टिस्ड अह बाय डिफरेंट संप्रदाय
Differently one Mahavidya is picked up for
डिफरेंटली वन महाविद्या इस पिक्ड अप फॉर
Instance We Have Sects That Are Only Inu
इंस्टेंस वी हैव संप्रदाय दैट आर ओनली इनू
Kali worship so Kali here is
काली उपासना सो काली हियर इज़
representing all the
रिप्रेजेंटिंग ऑल द
Similarly in the Tara has gone more to the
सिमिलरली इन द तारा हैज़ गॉन मोर टू द
Buddhism. Tara has traveled more to the
बुद्धिज्म। तारा हैज़ ट्रेवल्ड मोर टू द
Buddhist Tradition. there also you are
बुद्धिस्ट ट्रेडिशन। देयर आल्सो यू आर
White Tara, Black Tara, Red Tara, Blue
वाइट तारा, ब्लैक तारा, रेड तारा, ब्लू
Tara, Green Tara. Tara is representing
तारा, ग्रीन तारा। तारा इज़ रिप्रेजेंटिंग
all the end which is the shri which is
ऑल द एंड शोडशी व्हिच इज़ द श्री व्हिच इज़
Also called Tripura Sundari.
आल्सो कॉल्ड त्रिपुर सुंदरी।
Rajarajeswari. Right? this goddess is
राजराजेश्वरी। राइट? दिस देवी इज़
Representing the total of goddesses and twos
रिप्रेजेंटिंग द सम टोटल ऑफ़ देवीज़ एंड दोज़
who are doing the sadhana and upasana, they
हु आर डूइंग द साधना एंड उपासना, दे
Realize all the levels of this Goddess. Same S
रियलाइज़ ऑल द लेवल्स ऑफ़ दिस देवी। सेम एस
Kamakhya Devi Same S Kamakhya Devi
कामाख्या देवी सेम एस कामाख्या देवी
Kamakhya Devi is Kali personified it
कामाख्या देवी इज इज काली परसोनिफाइड इट्स
It's Kali basically and in the Kamakhya Devi
इट्स काली बेसिकली एंड इन द कामाख्या देवी
temple you find the pandits will tell you that
टेंपल यू फाइंड दे पंडित्स विल टेल यू दैट
this is there is lakshmi here and there is
दिस इज़ देयर इज़ लक्ष्मी हियर एंड देयर इज़
saraswati here basically it is shodashi antara
सरस्वती हियर बेसिकली इट इज़ शोडशी अंतारा
There it is sodash antara over there and then
देयर इट इज़ सोडश अंतारा ओवर देयर एंड देन
on that hill guwahati the way kamakhya is all
ऑन दैट हिल गुवाहाटी द वे कामाख्या इज़ ऑल
are the mahavidyas are there all the temples of
आर द महाविद्यास आर देयर ऑल द टेंपल्स ऑफ़
the mahavidyas are there so it is a
द महाविद्यास आर देयर सो इट इज़ अ इट इज़ अ
Representation of the Whole Culmination of All
रिप्रेजेंटेशन ऑफ द होल कलमिनेशन ऑफ ऑल
Goddess Merging Inu Kali Inu Kamakhya Again
देवी मर्जिंग इनू काली इनू कामाख्या अगेन
to understand this better i have a personal
टू अंडरस्टैंड दिस बेटर आई हैव अ पर्सनल
question yes i am born in 1993 and i
क्वेश्चन यस आई एम बोर्न इन 1993 एंड आई
Spent a majority of the 90s watching
स्पेंट अ मेजोरिटी ऑफ़ द 90ज वाचिंग
television and watching the ancient shows and
टेलीविज़ एंड वाचिंग दी पुराणिक शोज़ एंड
that's my first education about what we
दैट्स माय फर्स्ट एजुकेशन अबाउट व्हाट वी
no such sanatan dharma yes one i had never heard
नो एस सनातन धर्म यस अ आई हैड नेवर हर्ड
About the Mahavidyas till I turn 28
अबाउट द महाविद्यास अंटिल आई टर्न 28 मे
B and I had someone on the show talk about yes
बी एंड आई हैड समवन ऑन द शो टॉक अबाउट यस
so why did this knowledge visit me
सो व्हाई डिडट दिस दिस नॉलेज विजिट मी
When I was a kid. it is not visit many
व्हेन आई वाज अ किड। इट इज़ नॉट विजिट मेनी
Of the people not just you. Mahavidyas There
ऑफ़ द पीपल नॉट जस्ट यू। महाविद्यास देयर
For have been here. They are very powerful.
फॉर हैव बीन गो हियर। दे आर वेरी पावरफुल।
Extra Ordinarily Powerful and a Person
एक्स्ट्रा ऑर्डिनरीली पावरफुल एंड अ पर्सन
Can become stand alone energy. if you are if
कैन बिकम स्टैंड अलोन एनर्जी। इफ यू आर इफ
You get into the worship of Mahavidyas then you
यू गेट इंटू द वरशिप ऑफ़ महाविद्यास देन यू
Acquire The Shivaay And The Shakti Principle
एक्वायर द शिवाय एंड द शक्ति प्रिंसिपल
Both active and equal. and you stand alone
बोथ एक्टिव एंड इक्वल। एंड यू स्टैंड अलोन
then you don't require anything else in this
देन यू डोंट रिक्वायर एनीथिंग एल्स इन दिस
World. it's like the other in me has
वर्ल्ड। इट्स लाइक द अदर इन मी हैज़
Dissolved in me. and i am a stand
डिसॉल्व्ड इन मी। एंड आई आई एम अ स्टैंड
Alone Energy. So from the Sanatana Dharma Point
अलोन एनर्जी। सो फ्रॉम द सनातन धर्म पॉइंट
of view from the society point of view
ऑफ व्यू फ्रॉम द सोसाइटी पॉइंट ऑफ व्यू
This was the entire family. the concept of
दिस वाज़ एंटायर फैमिली। द कांसेप्ट ऑफ़
everybody becoming a self standing person
एवरीबडी बिकमिंग अ सेल्फ स्टैंडिंग पर्सन
Is an entire family. Family Tradition
इज़ अ एंटायर फैमिली। फैमिली ट्रेडिशन
Demands
डिमांड्स
Dependency Interdependency Dependency Good
डिपेंडेंसी इंटरडिपेंडेंसी डिपेंडेंसी गुड
Strengthening Dependencies by Supporting Each Other
डिपेंडेंसी स्ट्रेंथनिंग ईच अदर सपोर्टिंग
Each other living together were as Mahavidyas
ईच अदर लिविंग टुगेदर वेयर एस महाविद्यास
were found dangerous by the traditional society
वर फाउंड डेंजरस बाय द ट्रेडिशनल सोसाइटी
they were found dangerous because they were too
दे वर फाउंड डेंजरस बिकॉज़ दे वर टू
Strengthening You Know How to Strengthen You
स्ट्रेंथनिंग यू नो टू स्ट्रेंथनिंग यू
Can Extract Power Quickly Yes Very
कैन एक्सट्रैक्ट पावर क्विकली यस वेरी
quickly they are raw i told you they are very
क्विकली दे आर रॉ आई टोल्ड यू दे आर वैरी
raw u get darshan of mahavidyas very
रॉ यू यू गेट दर्शन ऑफ़ महाविद्यास वैरी
easily you start and you know the feeling
इजीली यू स्टार्ट एंड यू नो फील फीलिंग द
The Energy Inside You Can Very Easily Give Extra
एनर्जी इनसाइड यू वेरी ईजीली एक्सट्रा दे
are very raw so the kali tara and shodashi hu
आर वेरी रॉ सो द काली तारा एंड शोडशी हु
are the representatives of the trigunas
आर द रिप्रेजेंटेटिव्स ऑफ़ दी त्रिगुणास
And all that is there on earth they represent
एंड ऑल दैट इज़ देयर ऑन अर्थ दे रिप्रेजेंट
The Triune Nature Completely After
द त्रिगुणात्मक प्रकृति कंप्लीटली आफ्टर
that comes bhuvaneshwari which comes at the
दैट कम्स भुवनेश्वरी व्हिच कम्स एट द
Crown
क्राउन
level Bhuvaneshwari is the ruler of the
लेवल भुवनेश्वरी इज़ द रूलर ऑफ़ द
Bhuvan is the essence of the entire and so she is
भुवन ऑफ़ द ऑफ़ द एंटायर एंड सो शी इज़
Manifested what Kali Tara and Rishi should do
मैनिफेस्टेड व्हाट काली तारा एंड शुड ऋषी
want i think this is also an important
वांट आई थिंक दिस इज़ आल्सो एन इंपॉर्टेंट
Point in our episode to explain what
पॉइंट इन आवर एपिसोड टू एक्सप्लेन व्हाट
Chakras are but more than a Reiki
चक्रास आर बट मोर फ्रॉम अ रेकी
perspective and in the way that most people
पर्सपेक्टिव और इन द वे दैट मोस्ट पीपल
Understanding Chakras or The Seven Ways
अंडरस्टैंड चक्रास या द सेवन दे आर
Distribution Points Chakras R
डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन पॉइंट्स चक्रास आर
What are the distribution points?
डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन पॉइंट्स दे व्हाट टाइससेस
we call them they are propelling chakra means
वी कॉल देम दे आर प्रोपेलिंग चक्रा मींस
Literally word means wheel chakra means wheel
लिटरली वर्ड मींस व्हील चक्र मींस व्हील
something that is moving constantly and
समथिंग दैट इज मूविंग कॉन्सेंटली एंड
Propelling Channeling Energy Energy. so these
प्रोपेलिंग चैनलिंग एनर्जी एनर्जी। सो दीज़
Sevencraze in our body are seven energy
सेवनक्राज़ इन आवर बॉडी आर सेवन एनर्जी
points energy vertices that are
पॉइंट्स एनर्जी वर्टाइससेस दैट आर
actually distributing the cosmic
एक्चुअली डिस्ट्रीब्यूटिंग द कॉस्मिक
the energy that we are receiving we are receiving
एनर्जी दैट वी आर रिसीविंग वी आर रिसीविंग
Life Force Energy. this is nothing self
लाइफ फ़ोर्स एनर्जी। दिस इज़ नथिंग सेल्फ
Generated. there is no courage when you
जनरेटेड। देयर इज़ नो डअरशिप व्हेन यू
Understand the science of this Ranveer. there is
अंडरस्टैंड द साइंस ऑफ़ दिस रणवीर। देयर इज़
No fear. it's all an automated program
नो डअरशिप। इट्स ऑल अ ऑटोमेटेड प्रोग्राम
you know set right by god and it's all
यू नो सेट राइट बाय बाइ गॉड एंड इट्स ऑल
Happening. who has seen the chakra and who
हैप्पेनिंग। हु हैज़ सीन द चक्रा और हु
Program the Chakra and who has taught the Chakra
प्रोग्राम द चक्रा और हु हैज़ टॉट द चक्रा
To move in a certain way and to channel energy
टू मूव इन अ सर्टेन वे और टू चैनल एनर्जी
nobody has known god has known its god
नोबडी हैज़ टॉट गॉड हैज़ टॉट इट्स गॉड
created so these chakras the seven realms are
क्रिएटेड सो दीज़ चक्राज़ दी सेवन रेलम्स आर
Energy Vortices They Are Like
एनर्जी वर्टाइसेस दे आर लाइक
Distribution centers at different levels
डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन सेंटर्स एट डिफरेंट लेवल्स
Starting from the Root Chakra You Know Where the
स्टार्टिंग फ्रॉम द रूट चक्र यू नो वेयर द
Lower body is taken care of our lower body
लोअर बॉडी इज़ टेकन केयर ऑफ़ आवर लोअर बॉडी
is completely taken care of by the root chakra
इज़ कंप्लीटली टेकन केयर ऑफ़ बाय द रूट चक्र
And then the Swadhisthana. so the energy that
एंड देन द स्वाधिष्ठान। सो द एनर्जी दैट
means the root chakra energy center we call it the
मींस द रूट चक्र एनर्जी सेंटर वी कॉल इट द
Muladhara chakra. This Root Chakra Energy Center
मूलाधार चक्र। दिस रूट चक्र एनर्जी सेंटर
is actually responsible for all the
इज़ एक्चुअली रिस्पांसिबल फॉर ऑल द
Activities that are happening in the lower
एक्टिविटीज़ दैट आर हैप्पेनिंग इन द लोअर
Body. It Provides Energy, It Propels
बॉडी। इट प्रोवाइड्स एनर्जी, इट प्रोपेल्स
Energy and sends energy to all the organs
एनर्जी एंड सेंड्स एनर्जी टु ऑल द ऑर्गन
systems, physiological functions that are
सिस्टम्स, फिजियोलॉजिकल फंक्शनंस दैट आर
Happening in the lower body. Right? then you have
हैपनिंग इन द लोअर बॉडी। राइट? देन यू हैव
The Delicious and The Green We Call It Green.
द स्वादिष्टाना और द हरा वी कॉल इट हरा।
And
और
the this is also called cell chakra in in an
द दिस इज़ आल्सो कॉल्ड सेल चक्रा इन इन एन
Energy Language. This Controls the Lower Abs
एनर्जी लैंग्वेज। दिस कंट्रोल्स द लोअर ऐब
Part. You know your reproductive system
पार्ट। यू नो योर रिप्रोडक्टिव सिस्टम
Gayani Area
गयनी एरिया
and some part of the abdomen you know
एंड सम पार्ट ऑफ़ द एब्डोमेन यू नो लो
Abdomen extra and delicious is
एब्डोमेन एक्सट्रा एंड स्वादिष्टाना इज़
compared to the depth of the ocean its
कंपेयर्ड टू द डेप्थ ऑफ़ द ओशन इट्स
considered to be a very deep chakra and this
कंसीडर्ड टू बी अ वेरी डीप चक्रा एंड दिस
Chakra is sending energy to all these
चक्रा इज़ सेंडिंग एनर्जी टू ऑल दीज़
Parts of the Body. so when you think
पार्ट्स ऑफ़ द बॉडी। सो व्हेन यू थिंक
About Chakras and Talk About Chakra B The
अबाउट चक्राज़ और टॉक अबाउट चक्रा बी द
body they are basically providing energy to
बॉडी दे आर बेसिकली प्रोवाइडिंग एनर्जी टू
all the physiological functions which are
ऑल द फिजियोलॉजिकल फंक्शंस व्हिच आर
Present in their jurisdiction.
प्रेजेंट इन देयर जरिसडिक्टेड एरिया।
Allright. Swadhisthana is here. it is called
ऑलराइट। स्वाधिष्ठान इज़ हियर। इट्स कॉल्ड
Reproductive center also. and then
रिप्रोडक्टिव सेंटर आल्सो। एंड देन
Manipura. Manipura is a naval chakra. I am
मणिपुरा। मणिपुरा इज़ अ नेवल चक्र। आई एम
talking very briefly because our episode is
टॉकिंग वेरी ब्रीफली बिकॉज़ आवर एपिसोड इज़
not a bar healing that i could go deeper into
नॉट अ बार हीलिंग दैट आई कुड गो डीपर इंटू
The Subject. but just a brief about the
द सब्जेक्ट। बट जस्ट अ ब्रीफ़ अबाउट द
Chakraz. The Manipura The Naval Chakra Tex
चक्राज़। द मणिपुरा द नेवल चक्रा टेक्स
Care of this band. abdomen, spleen,
केयर ऑफ़ दिस बैंड। एब्डोमिनंस, स्प्लीन,
Liver, pancreas, extra over here,
लिवर, पैंक्रियास, एक्सेट्रा ओवर हियर,
Provides Energy for All
प्रोवाइड्स एनर्जी फॉर ऑल
the ah you know functions, physiological functions
द अह यू नो फंक्शंस, फिजियोलॉजिकल फंक्शंस
and organs. Any Time This Chakra Is
एंड ऑर्गन्स। एनी टाइम दिस चक्रा इज
Imbalance We Talk About Chakra Imbalance
इम्बैलेंस वी टॉक अबाउट चक्रा इम्बैलेंस
is of course you know you here people are talking about
इज़ ऑफेन यू नो यू हियर पीपल टॉकिंग अबाउट
This Chakra is not good and this Chakra is good.
दिस चक्रा इज़ नॉट गुड और दिस चक्र इज़ गुड।
So when we say it's not good that it means
सो व्हेन वी से इट्स नॉट गुड दैट मींस
it's not doing its duty to spread
इट्स नॉट डूइंग इट्स ड्यूटी टू स्प्रेड
Energy Everywhere and Consequentially the
एनर्जी एवरीव्हेयर एंड कॉन्सीक्वेंटली द
Organ travel. The solar plexus is called the
ऑर्गन सफर। सोलर प्लेक्सेस इज़ कॉल्ड द
Power Centre. this is called a sex centre
पावर सेंटर। दिस इज़ कॉल्ड अ सेक्स सेंटर
And this is called the Earth Center. these three
एंड दिस इज़ कॉल्ड द अर्थ सेंटर। दिस थ्री
The Chakras govern the realms of the Earth. Give
चक्रास गवर्न द रेलम्स ऑफ़ द अर्थ। दे
Govern the Realms of the Earth That Means All
गवर्न द रेलम्स ऑफ द अर्थ दैट मींस ऑल
Living Worldly All the Issues That Are
वर्ल्डली लिविंग ऑल इश्यूज दैट आर
Concerning our life on earth affect the
कंसर्निंग आवर लाइफ ऑन अर्थ अफेक्ट दी
Three Areas So the Chakras Exist Within
थ्री एरियाज सो द चक्रास एक्सिस्ट विद इन
our body with in our body but they also
आवर बॉडी विद इन आवर बॉडी बट दे आल्सो
Linked to the original loka that they belong
लिंक्ड टू दी ओरिजिनल लोका दैट दे बिलोंग
to those are the trigger points ah to the
टू दे आर द ट्रिगर पॉइंट्स अह टू दी द
connection points trigger points to the
कनेक्शन पॉइंट ट्रिगर पॉइंट्स टू द
different locales to the different ah ah
डिफरेंट लोकास टू द डिफरेंट अह अह
Galaxies to the two different Gods and
गैलेक्सीस टू द टू द डिफरेंट गॉड्स एंड
goddesses they are like you are a hub and these are
गॉडेसेस दे आर लाइक यू आर अ हब एंड दीज़ आर
are the points that are connecting you to the
आर द पॉइंट्स दैट आर कनेक्टिंग यू टू द
The Entire Universe. like antennas for
एंटायर यूनिवर्स। लाइक एंटीनास फॉर
Different. Antennas for different parts of
डिफरेंट। एंटीनाज फॉर डिफरेंट पार्ट्स ऑफ़
The Universe. Ok. so there is also a
द यूनिवर्स। ओके। सो देयर इज़ आल्सो अ
Biological aspects related to chakras in
बायोलॉजिकल एस्पेक्ट रिलेटेड टू चक्रास इन
Terms of a from a healing perspective.
टर्म्स ऑफ अ फ्रॉम द हीलिंग पर्सपेक्टिव।
yes, there is a there is a
यस, देयर देयर इज़ अ देयर इज़ अ
Physiological Biological Energy
फिजियोलॉजिकल बायोलॉजिकल एनर्जी
The Perspective That We as Healers Talk About
पर्सपेक्टिव दैट वी एज़ हीलर्स टॉक अबाउट
Of course there is a mystic approach here
ऑफन देयर इज़ अ मिस्टिक अप्रोच वेयर इन
Mahavidyas. We talk about this. you know that
महाविद्यास। वी टॉक अबाउट दिस। यू नो दैट
These goddesses are actually elemental. give and take
दीज़ देवीज़ आर एक्चुअली एलीमेंटल। दे आर
like elemental because the chakras also
लाइक एलीमेंटल बिकॉज़ द चक्राज़ आल्सो
Elemental. Chakras All Panchamahabhutas Have
एलीमेंटल। चक्रास ऑल पंचमहाभूताज़ हैव
Created this whole world. so there
क्रिएटेड दिस होल वर्ल्ड। सो देयर
everything has to be related to energy
एव्रीथिंग हैज़ टू बी रिलेटेड टु एनर्जी
And to ah to the element. something are fiery,
एंड टू अह टू द एलिमेंट। समथिंग आर फायरी,
Somethings are watery, somethings are eerie. You
समथिंग्स आर वॉटरी, समथिंग्स आर एरी। यू
No like that. so, the chakra is also, you know
नो लाइक दैट। सो, द चक्र इज़ ऑल्सो, यू नो
There is an earth element down below.
देयर देयर इज़ अ अर्थ एलिमेंट डाउन बिलो।
There is a water element in Swadhisthana.
देयर इज़ अ वाटर एलिमेंट इन स्वाधिष्ठान।
There is a fire element here. Allright. End
देयर इज़ अ फ़ायर एलिमेंट हियर। ऑलराइट। एंड
Then the air element comes at the heart level.
देन द एयर एलिमेंट कम्स एट द हार्ट लेवल।
we call it the anahata or the heart level texts
वी कॉल इट द अनाहट ओर द हार्ट लेवल टेक्स
Care of this part of the body. and the air
केयर ऑफ़ दिस पार्ट ऑफ़ द बॉडी। एंड द एयर
The element is ruling here. so thewes also
एलिमेंट इज़ रूलिंग हियर। सो दवीज़ आल्सो
Corresponding to this I will come to the list
करेस्पोंडिंग टू दीज़ आई विल कम टू द लिस्ट
Of goddess after this. so after the her
ऑफ़ देवीज़ आफ्टर दिस। सो आफ्टर द हर
element then you have the throat chakra and the
एलिमेंट देन यू हैव द थ्रोट चक्र और द
Vishuddhi. You know here it is the Aakash element.
विशुद्धि। यू नो हियर इट इज़ द आकाशा तत्व।
After the air element it is sky. that's me
आफ्टर द एयर एलिमेंट इट इज़ आकाश। दैट मी
Ether. And vishudhi is where the purification
इथर। एंड विशुद्धि इज़ वेयर द प्यूरिकेशन
Of prana and all the energy is happening.
ऑफ़ प्राणा एंड ऑल द एनर्जी इज़ हैपनिंग।
Allright. so when we come to mahadevis the maha
ऑलराइट। सो व्हेन वी कम टू महादेवीस द महा
Mahavidyas The Chinnamasta Is Here You Know
महाविद्यास द चिनमस्ता इज़ हियर यू नो
which is slotted the head completely and
व्हिच इज़ स्लॉटेड द हेड कंप्लीटली एंड
there is a purification of prana and the
देयर इज़ अ प्यूरिफिकेशन ऑफ़ प्राणा एंड द
Idae and Pingala are flowing you know with
इड़ाए एंड पिंगला आर फ्लोइंग यू नो विथ विथ
The Kundalini in Complete Activation. after the
द कुंडलिनी इन कंप्लीट एक्टिवेशन। आफ्टर द
sky element ah sky element is going at
आकाश तत्व अह आकाश तत्व इज़ गोइंग एट
different levels till the crown and beyond
डिफरेंट लेवल्स टिल द क्राउन एंड बिय्ड द
Crown There are these three stations of Devi
क्राउन देयर आर दीज़ थ्री स्टेशंस ऑफ़ देवी
The Kali, The Tara and The Shodashi. Ok. Yeah. Ahhh
द काली द तारा एंड द शोडशी। ओके। याह। अह
If One Takes a Cosmic Camera and Places
इफ वन टेक्स अ कॉस्मिक कैमरा एंड प्लेसेस
It's in those losses, what would one see? Because we
इट इन दोज़ लोस, व्हाट वुड वन सी? बिकॉज़ वी
are talking about three of the gunachakras, and
आर टॉकिंग अबाउट थ्री ऑफ़ द गुणाचक्रस, एंड
then seven other chakras, so we are talking
देन सेवन अदर अदर चक्रस, सो वी आर टॉक
About 10 different planes. Yes. that do not
अबाउट 10 डिफरेंट प्लेेंस। यस। दैट डू नॉट
Share physical space with our plane on Earth.
शेयर फिजिकल स्पेस विद आवर प्लेन ऑन अर्थ।
Yes. Right? Yes. what would you see if you are
यस। राइट? यस। व्हाट वुड यू सी इफ यू आर
there? Nothing could be seen, can be felt. C
देयर? नथिंग कुड बी सीन कैन बी फेल्ट। सी
There is no gross reality outside.
देयर देयर इज़ नो ग्रॉस रियलिटी आउटसाइड।
There are Sattler alums. Their Sattler Alum. nothing
देयर आर सटलर एलम्स। देयर सटलर एलम। नथिंग
Is Visible Tribble. it doesn't have a grip
इज़ विज़िबल ट्रिबल। इट डजंट हैव अ ग्राउ
Or. Difficult to place innu words. Yes.
या। डिफिकल्ट टू प्लेस इनू वर्ड्स। यस।
Very difficult to place in words. It
वेरी डिफिकल्ट टू प्लेस इनू वर्ड्स। इट
can be felt, sensed and seen with the inner
कैन बी फेल्ट सेंस्ड एंड सीन विथ द इनर
I. Can be can be sensed. can be felt
आई। कैन बी कैन बी सेंस्ड। कैन बी फेल्ट
And Seen by the Inner Eye. Heard by the Inner
एंड सीन बाय द इनर आई। हर्ड बाय द इनर
Word.
शब्द।
But the happenings that take place on earth in
बट द हैपनिंग्स दैट टेक प्लेस ऑन अर्थ इन
Terms of thought of a very big piticle
टर्म्स ऑफ द थॉट्स ऑफ अ वेरी बिग पिटिकल
Leader Hum
लीडर हम
and someone dying because of a freak accident
और समवन डाइंग बिकॉज़ ऑफ़ अ फ्रीक एक्सीडेंट
The decisions are being made in those lols.
द डिसिशनंस आर बीइंग मेड इन दोज़ लोल्स।
by the way varshi it works both ways when someone
वैसे वर्षा इट वर्क्स बोथ वेज़ व्हेन समवन
thinks about destruction this thought goes
थिंक्स अबाउट डिस्ट्रक्शन दिस दिस थॉट गोज़
there and it is accelerated
देयर एंड इट इज़ एक्सलरेटेड
energy you know it's like hiranyagarbha
एनर्जी यू नो इट्स इट्स लाइक हिरण्यगर्भा
We talk about Hiranyagarbha Hiranyagarbha is a
वी टॉक अबाउट हिरण्यगर्भा हिरण्यगर्भ इज़ अ
Voom of the Universe. is the collective thought and
वूम ऑफ़ द यूनिवर्स। इज़ द कलेक्टिव थॉट एंड
The Collective Mind of the Universe. sleep in
द कलेक्टिव माइंड ऑफ़ द यूनिवर्स। सो इन
Hiranyagarbha every thought is registered. End
हिरण्यगर्भा एव्री थॉट इज़ रजिस्टर्ड। एंड
It starts becoming a reality.
इट स्टार्ट्स बिकमिंग अ रियलिटी।
Manifesting It Starts Manifesting
मैनिफेस्टिंग इट स्टार्ट्स मैनिफेस्टिंग
over there from there so it comes back over
ओवर देयर फ्रॉम देयर सो इट कम्स बैक ओवर
here as a reality so the it's both ways it is
हियर एज अ रियलिटी सो द इट्स बोथ वेज़ इट्स
both ways traffic or so there is an element
बोथ वेज़ ट्रैफिक या सो देयर इज़ एन एलिमेंट
of free human will yes as well as the will of
ऑफ़ फ्री ह्यूमन विल यस एज वेल एज द विल ऑफ़
The Datis Yes Yes Okay Beautiful Explanation
द डेटीस यस यस ओके ब्यूटीफुल एक्सप्लेनेशन
Now I will let you continue to sleep at the heart
नाउ आई विल लेट यू कंटिन्यू सो एट द हार्ट
level it is the air element and at the throat
लेवल इट इज़ द एयर एलिमेंट एंड एट द थ्रोट
level it is the aakash and it goes beyond the
लेवल इट इज़ द आकाशा एंड इट गोज़ बिय्ड टू द
Crown Level So, beyond this upper triangle,
क्राउन लेवल सो, बियड दिस अपर ट्रायंगल,
We call it the Upper Triangle. Inverted Upper
वी कॉल इट द अपर ट्रायंगल। इनवर्टेड अपर
Triangle is seen as Kali, Ah Tara and
ट्रायंगल इज़ शोन ऐज़ काली, अह तारा एंड
Shodashi. Allright. This Upper Triangle
शोडशी। ऑलराइट। दिस अपर ट्रायंगल
starts manifesting in all the seven
स्टार्ट्स मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग इन ऑल दी सेवन
Lokas, it gets embedded in all these seven
लोकाज़, इट गेट्स एंबेडेड इन ऑल दीज़ सेवन
Lockjaw. that means that when bhuvaneshwari is
लोकाज़। दैट मींस दैट व्हेन भुवनेश्वरी इज़
Happening, when Bhuvaneshwari seated here,
हैपेनिंग, व्हेन भुवनेश्वरी सीटेड हियर,
There is a Kali and Tara and Shodashi in
देयर इज़ अ काली एंड तारा एंड शोडशी इन
Bhuvaneshwari also. Right? now let me talk
भुवनेश्वरी आल्सो। राइट? नाउ लेट मी टॉक
About the Tantra aspect of it. because it's
अबाउट द तंत्र एस्पेक्ट ऑफ़ इट। बिकॉज़ इट्स
A tantric subject. Mahavidyas Itself
अ तांत्रिक सब्जेक्ट। महाविद्यास इटसेल्फ
It is a Tantric subject. so every goddess
इज़ अ तांत्रिक सब्जेक्ट। सो एव्री देवी
From here onwards you know Bhuvaneshwari then
फ्रॉम हियर ऑनवर्ड्स यू नो भुवनेश्वरी देन
Chinamasta Bhairavi Bhuvaneshwari Den Bhairavi Den
चिनमस्ता भैरवी भुवनेश्वरी देन भैरवी देन
Chinnamasta Dhumavati Baglamukhi Matangi And
चिनमस्ता धुमावती बगलामुखी मातंगी एंड
kamalatmika all of these goddesses have this upper
कमलात्मिका ऑल ऑफ़ दीज़ देवीज़ हैव दिस अपर
Triangle residing within them. there's all this
ट्रायंगल रिसाइडिंग इन देम। देयरफ़ ऑल दीज़
goddess all the experiments that are done can be in
देवीज़ ऑल द प्रयोग दैट आर डन कैन बी इन
White, can be in red and can be in black.
वाइट, कैन बी इन रेड एंड कैन बी इन ब्लैक।
We each of this can be invoked as a star as
हम ईच ऑफ दिस कैन बी इनवोक्ड एज अ तारा एज
white each of these can be invoked as shorshi
वाइट ईच ऑफ दीज़ कैन बी इनवोक्ड एस शोरशी
As a Raid for Prosperity Business
एज अ रेड फॉर प्रोस्पेरिटी बिजनेस
extra and each of them can be taken to the
एक्सट्रा एंड ईच ऑफ़ देम कैन बी टेकन टू द
level of kali you see they are there this upper
लेवल ऑफ़ काली यू सी दे आर देयर दिस अपर
The triangle is residing in all these seven
ट्रायंगल इज़ रीसाइडिंग इन ऑल दीज़ सेवन
Manifestations of the Goddess. so bhuvaneshwari is
मैनिफेस्टेशंस ऑफ़ देवी। सो भुवनेश्वरी इज़
worship is also quite a lot, especially in
वरशिप आल्सो क्वाइट अ लॉट एस्पेशली इन
South India you see a lot of tradition. The
साउथ इंडिया यू सी अ लॉट ऑफ़ ट्रेडिशन। द
Mahavidya tradition has survived in the
महाविद्या ट्रेडिशन हैज़ सर्वाइव्ड इन द
South more than in the North. in the north edge
साउथ मोर देन इन द नॉर्थ। इन द नॉर्थ एज़
I explore and as I go I travel
आई एक्सप्लोर एंड एज़ आई गो आई ट्रेवल अ
Lot to See the Traditional Temples and Study
लॉट टू सी द ट्रेडिशनल टेंपल्स एंड स्टडी
I love this subject. i see that the
आई लव दिस सब्जेक्ट। आई सी दैट द
Mahavidyas are modernized in the North
महाविद्याज आर मॉडर्नाइज्ड इन द नॉर्थ दे
R Modernized. infact in some of the
आर मॉडर्नाइज़्ड। इनफैक्ट इन सम ऑफ़ द
Traditional temples that are there. you see the
ट्रेडिशनल टेंपल्स दैट आर देयर। यू सी द
Old pictures are removed now and a very
ओल्ड पिक्चर्स आर रिमूव्ड नाउ एंड अ वेरी
Feminine Feminine Domesticated Goddess
फेमिन फेमिनाइन डोमेस्टिकेटेड देवी
pictures are there which is wearing a saree
पिक्चर्स आर देयर व्हिच इज़ वेरिंग अ साड़ी
and july and those pictures are pur weather
एंड जूल एंड दोज़ पिक्चर्स आर पुर वेदर
Mahavidyas Var Very Rawr You See The Old P
महाविद्यास वर वैरी रॉर यू सी द ओल्ड प
old books that are written and in
ओल्ड बुक्स दैट आर रिटेन एंड इन
Museums You See in a Naked Black Weather Her
म्यूजियम्स यू सी इन अ नेकेड काली वेदर हर
Hair spread out in absolute freedom and
हेयर स्प्रेड आउट इन अब्सोलूट फ्रीडम एंड
She is completely divided of conditioning.
शी इज़ कम्प्लीटली डिवाइड ऑफ़ कंडिशनिंग।
There is no conditioning. and fiery fears
देयर इज़ नो कंडीशनिंग। एंड फायरी फियर्स
absolutely wearing a garland of
अब्सोल्युटली वेयरिंग अ गार्लैंड ऑफ
Skulls around and there is alphabet written
स्कल्स अराउंड एंड देयर इज़ वर्णमाला रिटन
On the skulls and so she is very fiery.
ऑन द स्कल्ल्स एंड सो शी इज़ वेरी फायरी।
so people are not you know in the history
सो पीपल आर नॉट यू नो इन इन इन द हिस्ट्री
Domestication of Mahavidyas
ऑफ़ सनातन धर्म डोमेस्टिकेशन ऑफ़ महाविद्यास
It has happened. first it was put into
हैज़ हैपेंड। फर्स्ट इट वाज़ पुट इंटू
Absolute Ah Guhiya Ah In Hiding And
अब्सोल्यूट अह गुहिया अह इन हाइडिंग एंड
as it is emerging by because people are asking
एज़ इट इज़ इमर्जिंग बाय बिकॉज़ पीपल आस्किंग
About Mahavidyas. you see so much of it
अबाउट महाविद्यास। यू सी सो मच ऑफ़ इट
Coming out now. when people are asking that
कमिंग आउट नाउ। व्हेन पीपल आर आस्किंग दैट
The Domesticated Version Is Preferred You Know
द डोमेस्टिकेटेड वर्जन इज़ प्रेफर्ड यू नो
As an incarnation of Durga and with a consort
एज़ एन अवतार ऑफ दुर्गा एंड विथ अ कंसोर्ट
Shiva and this is preferred for devotion this
शिवा एंड दिस इज़ प्रेफर्ड फॉर भक्ति दिस
is preferred i'm not pro i'm not
इज़ प्रेफर्ड आई एम नॉट प्रो आई एम नॉट
against this because for some reasons it's good
अगेंस्ट दिस बिकॉज़ फॉर सम रीज़ंस इट्स गुड
for some people it's good for householders
फॉर सम पीपल इट्स गुड फॉर हाउसहोल्डर्स
it's good but when you attent into a
इट्स गुड बट व्हेन यू एट अटेन इंटू अ
Yogic State of Mind and You Are Pursuing
योगिक स्टेट ऑफ़ माइंड एंड यू आर पर्सुइंग
this vidya then it goes into it's not a
दीज़ विद्या देन इट गोज़ इंटू इट्स नॉट अ
woman it's not a man its pure source of
वूमन इट्स नॉट अ मैन इट्स प्योर सोर्स ऑफ़
Raw Energy That You Can Harness
रॉ एनर्जी दैट यू कैन हारनेस
Bracketed as a woman for the sake of the
ब्रैकेटेड एज अ वूमेन फॉर द सेक ऑफ द
Average Human Mind or Why or Why Not
एवरेज ह्यूमन माइंड या व्हाई या व्हाई नॉट
Portray the Mahavidyas as men because of Shakti
पोट्रे द महाविद्यास एस मेन बिकॉज़ शक्ति
is
इज़
Feminine primal power has come out of
फेमिनाइन प्राइमरली शक्ति हैज़ कम आउट ऑफ
shiva you know she she is the moving energy shiva
शिवा यू नो शी शी इज़ द मूविंग एनर्जी शिवा
is she the divine only see both
इज़ द शी इज़ परमात्मा ओनली सी द बोथ
Aspects of Paramatma One is Ah is A
एस्पेक्ट्स ऑफ परमात्मा वन इज़ अह इज़ इज़ अ
Station Potential Energy Form and the Others
स्टेशन पोटेंशियल एनर्जी फॉर्म एंड द अदर
Is moving kinetic energy form. So, peacock
इज़ मूविंग काइनेटिक एनर्जी फॉर्म। सो, मोर
Again to the Feminine, That's Why We
अगेन टू द फेमिनाइन, दैट्स व्हाई वी
Depicted as goddess.
डिपिक्टेड एज़ देवीज।
hmm not that i want to despise them as
हम्म नॉट दैट आई वांट टू डिपेक्ट देम एज़
Mains. that was just my curiosity
मेन्स। दैट वाज़ जस्ट माय क्यूरियोसिटी
Speaking up. ah and i will tell you the
स्पीकिंग अप। अह एंड आई विल टेल यू द
Origin Source of That Curiosity. agreed
ओरिजिन सोर्स ऑफ़ दैट क्यूरियोसिटी। राजी
sir head said something
सर हेड सेड समथिंग
Like basically, the mantras come first.
लाइक बेसिकली, द मंत्रास कम फर्स्ट।
Mantras have their own energy and for the
मंत्रास हैव देर ओन एनर्जी एंड फॉर द
Mantras to be Able to Explain
मंत्र्रास टू बी एबल टू एक्सप्लेन
Themselves to human minds de potre
देमसेल्व्स टू ह्यूमन माइंड्स दे पोट्रे
Themselves as human looking forms like
देमसेल्व्स एज ह्यूमन लुकिंग फॉर्म्स लाइक
a goddess and goddess of course of course so it is
अ देवी और देवी ऑफकोर्स ऑफकोर्स सो इट इज
The Will of the Energy with these two Mantrasars
द विल ऑफ द एनर्जी विद इन दोज़ मंत्रासर्स
to portray themselves as well yes yes which
टू पोट्रे देमसेल्व्स एज वेल यस यस व्हिच
makes me question a lot
मेक्स मि क्वेश्चन अ लॉट
About Human Females and Human Males Is
अबाउट ह्यूमन फीमेल्स एंड ह्यूमन मेल्स इज़
The Nature of Being a Female Very Different
द नेचर ऑफ बीइंग अ फीमेल वेरी डिफरेंट
from the nature of being a male
फ्रॉम द नेचर ऑफ़ बीइंग अ मेल
It isn't at a spiritual level. we are semi
इट इजंट एट अ स्पिरिचुअल लेवल। वी आर अर्ध
Nareshwar. We are all Ardhanareshwar. we are ours
नरेश्वर। वी आर ऑल अर्धनरेश्वर। वी आर आवर
body is a rising and then ah is a race you
बॉडी इज़ अ रिसाइडिंग इज़ इज़ अह इज़ अ रेस यू
no the receding energy there is that of
नो द रीसाइडिंग एनर्जी देयर इज़ दैट ऑफ़
shivaan shakti both. there is consciousness
शिवाण शक्ति बोथ। देयर इज़ कॉन्शियसनेस
Inside Which Is the Potential Energy and
इनसाइड व्हिच इज़ द पोटेंशियल एनर्जी एंड
There is a whole energy field. gamut of
देयर इज़ अ होल एनर्जी फील्ड। गेमिट ऑफ़
The energy field that we have. which is the
एनर्जी फील्ड दैट वी हैव। व्हिच इज़ द
Power. So, we are all primarily by birth
शक्ति। सो, वी आर ऑल प्राइमरली बाइ बर्थ
Ardhanareshwar. but the conditioning that we take
अर्धनरेश्वर। बट द कंडीशनिंग दैट वी टेक
on makes us believe us to be a man or a
ऑन मेक्स अस बिलीव अस टू बी अ मैन ऑर अ
Woman. When the Awakening of the Other in New
वूमेन। व्हेन द अवेकनिंग ऑफ़ द अदर इन न्यू
Happens for instance ah biological man,
हैप्पेंस फॉर इंस्टेंस अह बायोलॉजिकल मैन,
When the awakening of the feminine happens,
व्हेन द अवेकनिंग ऑफ़ द फेमिनाइन हैपेंस,
then he becomes more sensitive, his ego
देन ही बिकम्स मोर सेंसिटिव, हिज़ ईगो
Gates changed. you know his ego personality
गेट्स चेंज्ड। यू नो हिज़ ईगो पर्सनालिटी
gets changed and he becomes more sensitive
गेट्स चेंज्ड एंड ही बिकम्स मोर सेंसिटिव
and he is then housing both a male and a
एंड ही इज़ देन हाउसिंग बोथ अ मेल एंड अ
Female. Not biologically but spiritually.
फीमेल। नॉट बायोलॉजिकली बट स्पिरिचुअली।
And the female version. by the way varsha she becomes
एंड द फीमेल वर्जन। वैसे वर्षा शी बिकम्स
Bold and Courageous End
बोल्ड एंड करजियस एंड
very much more than a man you know in the sense of
वेरी मच मोर देन अ मैन यू नो इन सेंस ऑफ़
Her energy in the sense of dynamism in the sense
हर एनर्जी इन सेंस ऑफ़ डायनामिज़्म इन सेंस
of her courage fairness extra so a
ऑफ़ हर करेज फेयरलेसनेस एक्सेट्रा सो अ
Yogi then houses both Shiva and Shakti within
योगी देन हाउसेस बोथ शिवाय शक्ति विद इन
him which is the goal which is the goal ok
हिम व्हिच इज द गोल व्हिच इज द गोल ओके
Coming Back to the Mahavidyas Dash 10
कमिंग बैक टू द महाविद्यास दश 10
Mahavidyas Great Knowledge Yes and There Are 10
महाविद्यास ग्रेट नॉलेज यस एंड देयर आर 10
chakras that we are speaking about yes so
चक्रस दैट वी आर स्पीकिंग अबाउट यस सो
six inside the body one right above and then
सिक्स इनसाइड द बॉडी वन राइट अबव एंड देन
Seven on the Body Including the Crown
सेवन सेवेन ऑन द बॉडी इंक्लूडिंग द क्राउन
And then that upper triangle is the three gunas
एंड देन दैट अपर ट्राइएंगल द थ्री गुनास
above hmm so as i am walking around the
अबव हम्म सो एज़ आई एम वॉकिंग अराउंड द
Human World I am carrying all 10 Chakras
ह्यूमन वर्ल्ड आई एम कैरिंग ऑल 10 चक्रस
with me yes you are carrying all the 10 chakras you
विथ मी यस यू आर कैरिंग ऑल द 10 चक्रस यू
We are carrying the potential of these 10 devices
आर कैरिंग द पोटेंशियल ऑफ दिस 10 डेवीज
with you the potential and maha
विथ यू द पोटेंशियल पोटेंशियल एंड महा
Vidya Sadhna is all about unlocking that
विद्या साधना इज ऑल अबाउट अनलॉकिंग दैट
Unlocking That Potential
पोटेंशियल अनलॉकिंग दैट पोटेंशियल
ok now ah based on what we spoke about
ओके नाउ अह बेस्ड ऑन व्हाट वी स्पोक अबाउट
in the last episode the ultimate goal for
इन द लास्ट एपिसोड दी अल्टीमेट गोल फॉर
Human kind is to reconnect with the all
ह्यूमन काइंड इज़ टू रिकनेक्ट विद दी ऑल
Encompassing God That We Call Parmatma Yes And
एनकंपसिंग गॉड दैट वी कॉल परमात्मा यस एंड
Deti is like krishna lord hanuman ji shivji
डेटी इज लाइक कृष्ण भगवान हनुमान जी शिवजी
Bhairav ​​baba all the people help us to go there
भैरव बाबा ऑल दी पीपल हेल्प अस टू गो देर
all the energy help us to reach that
ऑल दी एनर्जी हेल्प अस टू रीच दैट
Divine
परमात्मा
when it comes to the goddess that you just
व्हेन इट कम्स टू द देवीज़ दैट यू जस्ट
spoke about i am assuming that the three
स्पोक अबाउट आई एम अस्यूमिंग दैट द थ्री
Top goddesses are the ones which are the most
टॉप देवीज़ आर द वंस व्हिच आर द मोस्ट
Related to Paramatma and Huj Sadhna Texts
रिलेटेड टू परमात्मा एंड हुज साधना टेक्स
you to god the most fearfully but does the
यू टू परमात्मा द मोस्ट फियर्सली बट डस द
worship of the other seven also take you to the
वरशिप ऑफ द अदर सेवन आल्सो टेक यू टू द
god 100% each goddess is a door way to
परमात्मा 100% ईच देवी इज़ अ डोर वे टू
parmatma because the upper triangle is
परमात्मा बिकॉज़ द अपर ट्रायंगल इज़
Deciding whether it's all right in the three aspects
डिसाइडिंग इन ऑल द ओके द थ्री एस्पेक्ट्स
Of The Goddess Which Is Kali Taran Produce
ऑफ़ द देवी व्हिच इज़ काली ताराण प्रोडस
Resideing in all the end they are can be the end
रिसाइडिंग इन ऑल द एंड दे आर कैन बी एंड
they are very fast there are sadhanas they go here
दे वेरी फ़ास्ट देयर फ़ द साधनाज़ वर गो हियर
because they are very fast they give it
बिकॉज़ दे आर वेरी फास्ट दे दे इट
starts propelling immediately you know
स्टार्ट्स प्रोपेलिंग इमीडिएटली यू नो
Devi Sadhna Mahavidya Sadhna Immediately
देवी साधना महाविद्या साधना इमीडिएटली
Starts Propelling Energy Inside You.
स्टार्ट्स प्रोपेलिंग एनर्जी इनसाइड यू।
Ok. What I understand about Mahavidya
ओके। व्हाट आई अंडरस्टैंड अबाउट महाविद्या
sadhana is that in the modern
साधना इज़ दैट इन द मॉडर्न
de there is a lot of people using it for
डे देअर इज़ अ लॉट ऑफ़ पीपल यूज़िंग इट फॉर
usage in terms of the benefits of each of
प्रयोग इन टर्म्स ऑफ़ द बेनिफिट्स ऑफ़ ईच ऑफ़
The Individual. Yeah. Mahavidyas Rather Give
द इंडिविजुअल। याह। महाविद्यास रादर देन
Using them as a tool for ultimate
यूजिंग देम एज अ टूल फॉर अल्टीमेट
Liberation. Correct. but my question to you
लिबरेशन। करेक्ट। बट माय क्वेश्चन टू यू
is there a sadhna which includes
इज़ इज़ देयर अ साधना व्हिच इंक्लूड्स
Worshipping All 10 in Order to Get to Some End
वरशिपिंग ऑल 10 इन ऑर्डर टू गेट टू सम एंड
Result? Or. All 10 are encourage people like
रिज़ल्ट? या। ऑल 10 आर आर एनकरेज पीपल लाइक
me do it. For Exploring the Goddesses. So
मी डु इट। फॉर एक्सप्लोरिंग द देवीज़। सो
for instance when this is my students
फॉर इंस्टेंस व्हेन दिस माय स्टूडेंट्स
Learn Mahavidya Sadhna with me. we make them
लर्न महाविद्या साधना विथ मी। वी मेक देम
Do a Whole Circuit of All the Mantra Japa Dhyana
डू अ होल सर्किट ऑफ ऑल द मंत्र जपा ध्याना
extra for them to understand and
एक्सट्रा फॉर देम टू अंडरस्टैंड एंड
Realize which of the Goddess is calling them
रियलाइज व्हिच ऑफ़ द देवी इज़ कॉलिंग देम
because we all have different nature all of us
बिकॉज़ वी ऑल हैव डिफरेंट प्रकृति ऑल ऑफ़ अस
have different nature different nature one can
हैव डिफरेंट प्रकृति डिफरेंट नेचर वन कैन
can't be said better than the other we are all good
नॉट बी सेड बेटर देन द अदर वी आर ऑल गुड
But there is a calling for a certain just
बट देयर इज़ अ कॉलिंग फॉर अ सर्टेन जस्ट
Like how you have a calling for a certain
लाइक हाउ यू हैव अ कॉलिंग फॉर अ सर्टेन
colour and for a certain taste and smell all of
कलर और फॉर अ सर्टेन टेस्ट और स्मेल ऑल ऑफ़
We have choices. in the same way when you
अस हैव चॉइससेस। इन द सेम वे व्हेन यू
Visit All the 10 Mahavidyas You Get a Calling
विजिट ऑल द 10 महाविद्यास यू गेट अ कॉलिंग
from a particular goddess it is it is
फ्रॉम अ पर्टिकुलर देवी इट इज़ इट इज़
almost like she is telling you that I will
ऑलमोस्ट लाइक शी इज़ टेलिंग यू दैट आई विल
Help you go there. how are you? when you do the
हेल्प यू गो देयर। हाउ यू? व्हेन यू डू द
The entire sequence comes on its own. Or
एंटायर सीक्वेंस इट कम्स ऑन इट्स ओन। या
How is Ganesha linked to the Mahavidyas. Ganesha
हाउ इज गणेशा लिंक टू द महाविद्यास। गणेशा
in our sect in my sect because the
इन आवर संप्रदाय इन माय संप्रदाय बिकॉज़ द
Devi sits in his lap we are from ages the
देवी सीट्स इन हिज लैप वी आर फ्रॉम एजेस द
all the other people and my soul which was there
ऑल द अदर पीपल एंड माय सोल व्हिच वाज़ देयर
incarnated in earlier ages we have always
इनकारनेटेड इन अर्लियर एजेस वी हैव ऑलवेज
Done this sadhna of Devi and Ganesha together in
डन दिस साधना ऑफ़ देवी एंड गणेशा टुगेदर इन
Devi tradition also be it Shri Vidya and
देवी ट्रेडिशन आल्सो बी इट श्री विद्या और
Be it any other Kali worship. Ganesha Is
बी इट एनी अदर काली उपासना। गणेशा इज़
considered to be the removal of obstacle and
कंसीडर्ड टू बी द रिमूवल ऑफ़ ऑब्सकल एंड
The Protector That Nobody Comes in the Path of
प्रोटेक्टर दैट नोबडी कम्स इन द पाथ ऑफ
Your sadhana. So Ganesha Invocation Helps You
योर साधना। सो गणेशा इनवोकेशन हेल्प्स यू
To do the siddhi of a devi very easily.
टू डू द सिद्धि ऑफ अ देवी वेरी ईजीली।
That's why a lot of people do at least one
दैट्स व्हाई अ लॉट ऑफ पीपल डू एटलीस्ट वन
Mala of Ganesh Mantra whenever they are doing
माला ऑफ गणेश मंत्र व्हेनवर दे आर डूइंग
Goddess worship. What Ganesh Mantra? Annie Ganesh
देवी साधना। व्हाट गणेश मंत्र? एनी गणेश
Mantra in our sect we have a long
मंत्र इन आवर संप्रदाय वी हैव अ लॉन्ग
Ganesh Mahaganapati Mool Mantra And I Have Given
गणेश महागणपति मूल मंत्र एंड आई हैव गिवेन
it's to you on the dupatta that I have
इट टू यू ऑन द ऑन द दुपट्टा दैट आई हैव
Given you on the stole that I gave you. it's
गिवेन यू ऑन द स्टोल दैट आई गव यू। इट्स
Printed. very its an old mahaganapati original
प्रिंटेड। वेरी इट्स अ ओल्ड महागणपति मूल
Mantra available everywhere. we don't normally
मंत्र अवेलेबल एवरीवेयर। वी डोंट नॉर्मली
pronouns it's like this o on the on the on the
प्रोनाउन्स इट लाइक दिस ओ ऑन द ऑन द ऑन द
Show. The Mantra Is Not Supposed To Be Said Like
शो। द मंत्र इज़ नॉट सपोज्ड टू बी सेड लाइक
this on the it's a long mantra but it's a
दिस ऑन द इट्स अ लॉन्ग मंत्र बट इट्स अ
Beautiful mantra. Why is it? I have seen it
ब्यूटीफुल मंत्र। व्हाई इज इट? आई हैव सीन
Rajshri sir do this as well. like he is not
राजश्री सर डू दिस एस वेल। लाइक ही इज़ नॉट
Willing to say certain words and chants
विलिंग टू से सर्टेन वर्ड्स और चांट
Certain Mantras. because we do puraanas and
सर्टेन मंत्रास। बिकॉज़ वी डू पुरणस एंड
Rituals for Many Years Now. you know of
अनुष्ठान्स फॉर मेनी इयर्स नाउ। यू नो ऑफ़
The Mantra. Mantra becomes Siddha in our life
द मंत्रा। मंत्र बिकम सिद्ध इन आवर
System. we are not supposed to like it
सिस्टम। वी आर नॉट सपोज्ड टू इट्स लाइक
Giving a Lot of Reference and Respect
गिविंग अ लॉट ऑफ़ रेफरेंस एंड रेस्पेक्ट
That you're not just casually flirting with it
दैट यू आर नॉट जस्ट कैजुअली फ्लटिंग इट
here and there to impress the audience or to
हियर एंड देयर टू इंप्रेस द ऑडियंस ऑर टू
Show How Good I Am At That Mantra and
शो हाउ गुड आई एम एट दैट मंत्र और
whatever. It's in humility in
व्हाटएवर। इट्स इन इन ह्यूमिलिटी इन
Surrender and submission that it is kept
सरेंडर एंड सबमिशन दैट इट इज़ केप्ट
Quiet. Yeah. it's not that it's a
क्वाइट। याह। इट्स नॉट दैट इट्स अ
Secret. It's not a secret. you can
सीक्रेट। इट्स नॉट अ सीक्रेट। यू कैन
Find Mahaganapati Mool Mantra Anywhere You
फाइंड महागणपति मूल मंत्र एनीवेयर यू यू
Google and you will find it. it's not
Google एंड यू विल फाइंड इट। इट्स नॉट
That's a secret. it's not that it
द्याट इट्स अ सीक्रेट। इट्स नॉट दैट इट
Should not be given to people. it's we don't say
शुड नॉट बी गिवन टू पीपल। इट्स वी डोंट से
It's up to you to float it. or to utilize it for
इट टू फ्लोट इट। ओर टू यूटिलाइज इट फॉर
Our showcasing it. you know, ya. getting back
आवर शोकास्टिंग इट। यू नो, या। गेटिंग बैक
Into the Mahavidya
इनटू द महाविद्या
Conversation. I don't know what question to ask
कन्वर्सेशन। आई डोंट नो व्हाट क्वेश्चन टू
Ask you next to forward the conversation.
आस्क यू नेक्स्ट टू फॉरवर्ड द कन्वर्सेशन।
Because I don't know where to begin. Yeah.
बिकॉज़ आई डोंट नो वेयर टू बिगिन। याह।
so, i actually handed it over to you
सो, आई एक्चुअली हैंड इट ओवर टू टू टू टू
to you and then i will stop you
टू टू टू यू एंड देन आई विल स्टॉप यू
Whoever has a question. Yeah. most of the
व्हेरवर हैव अ क्वेश्चन। याह। मोस्ट ऑफ़ द
Mahavidyas minus the three which are down. The
महाविद्यास माइनस द थ्री व्हिच आर डाउन। द
once that come from baglamukhi, matangi and
वंस दैट कम फ्रॉम बगलामुखी, मातंगी एंड
Kamalatmika, they are very brave. give and take
कमलात्मिका, दे आर वेरी वर्ल्ली। दे आर
Very Worli Vidya and They Are Persuaded
वेरी वर्ल्ली विद्या एंड दे आर पर्सुएड
Bai Sadhakkas for Siddhis and for Magicals
बाई साधक्कस फॉर सिद्धिज़ एंड फॉर मैजिकल
Abilities and For. So, it's a play for
एबिलिटीज़ एंड फॉर। सो, इट्स अ प्ले फॉर
For God. You know, energy is a play for
फॉर गॉड। यू नो, एनर्जी इज़ अ प्ले फॉर
God, and in this creation all this magical
गॉड, एंड इन दिस क्रिएशन ऑल दिस मैजिकल
the mysticul things that you see are all
मिस्टिकुल थिंग्स दैट यू सी दीज़ आर ऑल
Games and Toys for God. this what what
गेम्स एंड टॉयज़ फॉर गॉड। दिस व्हाट व्हाट
I have understood out of this. these are
आई हैव अंडरस्टुड आउट ऑफ़ दिस। दीज़ आर
Games for us to play but play with him. You
गेम्स फॉर अस टू प्ले बट प्ले विथ हिम। यू
no, these are games that we can play but play
नो, दीज़ आर गेम्स दैट वी कैन प्ले बु प्ले
With him. if he gives us the ability to see
विथ हिम। इफ ही गिव्स असन एबिलिटी टू सी
through or to hear through. Or to do something.
थ्रू ऑर टू हियर थ्रू। ऑर टू डु समथिंग।
It's for us to play with him. And Not To
इट्स फॉर अस टू प्ले विथ हिम। एंड नॉट टू
Create an identity. dissolving the
क्रिएट एन आइडेंटिटी। डिसोल्विंग द
Identity is the goal of anyone
आइडेंटिटी इज़ द गोल ऑफ़ एनी
Sadhana. annie sadhna you name it dissolving our
साधना। एनी साधना यू नेम इट डिसोलविंग आवर
Identity into God is the goal. if that is the
आइडेंटिटी इंटू गॉड इज़ द गोल। इफ दैट इज़ द
Goal, how seriously should I take this
गोल, हाउ सीरियसली शुड आई टेक दिस
Distractions that come on the path. The Many
डिस्ट्रैक्शंस दैट कम ऑन द पाथ। द मेनी
Destructions That Come on the Path. The Gifts
डिस्ट्रक्शंस दैट कम ऑन द पाथ। द गिफ्ट्स
that are given to you are not for you to keep
दैट आर गिवन टू यू आर नॉट फॉर यू टू कीप
In the locker. And I am not for you to encash. And
इन द लॉकर। अर आर नॉट फॉर यू टू एनकैश। और
are not for you to gain power with but there are
आर नॉट फॉर यू टू गेन पावर विद बट देयर आर
To give it back to God.
टू गिव इट बैक टू गॉड।
How do you give it back to God if he is
हाउ डू यू गिव इट बैक टू गॉड इफ ही इज
Gifting you with the siddhis you give me when I attach you
गिफ्टिंग यू विद सिद्धिस यू यू देन अटैच
all of your karma all of your work vi
ऑल ऑफ योर कर्म ऑल ऑफ योर वर्क वि
divine right that will be done that kingdom
परमात्मा राइट दैट विल बी डन दैट किंगडम
bee says na that will be done so if it is
बी बोलते हैं ना दैट विल बी डन सो इफ इट्स
his will he will make me use the siddhi
हिज विल ही विल मेक मी यूज़ द सिद्धि
Somewhere where it is right in a surrender mode
समवेयर व्हेयर इट इज़ राइट इन अ सरेंडर मोड
to use the siddhis when it is
टू यूज़ द सिद्धिस व्हेन इट इज़
Appropriate in a surrender mode and be so the
एप्रोप्रियेट इन अ सरेंडर मोड एंड बी सो द
The level of awareness should be so high level of
लेवल ऑफ़ अवेयरनेस शुड बी सो हाई लेवल ऑफ़
the awareness of me and the me that watches me all the
अवेयरनेस द मी एंड मी दैट वाचेस द मी ऑल द
time should be so high that you should understand
टाइम शुड बी सो हाई दैट यू शुड अंडरस्टैंड
weather it is a prank that my ego is
वेदर इट इज़ अ प्रैंक दैट माय ईगो इज़
playing ok show it off now and do it off now
प्लेइंग ओके शो इट ऑफ नाउ और डू इट ऑफ़ नाउ
you know or is it coming as something which is
यू नो ऑर इज़ इट कमिंग एज़ समथिंग व्हिच इज़
just happening and i'm seeing it is
जस्ट हैप्पेनिंग एंड आई एम सीइंग इट इज़
happening when i have a witness see that
हैप्पेनिंग व्हेन आई हैज़ अ विटनेस सी दैट
something is happening through me then I
समथिंग इज़ हैपन हैप्पेनिंग थ्रू मी देन आई
no that i'm not doing it somebody is just
नो दैट आई एम नॉट डूइंग इट समबडी इज़ जस्ट
you know god is making me do it flow state
यू नो गॉड इज मेकिंग मी डू इट फ्लो स्टेट
it's flowing but if i find my head
इट्स फ्लोइंग बट इफ इफ आई फाइंड माय हेड
Manipulating Thinking Crafting That
मैनपुलेटिंग थिंकिंग क्राफ्टिंग दैट्स
why it's called which
व्हाई इट्स कॉल्ड व्हिच
Craft My Brain Is Crafting Now
क्राफ्ट माय ब्रेन इज़ क्राफ्टिंग नाउ
something and I want to play a show somewhere
समथिंग एंड आई वांट टू प्ले अ शो समवेयर
then its abuse of that siddhi and thats
देन इट्स अब्यूज ऑफ़ दैट सिद्धि एंड दैट्स
not what it was given to you
नॉट व्हाट इट वास गिवन टू यू
for comfortable talking about siddhi a
फॉर कंफर्टेबल टॉकिंग अबाउट सिद्धि अ
Little Bit Yes Why Not When We Say
लिटिल बिट यस व्हाई नॉट व्हेन वी से
Hanuman ji is the giver of Ashtasiddhi no Nidhi
हनुमान जी इज़ अष्टसिद्धि नो निधि के दाता
Lee what does that statement mean and
ली व्हाट डस दैट स्टेटमेंट मीन एंड
secondly are there at siddhis only and are
सेकंडली आर देयर एट सिद्धिस ओनली और आर
There are infinite number of siddhis here
देयर इनफाइनाइट नंबर ऑफ़ सिद्धि देर
Infinite number of siddhis and what could
इनफाइनाइट नंबर ऑफ़ सिद्धिज़ एंड व्हाट कुड
Be a very understandable siddhi for someone
बी अ वेरी अंडरस्टैंडेबल सिद्धि फॉर समवन
who never heard the term siddhi it's it
हुज़ नेवर हर्ड द टर्म सिद्धि इट्स इट्स
Actualization when we talk about a group
एक्चुअलाइजेशन व्हेन वी टॉक अबाउट अ ग्रुप
of sales a colony of sales okay when you
ऑफ़ सेल्स अ कॉलोनी ऑफ़ सेल्स ओके व्हेन यू
Talk about a group of cells or a colony
टॉक अबाउट अ ग्रुप ऑफ़ सेल्स और अ कॉलोनी
of sale when there is actualization and
ऑफ़ सेल व्हेन देयर इज़ एक्चुअलाइज़ेशन एंड
maximisation of
मैक्सिमाइजेशन ऑफ़
consciousness completely in full form than the
कॉन्शियसनेस कंप्लीटली इन फुल फॉर्म देन द
Shakti their siddhi word is related to
शक्ति देयर सिद्धि वर्ड इज़ रिलेटेड टू
Shakti it's not related to consciousness
शक्ति इट्स नॉट रिलेटेड टू कॉन्शियसनेस
it is related to shakti because that means that
इट्स रिलेटेड टू शक्ति बिकॉज़ दैट मींस दैट
Shakti is got it is come in its full
शक्ति इज़ गॉट इज़ इज़ इज़ कम इन इट्स फुल
Form like a player comes in its full
फॉर्म लाइक अ प्लेयर कम्स इन इट्स फुल
form right so that means you have
फॉर्म राइट सो दैट मींस यू हैव
Actualized and maximized that power
एक्चुअलाइज्ड एंड मैक्सिमाइज्ड दैट शक्ति
point over there so group of sales now are
पॉइंट ओवर देयर सो ग्रुप ऑफ़ सेल्स नाउ आर
Holding on to a maximum of an ability
होल्डिंग ऑन टू अ मैक्सिमम अह अ एबिलिटी
Of the power and this can be push anywhere.
ऑफ़ द शक्ति एंड दिस कैन बी पुश् एनीवेयर।
It can be pushed anywhere. so a the seeker
इट कैन बी पुश् एनीवेयर। सो ए द साधक
Realises that he is God, a siddhi. First
रियलाइज़ेस दैट ही इज़ गॉड अ सिद्धि। फर्स्ट
Of all that does not happen. rarely it
ऑफ़ ऑल वो होता नहीं है। रेयरली इट
happens because he is in so much
हैप्पेंस बिकॉज़ ही इज़ इन सो मच
Humility. If he is a real seeker. he is
ह्यूमिलिटी। इफ ही इज़ अ रियल साधक। ही इज़
In so much humility. there are people set off
इन सो मच ह्यूमिलिटी। देयर आर पीपल सेट ऑफ़
people who are pursuing siddhis and they are
पीपल हु आर पर्सुइंग सिद्धिज़ एंड दे आर
Doing Sadhana only for the sake of Siddhi.
डूइंग साधना ओनली फॉर द सेक ऑफ़ सिद्धि।
Which happens or may not happen. it may happen
व्हिच हैपेंस ऑर मे नॉट हैपन। इट मे हैपन
Or it may not happen. but if a seeker is
ऑर इट मे नॉट हैपन। बट इफ अ साधक इज
Sincere and on his path is emulsifying
सिंसियर एंड ऑन हिज पाथ इज़ इमल्गमेटिंग
and you know melting his ego and on the
एंड यू नो मेल्टिंग हिज ईगो एंड ऑन द
Sadhna his focus is not on the siddhi
साधना हिज अटेंशन इज़ नॉट ऑन द सिद्धि
Siddhis Come To Him
सिद्धिस कम टू हिम
anyway siddhis come to him anyway it's a bye
एनीवे सिद्धिस कम टू हिम एनीवे इट्स अ बाय
product of self
प्रोडक्ट ऑफ़ सेल्फ
Actualization One Colony of Sales
एक्चुअलाइज़ेशन वन वन कॉलोनी ऑफ़ सेल्स
Getting Activated in the Body Is
गेटिंग एक्टिवेट एक्टिवेटेड इन द बॉडी इज़
Like one's own accomplishment and the aim being that yours
लाइक वन वन सिद्धि एंड द ऐम बीइंग दैट योर
The whole body has become completely activated.
होल बॉडी हैज़ बिकम कंप्लीटली एक्टिवेटेड।
You know that energy is fair to say that hour
यू नो विथ दैट एनर्जी फेयर टू से दैट आवर
The Human Body Mind and Spirit Holds Much
ह्यूमन बॉडी माइंड एंड स्पिरिट होल्ड्स मच
More potential than we are told in the text
मोर पोटेंशियल दैट वी आर टोल्ड इन टेक्स्ट
books yes so there are siddhis packed into
बुक्स यस सो देयर आर सिद्धिस पैक्ड इंटू
each one of our bodies also yes but for the once
ईच वन ऑफ़ आवर बॉडीज आल्सो यस बट फॉर द वंस
Who aligns themselves with the practices
हु अलाइन देमसेल्व्स विथ द प्रैक्टिससेस
you actually end up seeing those siddhis
यू एक्चुअली एंड अप सीइंग दोज़ सिद्धिज़
Manifest Realities or the End of the World
मैनिफेस्ट रियलिटीज़ या एंड द एंड द
Ashtasiddhis and these names that you hear of
अष्टसिद्धिज एंड दीज़ नेम्स दैट यू हियर ऑफ़
the siddhis these are coming from
द सिद्धिज़ दीज़ आर कमिंग फ्रॉम
Our Traditional Scripture Churl Books. So
आवर ट्रेडिशनल स्क्रिप्चर चुरल बुक्स। सो
there is a limit to what is written
दे देयर इज़ अ लिमिट टू व्हाट इज़ रिटन
There. There is much more in the universe than
देयर। देयर इज़ मच मोर इन द यूनिवर्स देन
That. much more that doesn't have a nomenclature
दैट। मच मोर दैट डजंट हैव अ नोमनक्लेचर
Yet. Correct correct. much more that can be
येट। करेक्ट करेक्ट। मच मोर दैट कैन बी
Named in the future.
नेम्ड इन फ्यूचर।
what is n
व्हाट इज़ एन
Understanding Siddhi That You Can Talk
अंडरस्टैंडिंग सिद्धि दैट यू कैन टॉक
about. so that people have a context on
अबाउट। सो दैट पीपल हैव अ कॉनंटेक्स्ट ऑन
what is this. The simplest of the siddhi is
व्हाट दिस इज़। द सिंपलेस्ट ऑफ़ द सिद्धि इज़
Of archsiddhi. when you are doing naam
ऑफ़ आर्कसिद्धि। व्हेन यू आर डूइंग नाम
Remembrance, Nam Japa and when you are doing your
स्मरण, नाम जपा एंड व्हेन यू डूइंग योर
devotion regularly meditation regularly and
भक्ति रेगुलरली मेडिटेशन रेगुलरली एंड
Following the Yama Niyamas of Choosing the Right Way
फॉलोइंग द यम नियमाज़ चूजिंग अ राइट वे ऑफ़
Life is coming more in discipline making
लाइफ कमिंग मोर इन डिसिप्लिन मेकिंग
Conscious choices make you achieve success
कॉन्शियस चॉइससेस यू गेट वाक सिद्धि इज़ अ
Easiest siddhi vak siddhi is the power of
इज़ियस्ट सिद्धि वाक सिद्धि इज़ द पावर ऑफ़
Speech the colony of cells here get
स्पीच द कॉलोनी ऑफ़ सेल्स हियर गेट
Activate the Chakras and Get Divined
एक्टिवेटेड दे गेट डिविनाइज्ड द चक्र
Gates Divined. whatever you say comes
गेट्स डिविनाइज्ड। व्हाटएवर यू से कम्स
True. Vak siddhi is whatever you say
ट्रू। वाक सिद्धि इज़ व्हाटएवर यू से कम्स
True. it has to manifest because it
ट्रू। इट हैज़ टू मैनिफेस्ट बिकॉज़ इट
Becomes the power. it becomes a command that the
बिकम्स द पावर। इट्स बिकम्स अ कमांड दैट द
The universe has to accept.
यूनिवर्स हैज़ टू एक्सेप्ट।
Ok. you know so that's a that's one of the
ओके। यू नो सो दैट्स अ दैट्स वन ऑफ़ द
Easiest one than manifestation. some people have
इज़िएस्ट वन देन मैनिफेस्टेशन। सम पीपल हैव
More manifesting power than others. So two
मोर मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग पावर देन अदर्स। सो दोज़
who are you again everything is related to
हु आर अगेन एवरीथिंग इज़ रिलेटेड टू
Discipline and Practice. for some people are
डिसिप्लिन एंड प्रैक्टिस। फॉर सम पीपल आर
Born with the Siddhis. for example if
बोर्न विद दी सिद्धिज़। फॉर एग्जांपल इफ
someone has been a seeker in his previous life
समवन हैज़ वाज़ अ साधक इन हज़ प्रीवियस लाइफ
time and had done a lot of tapa tapa and
टाइम एंड हैड डन अ लॉट ऑफ़ तपा तपस्या एंड
have worked you know on all his ah energy
हैव वर्क्ड यू नो ऑन ऑल हिज़ अह एनर्जी
The system and he lets his body end
सिस्टम एंड ही लेट्स से हिज़ बॉडी एंडेड
that life ended now he is born again
दैट लाइफ एंडेड नाउ ही इज़ बोर्न अगेन अ
new born he is born with what it carries
न्यू बोर्न ही इज़ बोर्न विथ दैट इट्स कैरी
forward he is born with all of that
फॉरवर्ड ही इज़ बोर्न विथ ऑल ऑफ़ दैट
the attainment that he had in his previous life
अटेनमेंट दैट ही हैड इन हिज़ प्रीवियस लाइफ
time and as a kid he is born with
टाइम एंड ऐज़ अ किड ही इज़ बोर्न विथ
siddhis you see so many youngsters you see
सिद्धिस यू सी सो मेनी यंगस्टर्स यू सी
These are the miraculous children everywhere young
दिस दे मिरेकुलस चिल्ड्रन एवरीवेयर यंग
small boys and girls you know what they are
स्मॉल बॉयज एंड गर्ल्स यू नो सो दे आर
Born with their Siddhas and so this life
बोर्न विथ देयर सिद्धस एंड सो दिस लाइफ
Time is a very limitation to understand
टाइम इज़ अ वेरी लिमिटेशन टू अंडरस्टैंड
Very Big Limitation Here We Get Confused
वेरी बिग लिमिटेशन हियर वी गेट कन्फ्यूज्ड
A common man would get confused why he
अ कॉमन मैन वुड गेट कन्फ्यूज्ड व्हाई ही
why not me he did this for just one year
व्हाई नॉट मी ही डिड दिस फॉर जस्ट वन ईयर
and he has reached somewhere i am doing it
एंड ही हैज़ रीच्ड समवेर आई एम डूइंग इट
for eight years i haven't reached anywhere
फॉर एट इयर्स आई हैव नॉट रीच्ड एनीवेयर
his previous account is not taken into
हिज़ प्रीवियस अकाउंट इज़ नॉट टेकन इनटू
Calculate
कैलकुलेट
session for instance u have maharathis maha
ेशन फॉर इंस्टेंस यू हैव महारथीस महा
Rishis like Raman Maharshi and you know and many
ऋषिज़ लाइक रमन महर्षि एंड यू नो एंड मेनी
Other Saints from Childhood They've Been
अदर सेंट्स दे फ्रॉम चाइल्डहुड दे हैव बीन
Saintly they have been saintly and they have
सेंटली दे हैव बीन सेंटली एंड दे हैव
Born with the wisdom of an 80 year old man
बोर्न विथ द विज़डम ऑफ़ अ 80 ईयर ओल्ड मैन
or a very very awakened man what's the
ऑर अ वेरी वेरी अवेकन मैन व्हाट्स द
partiality god is doing here that someone
पार्शियलिटी गॉड इज़ डूइंग हियर दैट समवन
is born with this light and someone is not
इज़ बोर्न विथ दिस लाइट एंड समवन इज़ नॉट
Born with the Light and Born with Darkness
बोर्न विथ द लाइट एंड बोर्न विथ डार्कनेस
in the head what is this partiality it is
इन द हेड व्हाट इज़ दिस पार्शियलिटी इट्स
nothing there is no partiality
नथिंग देयर इज़ नो पार्शियलिटी िटी
Everything Goes in Law & Order Here There
एवरीथिंग गोज़ इन लॉ एंड ऑर्डर हियर देयर
There is a perfect order in the universe. there
इज़ अ परफेक्ट ऑर्डर इन द यूनिवर्स। देयर
There is a law of cause and effect that is working
इज़ अ लॉ ऑफ़ कॉज़ एंड इफ़ेक्ट दैट इज़ वर्किंग
and the accounts are maintained flawlessly
एंड द अकाउंट्स आर मेंटेंड फ्लोलेसली
Without any error. The Human Body in Fact
विदाउट एनी एरर। द ह्यूमन बॉडी इन फ़ैक्ट
Is a flawless machine. Automated Flawless Machine
इज़ अ फ्लोलेस मशीन। ऑटोमेटेड फ्लोलेस मशीन
where everything is happening automatically
व्हेयर एव्रीथिंग इज़ हैपनिंग ऑटोमेटिकली
Without your conscious interference in it.
विदाउट योर कॉन्शियस इंटरफेरेंस इन इट।
your digestive system is working,
योर योर डाइजेस्टिव सिस्टम इज़ वर्किंग,
The excretory system is working,
एक्सक्रीटरी सिस्टम इज़ वर्किंग,
The circulatory system is working. there is so
सर्कुलेटरी सिस्टम इज़ वर्किंग। देयर इज़ सो
True miniscule minute detailing in
सच मा मिनिस्क्युल माइन्यूड डिटेलिंग इन
All these processes. we don't have to have the
ऑल दिस प्रोसेससेस। वी डोंट हैवन हैव द
Ability to understand these processes
एबिलिटी टू अंडरस्टैंड दीज प्रोसेससेस
Fully. Leave it to them having any control over
फुल्ली। लीव अड हैविंग एनी कंट्रोल ओवर
It. I don't know why I am asking you
इट। आई डोंट नो व्हाई आई एम आस्किंग यू
This question. but whenever we have them
दिस क्वेश्चन। बट व्हेनएवर वी हैव दी
Spiritual Conversations Were Usually
स्पिरिचुअल कन्वर्सेशन वेयर यूजुअली
talking about such subjects weather
टॉकिंग अबाउट अह सब्जेक्ट्स वेदर
Context is age zero to age 80 and 90
कॉन्टेक्स्ट इज़ एज ज़ीरो टू एज 80 और 90
When you pass away. what about the phase of
व्हेन यू पास अवे। व्हाट अबाउट द फेज ऑफ
The time which happens after you pass away in
टाइम व्हिच हैपेंस आफ्टर यू पास अवे इन
Terms of if you have done the sadhana through out
टर्म्स ऑफ इफ यू हैव डन द साधना थ्रूआउट
Your Life But You Have Not Reached Enlightenment
योर लाइफ बट यू हैव नॉट रीच्ड एनलाइटनमेंट
you got a come back to this realm so between the
यू गॉट अ कम बैक टू दिस रेल्म सो बिटवीन द
the next birth and this birth while you are
नेक्स्ट बर्थ एंड दिस बर्थ व्हाइल यू आर
Spending time up there and down there do you
स्पेंडिंग टाइम अप देर और डाउन देर डू यू
Get to interact with the date? this this
गेट टू इंटरक्ट विथ द डेटीस? दिस दिस
also a two schools have thought that duality and
आल्सो अ टू स्कूल्स हैव थॉट दैट द्वैत एंड
Advaita think differently about this. The Soul
अद्वैत थिंक डिफरेंटली अबाउट दिस। द सोल
has been different from the whole game of
हैज़ बीन डिफरेंट फ्रॉम द होल गेम ऑफ
Consciousness. itself is advaita
कॉन्शियसनेस। इटसेल्फ इज़ अद्वैत
Perspective Where It Travels and Goes
पर्सेपेक्टिव व्हेयर इट ट्रैवल्स एंड गोज़
to different realms and goes through four heavens
टू डिफरेंट रेलम्स एंड गोज़ थ्रू फोर हेवंस
And then it's coming back on the Earth. The
एंड देन इज़ कमिंग बैक ऑन द अर्थट्रा। द
Stories as the Stories and the Explanations
स्टोरीज़ एज़ द स्टोरीज़ एंड द एक्सप्लेनेशन
As written in the Puranas, different
एज़ रिटन इन द पुराणाज़, डिफरेंट
Scriptures, different Puranas talk about the
स्क्रिप्चर्स, डिफरेंट पुराण टॉक अबाउट द
Different journeys of the soul you know after death.
डिफरेंट जर्नीज़ ऑफ़ द सोल यू नो आफ्टर डेथ।
Advaita which is non dual consciousness
अद्वैता व्हिच इज़ नॉन डुअल कॉन्शियसनेस
talks about there is a screen there is
टॉक्स अबाउट देयर इज़ अ स्क्रीन देयर इज़
Consciousness. Ok? Now there is a ring.
कॉन्शियसनेस। ओके? नाउ देयर इज़ अ रिंग।
Imagine a ring which is your causal body.
इमेजिन अ रिंग व्हिच इज़ योर कॉज़ल बॉडी।
Which is your destiny. Let's Say It
व्हिच इज़ योर डेस्टिनी। लेट्स से इट्स
Coloured red and blue. in this life your cause
कलर्ड रेड एंड ब्लू। इन दिस लाइफ योर कॉज़ल
The body is colored red and blue. your story
बॉडी इज़ कलर्ड रेड एंड ब्लू। योर स्टोरी
Is red and blue. You are living this life.
इज़ रेड एंड ब्लू। यू आर लिविंग दिस लाइफ।
And you are doing some effort. you are
एंड यू आर डूइंग सम पुरुषार्थ। यू आर
doing podcast and you're doing this and
डूइंग पॉडकास्ट एंड यू आर डूइंग दिस एंड
You are doing a lot of good work for people. you are
यू डूइंग लॉट ऑफ़ गुड वर्क फॉर पीपल। यू आर
En Lightning Your Masses and You Are a Fan
एन लाइटनिंग योर मासेस एंड यू आर फैन
Followings and so, all of this is adding some
फॉलोइंग्स एंड सो, ऑल ऑफ़ दिस इज़ एडिंग सम
Golden color to your red and blue. Allright.
गोल्डन कलर टु योर रेड एंड ब्लू। ऑलराइट।
and if there's anything bad some black
एंड इफ़ देर एनीथिंग एनी बैड सम ब्लैक
Spots are added to it. Ok? now your life
स्पॉट्स आर एडेड टु इट। ओके? नाउ योर लाइफ
Time Gates Over Physical Life Time Gates
टाइम गेट्स ओवर फिजिकल लाइफ टाइम गेट्स
over you leave the shut this body it's only
ओवर यू लीव द शट दिस बॉडी इट्स ओनली
dropping down the body just like you would
ड्रॉपिंग डाउन द बॉडी जस्ट लाइक यू वुड
drop a shirt you just drop this body this
ड्रॉप अ शर्ट यू जस्ट ड्रॉप दिस बॉडी दिस
The ring is not moving anywhere this ring is
रिंग इज़ नॉट मूविंग एनीवेयर दिस रिंग इज़
Here and in the back drop of this ring they
हियर एंड इन द बैक ड्रॉप ऑफ दिस रिंग दे
Pure Consciousness Pure Light Now for the
प्योर कॉन्शियसनेस प्योर लाइट नाउ फॉर द
Next Lifetime Next Human
नेक्स्ट लाइफटाइम नेक्स्ट ह्यूमन
embodiment this ring color changes a little the
एंबोडीमेंट दिस रिंग कलर चेंजज़ अ लिटिल द
Soul chooses to play a different role
सोल चूज़ टू प्ले डिफरेंट रोल अ डिफरेंट
The script and these black spots
स्क्रिप्ट एंड दीज़ ब्लैक ब्लैक स्पॉट्स
Will remain here. this is golden that you did
विल रिमेन हियर। दीज़ गोल्डन दैट यू डिड
Will remain here. And now the color of the ring
विल रिमेन हियर। एंड नाउ द कलर ऑफ़ द रिंग
Pink and Green from Is Coming. Consciousness
इज़ कमिंग से पिंक एंड ग्रीन। कॉन्शियसनेस
That means the back drop is not changing at
दैट मींस द बैक ड्रॉप इज़ नॉट चेंजिंग एट
All. Consciousness is remaining. what does that mean
ऑल। कॉन्शियसनेस इज़ रिमेनिंग। दैट मींस
here we are four people with are no four
हियर वी आर फोर पीपल विद आर नो फोर
Brahmanas. this is one brahmin in which
ब्राह्मणस। दिस इज़ वन ब्राह्मण इन व्हिच
The four rings are operating. You get it? Yes.
फोर रिंग्स आर ऑपरेटिंग। यू गेट इट? यस।
so when i leave this body my body will be
सो व्हेन आई लीव दिस बॉडी माय बॉडी विल बी
Discard and go back to nature and I see this
डिस्कारेड एंड बैक टू नेचर एंड आई दिस
The ring will embody another body in the form of
रिंग विल एंबोडी अनदर बॉडी इन द फॉर्म ऑफ
a baby will grow and this ring will remain
अ बेबी एंड विल ग्रो दिस रिंग विल रिमेन
in this in this ah body for as long as
इन द इन दिस इन दिस अह बॉडी फॉर एज़ लॉन्ग
as the body will live so there is no question
एज़ द बॉडी विल लिव सो देयर इज़ नो क्वेश्चन
of losing data number one there is no
ऑफ़ लूजिंग डेटा नंबर वन देयर इज़ नो
The question of losing data the data is there
क्वेश्चन ऑफ़ लूजिंग डेटा द डेटा इज़ देयर
It's there and you can tap into this data
इट्स देयर एंड यू कैन टैप इंटू दिस डेटा
As much as you want for instance wisdom all
एज़ मच एज़ यू वांट फॉर इंस्टेंस विज़डम ऑल
All the golden things that you have earned in this life
ऑल द गोल्डन दैट यू हैव अर्न इन दिस लाइफ
time let's say in the next life time you
टाइम लेट्स से इन द नेक्स्ट लाइफ टाइम यू
Forgotten about it you can tap into it and
फॉरगॉटन अबाउट इट यू कैन टैप इनू इट एंड
revive this golden this power this gleam
रिवाइव दिस गोल्डन दिस दिस पावर दिस ग्लीम
this shine that people who are in yoga or into
दिस शाइन दैट पीपल हु आर इनू योगा ओर इंटू
spirituality and to mysticism this
स्पिरिचुअलिटी एंड टू मिस्टिसिज्म दिस
The glow and the gleam that you see on there
ग्लो एंड दैट ग्लीम दैट यू सी ऑन देयर
Faces and in their ora is nothing but the old
फेसेस एंड इन देयर ओरा इज़ नथिंग बट द ओल्ड
reviving and coming and surfacing into the
रिवाइविंग एंड कमिंग एंड सरफेसिंग इंटू द
The present life where everybody has everybody
प्रेजेंट लाइफ व्हिच एवरीबडी हैज़ एवरीबडी
Haze
हैज़
ok back to the mahavidyas yes answered my
ओके बैक टू द महाविद्यास यस आंसर्ड माय
Tangent so you know the three lower Mahavidyas
टेंजेंट सो यू नो द थ्री लोअर महाविद्यास
Baglamukhi Matangi Full of Magic Mysticism
बगलामुखी मातंगी फुल ऑफ़ मैजिक मिस्टिसिज्म
That's why maximum experiments are done with
दैट्स व्हाई मैक्सिमम प्रयोग आर डन विद
These Baglamukhi Matangi and Kamalatmika
दीज़ बगलामुखी मातंगी एंड कमलात्मिका
Kamalatmika Yes Kamalatmika is a kid
कमलात्मिक हां कमलात्मिका इज अ किड
lakshmi mahalakshmi ok kamalatmika is
लक्ष्मी महालक्ष्मी ओके कमलात्मिका इज़
Just like Mahalakshmi seated on a lotus and
जस्ट लाइक महालक्ष्मी सीटेड ऑन अ लोटस एंड
seated on a lotus and so she gives you the
सीटेड ऑन अ लोटस एंड सो शी शी गिव्स यू द
siddhi of wealth and you know everything and
सिद्धि ऑफ़ वेल्थ एंड यू नो एवरीथिंग एंड
Matangi is absolutely beautiful
मातंगी इज़ इज़ इज़ अबब्सोलुटली ब्यूटीफुल
Crafty Goddess. you know the parrot sings with her
क्राफ्टी देवी। यू नो द पैरेट सिंग विथ हर
and she is often depicted with a veena and
एंड शी इज़ ऑफन डिपिक्टेड विथ अ वीना एंड
very she is dark
वेरी शी इज़ डार्क
And she is called Uchchishta Devi. Maxima
एंड शी इज़ कॉल्ड उच्चिष्ट देवी। उच्चिष्ट
Devi means she is one of the goddesses that you
देवी मतलब शी इज़ वन ऑफ़ द देवीज़ दैट यू
Worship happens in any way she will accept it.
वरशिप हवे इन एनी वे शी विल एक्सेप्ट इट।
With lots of goddesses. there are the lots of
विथ लॉट ऑफ़ देवीज़। देयर आर द लॉट ऑफ़
Rituals That People Are Very Careful About
रिचुअल्स दैट पीपल आर वेरी केयरफुल अबाउट
Cleanliness and Hydran and Left Hand
क्लेंलीनेस एंड हाइड्रन एंड लेफ्ट हैंड
and right hand and this cloth and that
एंड राइट हैंड एंड दिस वस्त्र एंड दैट
Clothes. Matangi is one goddess that will
वस्त्र। मातंगी इज़ वन देवी दैट विल
Accept whatever you do. there was a very
एक्सेप्ट व्हाटएवर यू डू। देयर वाज़ अ वेरी
Beautiful There is a very beautiful South
ब्यूटीफुल देयर इज़ अ वेरी ब्यूटीफुल साउथ
Indian Movie Ah In Which There Is A Goddess
इंडियन मूवी अह इन व्हिच देयर इज़ अ देवी
Shon looks like matangi to me.
शोन लुक्स लाइक मातंगी टू मी।
and there is a big pendol and a big
एंड देयर इज अ बिग पेंडोल एंड अ बिग
function happening in that home because they are there
फंक्शन हैपनिंग इन दैट होम बिकॉज़ दे दे वर
calling somebody like
कॉलिंग समबडी लाइक
Shankaracharya status person to come and do the
शंकराचार्य स्टेटस पर्सन टू कम एंड डू द
Worship of that goddess. so ah panchbhog and so
वरशिप ऑफ़ दैट देवी। सो अह पंचभोग एंड सो
Much of ah prasad and everything was done. in
मच ऑफ़ अह प्रसाद एंड एवरीथिंग वाज़ डन। इन
That house. there was a servant made you know
दैट हाउस। देयर वाज़ अ सर्वेंट मेड यू नो
Who is working and she is in love with Devi.
हु इज़ वर्किंग एंड शी इज़ इन लव विथ दवी।
but she is obviously not allowed to come there
बट शी इज़ ऑब्वियसली नॉट अलाउड टू कम देयर
And do things because she is a worker. So
एंड डु थिंग्स बिकॉज़ शी इज़ अह अ वर्कर। सो
she in her small plate you know does everything
शी इन हर स्माल प्लेट यू नो डस एवरीथिंग
what the priest was doing giving prasad
व्हाट द पुजारी वास डूइंग गिविंग प्रसाद
Giving this then she was tasting and seeing
गिविंग दिस देन शी वाज़ टेस्टिंग एंड सीइंग
If That Little She Made Was Good or Not
इफ दैट व्हाट लिटिल शी मेड वाज़ गुड ऑर नॉट
And they show that when the invocation actually occurs
एंड दे शो दैट व्हेन द इनवोकेशन एक्चुअली
happens thee is not sitting in that
हैप्पेंस दवी इज़ नॉट सिटींग इन दैट
statue which is there she comes and sits
प्रतिमा व्हिच इज़ देयर शी कम्स एंड सीट्स
in every plate you know it's a very beautiful
इन हर प्लेट यू नो इट्स अ वेरी ब्यूटीफुल
Depiction It's a Story But the Ethos Is Very
डिपिक्शन इट्स अ स्टोरी बट द एथोस इज़ वेरी
Clear that goddesses respond to love and
क्लियर दैट देवीज़ रिसोंड टू लव एंड
Sincerity especially the Mahavidyas de
सिंसियरिटी एस्पेशली द महाविद्यास दे
Respond to Love Sincerity and You Know What
रिस्पोंड टू लव सिंसियरिटी एंड यू नो आडंट
desire to be with her aunt desire to be
डिजायर टू टू बी विथ हर आंट डिजायर टू बी
with her to see her darshan you know and she
विथ हर टू सी हर हर दर्शन यू नो एंड शी
Resounds so Mahavidya the school that I
रिसोंड्स सो महाविद्या द स्कूल दैट आई
belong to there is no formality it should
बिलोंग टू देयर इज़ नो फॉर्मेलिटी इट शुड
Be Just Done Intense Sadhna with Meditation and
बी जस्ट डन इंटेंस साधना विथ मेडिटेशन एंड
Mantra Intense Sadhana with Meditation and
मंत्र इंटेंस साधना विद मेडिटेशन एंड
Mantra And And That's It But There Are
मंत्र एंड एंड दैट्स इट बट देयर आर
Other Schools Sri Vidya For
स्कूल्स अदर स्कूल श्री विद्या फॉर
Instance we have lots of schools here in
इंस्टेंस वी हैव लॉट ऑफ़ स्कूल्स हियर इन
India says down south you have it in the east
इंडिया सा डाउन साउथ यू हैव इन द ईस्ट
east of india in the north east also
ईस्ट ऑफ़ इंडिया इन द नॉर्थ ईस्ट आल्सो
Shri Vidya is very popular Shri Vidya
श्री विद्या इज़ वेरी पॉपुलर श्री विद्या
shodashi shodashi and that is tripura sundari the
शोडशी शोडशी एंड दैट इज़ त्रिपुर सुंदरी द
The Pyramid That You See You Know The Shree Yantra
पिरामिड दैट यू सी यू नो द श्री यंत्रा
Puja What You See The Shree Yantra Shree Yantra
पूजा व्हाट यू सी द श्री यंत्र श्री यंत्र
is a three dimensional picture of the yantra
इज़ अ थ्री डायमेंशनल पिक्चर ऑफ़ द यंत्र
that can be even flat the instruments you know we
दैट कैन बी इवन फ्लैट द यंत्रज़ यू नो वी
Have three kinds of yantras. you have a
हैव थ्री काइंड्स ऑफ़ यंत्राज़। यू हैव अ
Flat Surface We Call It. then there is
फ्लैट भूपृष्ठ वी कॉल इट। देन देयर इज़
Kurmapage. that means it's like a toto is
कुर्मपृष्ठ। दैट मींस इट्स लाइक अ टोटो इज़
Like a Semai circle. You Know. and then you
लाइक अ सेमाई सर्कल। यू नो। एंड देन यू
have a meru and a mountain like the way of shri
हैव अ मेरू और अ माउंटेन लाइक द वे द श्री
Yantra is what you know about the Sri Vidya tradition
यंत्र इज़ यू नो सो द श्री विद्या ट्रेडिशन
has evolved quite a lord in india v
हैज़ इवॉल्व्ड क्वाइट अ लॉर्ड इन इंडिया वी
have some very dynamic very powerful very
हैव सम वेरी डायनामिक वेरी पावरफुल वेरी
Good Schools Down South in Kerala and
गुड स्कूल्स डाउन साउथ इन केरला एंड
Tamilnadu Ah Which Import Sri Vidya
तमिलनाडु अह व्हिच इंपार्ट श्री विद्या
Maha Vidya is really an open school and really an open faith
महाविद्या सच अ ओपन स्कूल इज़ सच अ ओपन फेथ
that one could develop his own system according to
दैट वन कुड डेवलप हिज़ ओन सिस्टम अकॉर्डिंग
To the guidance of his master mentor he can
टू द गाइडेंस ऑफ़ हिज़ मास्टर मेंटोर ही कैन
developed his own system of worship even than the
डेवलप हिज़ ओन सिस्टम ऑफ़ वरशिप इवन देन द
shri de school which are existing there
श्री दे स्कूल व्हिच आर एकज़िस्टिंगली देयर
They are different ways of doing the worship. Even
दे आर डिफरेंट वेज़ ऑफ़ डूइंग द वरशिप। सम
people support ah take the support from lalita
पीपल सपोर्ट अह टेक द सपोर्ट फ्रॉम ललिता
SahasranÄma. some people take the support from
सहस्त्रनाम। सम पीपल टेक द सपोर्ट फ्रॉम
Khadgamala. you know there others towards assam
खड़गमाला। यू नो देयर अदर्स टुवर्ड्स आसाम
side and kolkata side which is completely
साइड एंड कोलकाता साइड व्हिच इज़ कंप्लीटली
Different. You know so it's not the last word.
डिफरेंट। यू नो सो इट्स नॉट द लास्ट वर्ड।
Belonging to a sect is like
बिलॉन्गिंग टू अ संप्रदाय इज़ लाइक
Belonging to a family were certain way off
बिलोंगिंग टू अ फैमिली वेयर सर्टेन वे ऑफ
Living is a burden. Right? Or
लिविंग इज फॉललोड। राइट? या
Ok. Let's speak about the three.
ओके। लेट्स स्पीक अबाउट दी थ्री।
you speak about matangi right now or what
यू स्पोक अबाउट मातंगी राइट नाउ या व्हाट
is the associated siddhi
इज द एसोसिएटेड सिद्धि
Craft You Know Mohini Sadhna Mohini Sadhna
क्राफ्ट यू नो मोहिनी साधना मोहिनी साधना
Vashikaran All of this goes with Matangi Sadhna
वशीकरण ऑल ऑफ दिस गोज़ विद मातंगी साधना
and basically because she is a mesmerizing
एंड बेसिकली बिकॉज़ शी इज़ अ मेस्मराइजिंग
Devi She is a Goddess that can mesmerize and
देवी शी इज़ अ देवी दैट कैन मेसमराइज एंड
she is a goddess that can give you power to
शी इज़ अ देवी दैट कैन गिव यू पावर टू
Mesmerize. so my take on this is you know my
मेसमराइज। सो माय टेक ऑन दिस इज यू नो माय
What is my take back of the sadhna
व्हाट व्हाट इज माय टेक बैक ऑफ द साधना
that i have done with this is that exploring
दैट आई हैव डन विथ दस इज दैट एक्सप्लोरिंग
Every Love Factor and If You Can Experience It
हर लव फैक्टर एंड इफ यू कैन एक्सपीरियंस
matangi in you you get her craft in your
मातंगी इन यू यू गेट हर क्राफ्ट इन योर
Hands Anything You Touch Can Be Divined
हैंड्स एनीथिंग यू टच कैन बी डिविनाइज्ड
anything you make can be divined i
एनीथिंग यू मेक कैन बी डिविनाइज्ड आई
Explore My Energy I Live In The
एक्सप्लोर माय एनर्जी आई लिव इन द
Hermitage I Live on My Own and I Live In
हर्मिटेड आय लिव ऑन माय ओन एंड आई लिव इन
Isolation and I Work with Stones
आइसोलेशन एंड आई वर्क विथ स्टोनस विथ
Plants with Herbs with So Many Things
प्लांट्स विथ हर्ब्स ्स वि सो मेनी थिंग्स
I made a very beautiful candle for you and
आई मेड अ वे ब्यूटीफुल कैंडल फॉर यू एंड
brought it yes with lots of mantras in it you
ब्रॉट इट यस विथ लॉट ऑफ़ मंत्रास इन इट यू
no i explore this manifestation of the
नो आई एक्सप्लोर दिस मैनिफेस्टेशन ऑफ द
Divine energy in every iota and part and
देवी एनर्जी इन एव्री आयोटा एंड पार्ट एंड
every grain of your living is the true
एव्री ग्रेन ऑफ योर लिविंग इज़ द ट्रू
Utility of this goddess to play these games
यूटिलिटी ऑफ़ दिस देवी टू प्ले दिस गेम्स
that can very easily get hooked on to your
दैट कैन वेरी ईजीली गेट हुक्क ऑन टू योर
Ego Like Things Like Vashikaran And Things
ईगो लाइक थिंग्स लाइक वशीकरण एंड थिंग्स
like you know ah mesmerizing someone taking
लाइक यू नो अह मेसम्मराइजिंग समवन टेकिंग
someones mind in control how good would that
समवनस माइंड इन कंट्रोल हाउ गुड वुड दैट
be this karma it is too complicated its
बी दिस कर्मा इट इज टू कॉम्प्लिकेटेड इट्स
Too complicated when you are a real seeker
टू कॉम्प्लिकेटेड व्हेन यू आर अ रियल साधक
Then you want to share your personnel
देन यू वांट टू शेयर ऑफ योर कार्मिक
Patterns Rather Than Pile On More and More
पैटर्न्स रादर देन पाइल ऑन मोर एंड एनी
kind of interaction with another human being
काइंड ऑफ़ इंटरक्शन विथ अनदर ह्यूमन बीइंग
Create a positive or negative will
वेदर पॉजिटिव और नेगेटिव विल क्रिएट करो
or 100% like even if I'm having a two
या 100% लाइक इवन इफ आई एम हैविंग अ टू
Sentence Conversation with Someone That is 100% N
सेंटेंस कन्वर्सेशन विथ समवन दैट 100% एन
Intention Forget About Conversation Even If
इंटेंशन फॉरगेट अबाउट कन्वर्सेशन इवन इफ
you have an intention in your heart
यू हैव एन इंटेंशन इन योर हार्ट
to utilize this for something that has also
टू यूटिलाइज दिस फॉर समथिंग दैट हैज़ आल्सो
Created Karma Even Thought Creates Karma
क्रिएटेड कर्मा इवन थॉट क्रिएट्स कर्मा
Enough thought creates more karma than action really
इनफ थॉट क्रिएट मोर कर्मा देन एक्शन रियली
Yes Thought Creates More Karma Than Action N
यस थॉट क्रिएट्स मोर कर्मा देन एक्शन एन
unevolved ignorant person if he goes and
अनइवॉल्व्ड इग्नोरेंट पर्सन इफ ही गोज़ एंड
slaps a boy on the street it will create
स्लैप्स अ बॉय ऑन द स्ट्रीट इट विल क्रिएट
A karma but not as bad as if I visualize it
अ कर्मा बट नॉट एज़ बैड एज़ इफ आई विजुअलाइज़
that's where I'm going and slumping that boy just
दैट आई एम गोइंग एंड स्लपिंग दैट बॉय जस्ट
Visualize and have an intention I wanna go
विजुअलाइज़ और हैव एन इंटेंशन आई वांट गो
and slap that boy it created a bigger
एंड स्लैप दैट बॉय इट्स क्रिएटेड अ बिगर
Karma Seed That Man Who's Actually Gone
कर्मा सीड दैट मैन द मैन हुस एक्चुअली गॉन
and slapped him why do because you are not
एंड स्लेप्ड हिम व्हाई दो बिकॉज़ यू आर नॉट
Causing physical harm by thought is easy
कॉजिंग फिजिकल हार्म बाय थॉट थॉट इज इज़ इज़
a wave is a vibration nazar thought is a wave is
अ वेव इज अ वाइब्रेशन नज़र थॉट इज अ वेव इज़
a vibration just like bad luck is like you
अ वाइब्रेशन जस्ट लाइक बैड नज़र इज लाइक यू
Putting an eye on that boy on that boy and more
पुटिंग नज़र ऑन दैट बॉय ऑन दैट बॉय और मोर
then you are evolved see anybody who is
देन दैट यू आर इवॉल्व्ड सी एनीबडी हु इज़
Doing Experiments or Is Wanting to
डूइंग प्रयोग और इज़ वांटिंग टू
Experiment with these things is obvious
एक्सपेरिमेंट विथ दीज़ थिंग्स इज़ ऑब्वियसली
An Evolved Person Evolved Soul Right A
अ इवॉल्व्ड पर्सन इवॉल्व्ड सोल राइट अ
An ordinary man wouldn't want to do anything
ऑर्डिनरी मैन वुडंट वांट टू डू एनीथिंग
ok he is a help
ओके ही इज़ अ हेल्प
Helpless you know living an ordinary life.
हेल्पलेस यू नो लिविंग अ ऑर्डिनरी लाइफ।
so an evolved person having the intention to
सो एन इवॉल्व पर्सन हैविंग द इंटेंशन टू
control someone in
कंट्रोल समवन इन
it itself is a huge karma
इटसेल्फ इज़ अ ह्यूज कर्मा
Creation. This goes into the golden womb. it's
क्रिएशन। दिस गोज़ इनू द हिरण्य गर्भ। इट्स
like in very ordinary language if a poor
लाइक इन वेरी ऑर्डिनरी लैंग्वेज इफ अ पुअर
man on the street a beggar a rickshaw wala or
मैन ऑन द स्ट्रीट अ बेगर अ रिक्शा वाला या
Someone it just picks up a â‚¹100 from someone
समवन इट जस्ट पिक्स अप अ ₹100 फ्रॉम समवंस
Pocket. he rubs lets say â‚¹100 from someone
पॉकेट। ही रब्स लेट्स से ₹100 फ्रॉम समवंस
Pocket. It will create a karma. but it wont
पॉकेट। इट विल क्रिएट अ कर्मा। बट इट वोंट
create such a big karma as much as i go
क्रिएट सच अ बिग कर्मा एस मच एस इफ आई गो
and pick up a â‚¹1 from someone's purse when
एंड पिक अप अ ₹1 फ्रॉम समवनस पर्स व्हेन
You are evolved as a soul and you are born with
यू आर इवॉल्वड अ सोल एंड यू आर बोर्न विथ
awareness and you have been blessed with the
अवेयरनेस एंड यू हैव बीन ब्लेस्ड विथ द
Higher Deeper Knowing of the Universe and You Can
हायर डीपर नोइंग ऑफ द यूनिवर्स एंड यू कैन
See the Substratum and You Can Lift Up and
सी द सबस्ट्रेटम एंड यू कैन लिफ्ट अप एंड
Look into the Karma cycle and the cause and the
लुक इंटू द कर्मा साइकिल एंड द कॉज एंड द
effect with this deep understanding if you
इफेक्ट विथ दिस डीप अंडरस्टैंडिंग इफ यू
do a petty something it creates a huge
डू अ पेटी समथिंग इट क्रिएट्स अ ह्यूज
Karma
कर्मा
The Higher You Climb The Harder You Will Fall
द हायर यू क्लाइम द हार्डर यू विल फॉल
that's it
दैट्स इट
OK WE SPOKE ON MATANGI RIGHT NOW
ओके वी स्पोक ऑन मातंगी राइट नाउ
Associated We Craft And Ya Mohini Sadhna
असोसिएटेड वि क्राफ्ट एंड या मोहिनी साधना
Mostly Vashikaran Mohini Sadhna and Also
मोस्टली वशीकरण मोहिनी साधना एंड आल्सो
Lot of
लॉट ऑफ़
Small Fragments of These Sadhna Diez
स्मॉल फ्रेगमेंट्स ऑफ दीज़ साधना दीज़
Experiment are done you know they prepare talisman and
प्रयोग आर डन यू नो दे प्रिपेयर तावीज़ एंड
they prepare you know all kinds of things
दे प्रिपेयर यू नो ऑल काइंड्स ऑफ़ थिंग्स
to eat extra they are all fragments of
टू ईट एक्सट्रा दे आर ऑल फ्रेगमेंट्स ऑफ़
these are two sadhnas basically if you want to
दीज़ टू साधनाज़ बेसिकली इफ यू वांट टू
Pursue the Goddess Matangi to a very deep
पर्स्यू से गॉडेस मातंगी टू अ वेरी डीप
Degree How Much Time Do You Have to Dedicate
डिग्री हाउ मच टाइम डू यू हैव टू डेडिकेट
Depends on your soul's back
डिपेंड्स ऑन योर सोल्स बैक
Journey for Instance It Doesn't Take Any Time
जर्नी फॉर इंस्टेंस इट डजंट टेक एनी टाइम
for me because i think i am the only one
फॉर मी बिकॉज़ आई थिंक आई एम आई एम ओनली
Living my past lives is my life
लिविंग माय पास्ट लाइफ्स मेरे को इस लाइफ
I haven't worked very hard
में तो मैंने ज्यादा मेहनत करी नहीं है आई
have work very hard in this life you really
हैव वर्क वैरी हार्ड इन दिस लाइफ यू रियली
Think Despite Living Alone Doing Sadhna I
थिंक डिस्पाइट लिविंग अलोन डूइंग साधना आई
think so
थिंक सो
ok or
ओके या
But the Sadhna Wood Entails and Elaborates
बट बट द साधना वुड एंटेल एंड इलैबोरेट
Mantra Yes for sure it has Mantra End
मंत्र यस फॉर श्योर इट हैज़ मंत्र एंड
Meditation as a part of it control of food
मेडिटेशन एज़ अ पार्ट ऑफ इट कंट्रोल ऑफ फूड
Timings of Diet Control Diet Control
टाइमिंग्स कंट्रोल ऑफ़ डाइट डाइट कंट्रोल
Timings go with the rhythm of nature you know
टाइमिंग्स गो विथ द रिदमम ऑफ द नेचर यू नो
go with the rhythm of the nature
गो विथ द रिदमम ऑफ़ द नेचर
And we say these are all supporting systems.
एंड वी स दीज़ आर ऑल सपोर्टिंग सिस्टम्स।
See a yogi who is living in the forest and
सी अ योगी हु इज़ लिविंग इन द फॉरेस्ट एंड
Doing Matangi Sadhana. let's say may not do
डूइंग मातंगी साधना। लेट्स से मे नॉट डू
all of these things for him just the mantra
ऑल ऑफ़ दीज़ थिंग्स फॉर हिम जस्ट द मंत्र
And Dhyana is Enough for How Long Years
एंड ध्याना इज इनफ फॉर हाउ लॉन्ग इयर्स
together and probably hours daily or but it
टूगेदर एंड प्रोब्ली आवर्स डेली या बट इट
it's like you can't appropriate you can't
इट्स लाइक यू कांट अप्रोप्रियेट यू कांट
approximately this because somebody who is caring
अप्रोक्समेट दिस बिकॉज़ समबडी हु इज़ कैरिंग
forward a previous
फॉरवर्ड अ प्री प्रीवियस
Life Balance With Him Few Months Could Be
लाइफ बैलेंस विथ हिम फ्यू मंथ्स कुड बी
Enough for him to trigger that wisdom and
इनफ फॉर हिम टू ट्रिगर दैट विज़डम एंड
trigger that energy which was already late
ट्रिगर दैट एनर्जी व्हिच वाज़ ऑलरेडी देर
In the snow. How does one know if the energy has been
इन हिम। हाउ डस वन नो इफ द एनर्जी हैज़ बीन
Triggered?
ट्रिगरर्ड?
It gets found out. It gets found out. Kant B
पता चल जाता है। पता चल जाता है। कांट बी
Explain in words may your dream be there
एक्सप्लेन इन वर्ड्स मे बी योर ड्रीम देयर
is there a realization of something
इज अ देयर इज अ रियलाइजेशन ऑफ समथिंग
inside it's like i know but i can't
इनसाइड इट्स इट्स लाइक आई नो बट आई कांट
explain it or
एक्सप्लेन इट या
ok sorry what was the lowest chakra one
ओके सॉरी व्हाट वास द लोएस्ट चक्र वन
Kamalatmika is like Lakshmi goddess of
कमलात्मिका इज़ लाइक लक्ष्मी गॉडेस ऑफ
Early Wealth and Money and Prosperity and
अर्ली वेल्थ एंड मनी एंड प्रोस्पेरिटी एंड
Everything. so she is kamalatmika has
एवरीथिंग। सो शी इज़ कमलात्मिका हैज़
Mostly Dissolved in the Form of Lakshmi
मोस्टली डिॉल्व्ड इनू द फॉर्म ऑफ लक्ष्मी
Which is in the present day. that nobody is
व्हिच इज इन द प्रेजेंट डे। उस नोबडी इज़
Doing special sadhanas for Kamalatmika on
डूइंग स्पेशल साधनाज़ फॉर कमलात्मिका पर
From. really or it's almost like you know
से। रियली या इट्स ऑलमोस्ट लाइक यू नो
Taken as the other Laxmi Sadhna we do Shri
टेकन एज द अदर लक्ष्मी साधना वी डू श्री
Suktam and We Do You Know Kanak Kanak
सूक्तम और वी डू यू नो कन कनक कनक
Mahalakshmi Stotra and so many others. So
महालक्ष्मी स्तोत्रा और सो मेनी अदर्स। सो
she is almost like amalgamated with the
शी इज़ ऑलमोस्ट लाइक एमल्गमेटेड विथ द
Modern day Lakshmi. or so when we say
मॉडर्न डे लक्ष्मी। या सो व्हेन वी से
Lakshmi is the Goddess of Wealth or
लक्ष्मी इज द गॉडेस ऑफ वेल्थ वेल्थ या
praying to her will attract wealth of
प्रइंग टू हर विल अट्रैक्ट वेल्थ ऑफ़
different yes of course of course it will be okay we
डिफरेंट यस ऑफकोर्स ऑफकोर्स इट विल ओके हम
Baglamukhi yes so baglamukhi comes from the
बगलामुखी यस सो बगलामुखी कम्स फ्रॉम द
The Solar Plexus is Obviously Fire Energy
सोलर प्लेक्सेस ऑब्वियसली फायर एनर्जी
Energy of Will Energy of Power So She Is Say
एनर्जी ऑफ़ विल एनर्जी ऑफ़ पावर सो शी इज़ से
Erection power Baglamukhi is Erection power She
स्तंभन शक्ति बगलामुखी इज़ स्तंभन शक्ति शी
can't stop anything it can it can it can
कैन स्टॉप एनीथिंग इट कैन इट कैन इट कैन
come with the solar power you know the power of the
कम विद द सोलर पावर यू नो द पावर ऑफ द
Solar Plexus
सोलर प्लेक्सेस
that yellow and that blazing fire is what
दैट येलो एंड दैट ब्लज़िंग फायर इज़ व्हाट
Baglamukhi is deified at and that's why
बगलामुखी इज़ डिप्टेड एट एंड दैट्स व्हाई
she is a specialist at stopping something you
शी इज़ अ स्पेशलिस्ट एट स्टॉपिंग समथिंग यू
No to end all the high death all experiments are
नो टू एंड ऑल द उच्चटन मरण ऑल प्रयोग्स आर
Done with Matangi and Ah Baglamukhi both are
डन विद मातंगी एंड अह बगलामुखी बोथ आर
Utilize these you know this. So the Lower Three
यूटिलाइज़ इन यू नो दिस। सो द लोअर थ्री
Chakras a lot of work is done. The Early Work
चक्राज़ अ लॉट ऑफ़ वर्क इज़ डन। द अर्ली वर्क
It is done. ah the other once higher once are mostly
इज़ डन। अह द अदर वंस हायर वांस आर मोस्टली
Utilized for ah transcendence and for
यूटिलाइज्ड फॉर अह ट्रांसेंडेंस एंड फॉर
Higher Ah Aints. but, if there are 100
हायर अह अंटेंट्स। बट, इफ देयर आर 100
Who Human Beings Hypothetically Are
ह्यूमन बीइंग्स हाइपोथेटिकली हु आर
Practicing the Sadhanas of the Three Lower
प्रैक्टिसिंग द साधनाज़ ऑफ़ द थ्री लोअर
Devise. What is there intention usually?
देवीज। व्हाट इज देयर इंटेंशन यूजुअली?
Like I'm sure 100 out of 100 are not
लाइक आई एम श्योर 100 आउट ऑफ़ 100 आर नॉट
Utilizing it. It is curiosity.
यूटिलाइज़िंग इट। इट इज़ क्यूरियोसिटी।
Ok. Mostly it is curiosity. What is
ओके। मोस्टली इट इज़ क्यूरियोसिटी। क्या है
We will see. Let us see what it is. End
देखेंगे। लेट अस सी व्हाट इट इज। एंड
Curiosity Spiritual Curiosity More
क्यूरियोसिटी स्पिरिचुअल क्यूरियोसिटी मोर
So
सो
Also as a seeker my observation is this. I
आल्सो एज अ साधक माय ऑब्जरवेशन इज दिस। आई
May be wrong. as a seeker is growing you know
मे बी रोंग। एज अ साधक इज ग्रोइंग यू नो
as you are
एज यू आर
Growing. There are many others watching you.
ग्रोइंग। देयर आर मेनी अदर्स वाचिंग यू।
There are many others looking at you. there
देयर आर मेनी अदर्स लुकिंग एट यू। देयर
many others are close to you and they may be
मेनी अदर्स आर क्लोज टू यू एंड दे मे बी
wanting to also try and do things
वांटिंग टू टू आल्सो ट्राई एंड डू थिंग्स
That's what you are doing. so a lot of borod
दैट यू आर डूइंग। सो अ लॉट ऑफ बोरोड
Desires. It is a very big disease. is a
डिजायर्स। इज अ वैरी बिग बीमारी। इज अ
Very big disease. Borod Desire. Or. I I
वैरी बिग डिजीज। बोरोड डिजायर। या। आई आई
I this is my phrase. My personal phrase.
आई दिस इज माय फ्रेज। माय पर्सनल फ्रेज।
I have read it anyway. Borrowed Desires Is
आई हैव रेड इट एनीवेर। बोरोड डिजायर्स इज़
Like you see someone being successfully flying
लाइक यू सी समवन बीइंग सक्सेसफुल फ्लाइंग
A kite. Ok. now you will see the 100 people
अ काइट। ओके। नाउ यू विल सी द 100 पीपल
More Flying Kites. it's like you know you
मोर फ्लाइंग काइट्स। इट्स लाइक यू नो यू
doing a good podcast there are many others who
डूइंग अ गुड पॉडकास्ट देर मेनी अदर्स हू
You want to be just the way you are. You Know
आर वांटिंग टू बी जस्ट द वे यू आर। यू नो
Similar to me. oh ah what a wonderful life
सिमिलरली मी। ओह अह व्हाट अ वंडरफुल लाइफ
But they don't know what life I go through.
बट दे डोंट नो व्हाट लाइफ आय गो थ्रू।
Living Up on the Mountain Alone. you know is
लिविंग अप ऑन द माउंटेन अलोन। यू नो इज़
Life. So a lot of borrowed desire. Meni
लाइफ। सो अ लॉट ऑफ़ बोरोड डिजायर। मेनी
People who are on this path. late se a 100 off
पीपल हु आर ऑन दिस पाथ। लेट से अ 100 ऑफ़
Them that you said. RR of Curiosity
देम दैट यू सेड। आर आर ऑफ क्यूरियोसिटी
and a borrowed curiosity of not really
एंड अ बोरोड क्यूरियोसिटी ऑफ नॉट रियली
Wanting neither the goddess nor the shiva.
वांटिंग नीदर द गॉडेस नर द शिवा।
what is the right intention with wanting to
व्हाट इज द राइट इंटेंशन विथ वांटिंग टू
do the sadhana? you should be ready to die to be
डू द साधना? यू शुड बी रेडी टू डाई टू बी
Late.
देर।
Want it as much as you want a breath. you you
वांट इट एस मच एस यू वांट अ ब्रीथ। यू यू
you should be ready to dissolve your self and
यू शुड बी रेडी टू डिसॉल्व युर सेल्फ एंड
Let her be. so that even ends and there is no god
लेट हर बी। सो डट इवन एंड एंड नो गॉड
Realization can happen without you dying as
रिअलाइज़ेशन कैन हैपेन विथाउट यू डाइंग एज़
An ego. it can't happen if one does any of these
अ ईगो। इट कांट हैपन इफ वन डज़ एनी ऑफ़ दीज़
Mahavidya Sadhanas
महाविद्या साधनास
Correctly and Correctly is a Subjective
करेक्टली एंड करेक्टली इज़ अ सब्जेक्टिव
term but yes if one does it we complete faith a
टर्म बट यस इफ वन डज़ इट वि कंप्लीट फेथ अ
you know penance etsetra etsetra what is the
यू नो पेनेंस एटसेट्रा एसेटरा व्हाट इज द
and result and result is a philosophy and
एंड रिजल्ट एंड रिजल्ट इज़ अ दर्शन एंड
realization of that energy in you it's in
रियलाइज़ेशन ऑफ़ दैट एनर्जी इन यू इट्स इन
It's in you that you realize for instance
इट्स इन यू दैट यू रियलाइज़ फॉर इंस्टेंस
I have loved Matangi for a long time
आई हैव लव्ड मातंगी फॉर अ लॉन्ग टाइम
And she just disappears everywhere to me.
एंड शी जस्ट डिसअपीयर्स एवरीवेयर टू मी।
Just out of your devotion for her. yes, just
जस्ट आउट ऑफ़ योर भक्ति फॉर हर। यस, जस्ट
Out of her devotion for her. can you look at
आउट ऑफ़ हर भक्ति फॉर हर। कैन यू लुक एट
someone and get to know them a little bit and
समवन एंड गेट टू नो देम अ लिटिल बिट एंड
tell them that he this is the mahavidya you should
टेल देम डैट हे दिस इज़ द महाविद्या यू शुड
B. Or,
बी। या,
Immediately. Immediately. you will be speaking
इमीडीएटली। इमीडीएटली। यू विल बी स्पीकिंग
After the podcast.
आफ्टर द पडकास्ट।
Anything else you want to say about Baglamukhi?
एनीथिंग एल्स यू वांट से अबाउट बगलामुखी?
She is considered very dangerous. that's why
शी इज़ कंसिडर्ड वैरी डेंजरस। दैट्स व्हाई
People are dangerous in the sense that they are very fiery.
पीपल आर डेंजरस इन द सेंस दैट वैरी फायरी।
so don't touch me until you are very sure
सो टच मी नॉट अंटिल यू आर वैरी श्योर
About it and very dedicated. Why?
अबाउट इट एंड वेरी डेडिकेटेड। व्हाई?
because it has a fiery energy and a lot of
बिकॉज़ इट्स अ फायरी एनर्जी एंड अ लॉट ऑफ़
Negative experiments are done. More of Negative
नेगेटिव प्रयोग आर डन। मोर ऑफ़ नेगेटिव
Experiments are done with her. so people are scared
प्रयोग आर डन विथ हर। सो पीपल आर स्केर्ड
To come into every devotion. those who have come into
टू कम इंटू हर भक्ति। दोज़ हु हैव कम इंटू
The bhakti have come into the bhakti because they have
द भक्ति हैव कम इंटू द भक्ति बिकॉज़ दे हैव
Been Blessed with Something That Was Successful
बीन ब्लेस्ड विथ समथिंग दैट वाज़ सक्सेसफुल
And taken for granted. At some point. at some point
एंड ग्रांटेड फॉर देम। एट सम पॉइंट। एट सम
Point. somebody wanted to win a court case
पॉइंट। समबडी वांटेड टू विन अ कोर्ट केस
And you know he did some sadhana baglamukhi vent
एंड यू नो ही डिड सम साधना बगलामुखी वेंट
Somewhere and some pandit did a puja for him
समवेयर एंड सम पंडित डिड अ पूजा फॉर हिम
Oher and the court case was you know through and
ओहर एंड द कोर्ट केस वाज़ यू नो थ्रू एंड
Due to this he became an eternal devotee of Baglamukhi.
देन ही बिकम एटरर्नल भक्त ऑफ़ बगलामुखी।
many of them are into bhakti like
मेनी ऑफ़ देम आर इनटू भक्ति लाइक
That. few of them rarely and they are really
दैट। फ्यू ऑफ़ देम रेयरली एंड दे आर रियली
Uniform that they just have a liking for her.
वर्दी दैट दे जस्ट हैव अ लाइकिंग फॉर हर।
They just have attraction for her. they just
दे जस्ट हैव अट्रैक्शन फॉर हर। दे जस्ट
have you known something is pulling me to
हैव अ यू नो समथिंग इज पुलिंग टू मी टू
every. For no reason. That is true devotion. that
हर। फॉर नो रीज़। दैट इज ट्रू भक्ति। दैट
There is true attraction and that is a calling.
इज ट्रू अट्रैक्शन एंड दैट इज अ कॉलिंग।
True calling. so the sadhna should be done coming
ट्रू कॉलिंग। सो द साधना शुड बी डन कमिंग
Back to the statement again. the sadhana should be
बैक टू द स्टेटमेंट अगेन। द साधना शुड बी
Don't be friends the power to realize her in
डन टू बी फ्रेंड द शक्ति टू रियलाइज हर इन
You end up getting a realization,
यू एंड टू गेट अ रियलाइजेशन,
Actualization and acquisition. we that should be the
एक्चुअलाइजेशन और अर्शन। हम दैट शुड बी द
Reason. Everything else will come soon.
रीज़न। बाकी तो सब आ ही जाएगा।
Hot moving on to the upper cycle. to the
गरम मूविंग ऑन टू द अपरचक्र। टू द
Dhumavati. Dhumavati. from here from here
धूमावती। धूमावती। फ्रॉम हियर फ्रॉम हियर
You know the centers the vertices. these three r's
यू नो द सेंटर्स द वर्टाइसेस। दीज़ थ्री आर
the worldly vertices and these are the
द वर्ल्डली वर्टाइसेस एंड दीज़ आर द
Psychological and the Upper World Vertices
साइकोलॉजिकल एंड द अप्पर वर्ल्ड वर्टाइसेस
Chakras. So, Dhumavati you know, ah
चक्रास। सो, धूमावती यू नो, अह
Corresponds to the air element. thats
करेस्पोंड्स टू द एयर एलिमेंट। दैट्स
Why She Is Departed Grey and Very
व्हाई शी इज़ डिप्टेड ग्रे एंड वेरी
depressive which is a very very
डिप्रेसिव व्हिच इज़ अ वेरी वेरी
Distracting picture of hers. she is
डिस्ट्रैक्टिंग पिक्चर ऑफ़ हर्स। शी इज़
Actually an ocean of love. she can remove poverty
एक्चुअली ओशन ऑफ़ लव। शी कैन रिमूव पॉवर्टी
Completely. She can remove grief completely.
कंप्लीटली। शी कैन रिमूव ग्रीफ कंप्लीटली।
she can remove it but people are very scared too
शी कैन रिमूव बट पीपल आर वेरी स्केर्ड टू
enter into her because she is depicted like
एंटर इंटू हर बिकॉज़ शी इज़ डिपिक्टेड लाइक
die like a widow like a very scary
ड्यात लाइक अ विडो लाइक अ वेरी स्केरी
figure with you know no color in her yantras
फिगर विथ यू नो नो कलर इन हर यंत्राज़
also there is no color there is just a grey
आल्सो देयर इज़ नो कलर देयर इज़ जस्ट अ ग्रे
and in fact many temples even if you go
एंड इन फैक्ट मेनी टेंपल्स इवन इफ यू गो
to kamakhya they say the dhumavati nobody goes a
टू कामाख्या दे से द धुमावती नोबडी गोज अ
Lots of our temple traditions which are
लॉट ऑफ़ अह आवर टेंपल ट्रेडिशन्स व्हिच आर
there they discourage people to take darshan of
देयर दे डिसकरेज पीपल टू टेक दर्शन ऑफ़
Dhumavati. I have people discourage Dhumavati
धुमावती। आई हैव पीपल डिसकरेज धुमावती
Worship on the show as well. or sleep, but she
वर्शिप ऑन द शो एज़ वेल। या सो, बट बट शी
Is really in ocean of love. i went to the
इज़ रियली इन ओशन ऑफ़ लव। आई वेंट टू द
Baglamukhi Am Temple At
बगलामुखी अम् टेंपल एट
Ah In The Middle
अह इन इन मध्य
State Datia. there is a beautiful
प्रदेश दतिया। देयर इज़ अ ब्यूटीफुल
Baglamukhi Temple at Datia. we i had gone
बगलामुखी टेंपल एट दतिया। वी आई हैड गॉन
with one of my friend and
विद वन ऑफ़ माय फ्रेंड एंड
Students. when we were coming out of the
स्टूडेंट्स। व्हेन वी वर कमिंग आउट ऑफ द
Temple after doing the puja and everything.
टेंपल आफ्टर डूइंग द पूजा एंड एवरीथिंग।
There is a Dhumavati temple there. So The Pandit
देयर इज़ अ धुमावती टेंपल देयर। सो द पंडित
I told you, mother, please do not go there. Bus
टोल्ड अस कि माता जी आप वहां मत जाइए। बस
I told you about the pain, please take a darshan mother
आपको दर्द मैंने बोला दर्शन तो ले ले मां
I didn't do it, you just took it from the window
का तो मैंने नहीं खिड़की से ले यू जस्ट
look into the pp through the window and that's
लुक इंटू द पीपी थ्रू द विंडो एंड दैट्स
it he was discouraging us to even go there
इट ही वास डिसकरेजिंग अस टू इवन गो देयर
so we kept his honour you know okay because okay
सो वी केप्ट हिज ऑनर यू नो ओके बिकॉज़ ठीक
if he saying don't go we just don't go
है इफ ही सेइंग डोंट गो डोंट गो वी जस्ट
came back to our car a huge crow that i
केम बैक टू आवर कार अ ह्यूज क्रो दैट आई
have never seen in my life such a huge crow
हैव नेवर सीन इन माय लाइफ सच अ ह्यूज क्रो
came and sat on our
केम एंड सैट ऑन आवर
Car You Know So It Is As If She Came And Crow
कार यू नो सो इट इज़ एज इफ शी केम एंड क्रो
is a vahan for dhumavati you know it is as if
इज़ अ वाहन फॉर धुमावती यू नो इट इज़ एज इफ
she came to him and she said okay you're not
शी केम हिम एंड शी सेड ओके यू आर नॉट
I am coming you know so these are so
कमिंग आई एम कमिंग यू नो सो दीज़ आर वै सल
The indications are very subtle
इंडिकेशंस वेरी सटल
Indications for a common man who is very
इंडिकेशंस फॉर अ कॉमन मैन हु इज़ वेरी
Logical End
लॉजिकल एंड
very you know brain oriented intellectual
वेरी यू नो ब्रेन ओरिएंटेड इंटेलेक्चुअल
he may not even give an importance to such a thing
ही मे नॉट इवन गिव एन इम्पोर्टेंस टू सच
An event what is there what is so big
एन इवेंट व्हाट इज़ देयर व्हाट इज़ सो बिग
About a crow coming and sitting on your car
अबाउट अ क्रो कमिंग एंड सिटींग ऑन योर कार
But when it is coming as a coincidence
बट व्हेन इट इज़ कमिंग एज़ अ कोइंसिडेंस
When you are not going to the temple and end
व्हेन यू आर नॉट गोइंग टू द टेंपल एंड एंड
Suddenly I don't know where such a big crow is
सडनली आई डोंट नो वेयर सच अ बिग क्रो द
The size of the crow was amazing. and we three
साइज ऑफ़ द क्रो वाज़ अमेजिंग। एंड वी थ्री
we were three of us and whether we were three
वी वर थ्री ऑफ़ अस एंड वेदर वी थ्री वर
Wide Eyed Jaw Dropped Looking At The Crow.
वाइड आईड जॉर ड्रॉपड लुकिंग एट द क्रो।
because we all understood three in our
बिकॉज़ वी ऑल अंडरस्टुड थ्री इन आवर
Hearts That's Where She Is. so you know they
हार्ट्स दैट हियर शी इज़। सो यू नो दे
Manifest around you. so dhumavati is an ocean
मैनिफ़ेस्ट अराउंड यू। सो धुमावती इज़ अ ओशन
Of compassion very very beautiful. so as a
ऑफ़ कंपैशन वेरी वेरी ब्यूटीफुल। सो एज़ अ
therapist and as a person who is into
थेरेपिस्ट एंड एज़ अ पर्सन हु इज़ इंटू
Mahavidya Sadhanaaz. We recommend Dhumawatis
महाविद्या साधनाज़। वी रेकमेंड धुमावतीस
Mantra Rarely Only When Somebody Is Grief
मंत्र रेयरली ओनली व्हेन समबडी इज़ ग्रीफ
Stricken For
स्ट्रिकन फॉर
Long Innu Deep Depression and Grief Stricken
लॉन्ग इनू डीप डिप्रेशन और ग्रीफ स्ट्रिकन
and just doesn't find any light in life then
एंड जस्ट डज़ंट फाइंड एनी लाइट इन लाइफ देन
Dhumavati is given as a very antidote for a
धुमावती इस गिवेन एज अ वेरी एंटीटोड फॉर अ
very short
वेरी शॉर्ट
vile and then there are tantriks
वाइल एंड देन देयर आर तांत्रिक
Practitioners That Do the Siddhi of Dhumavati
प्रैक्टिशनर्स दैट डू द सिद्धि ऑफ़ धुमावती
also for prayog chinmast and dhumavati
आल्सो फॉर प्रयोग चिनमस्त एंड धुमावती
also have a set of experiments that are you know
आल्सो हैव अ सेट ऑफ़ प्रयोग दैट आर यू नो
popular use for for all of this that we
पॉपुलर यूज फॉर फॉर ऑल ऑफ दिस दैट वी
Speak about mesmerizing games and playing
स्पोक अबाउट मेसराइजिंग गेम्स एंड प्लेइंग
with the toys that god has given us
वि द टॉयज दैट गॉड हैज़ गिवेन अस
ok give two extremes of people that do her
ओके दे टू एक्सट्रीम्स ऑफ़ पीपल दैट डू हर
Sadhna once that wanted to extract the power
साधना वंस दैट वांट टू एक्सट्रैक्ट द पावर
You know I utilize the power for different
यू नो आई यूटिलाइज़ द पावर फॉर डिफरेंट
Kinds of Experiments That They Want to Do
काइंड्स ऑफ़ एक्सपेरिमेंट्स दैट दे वांट टू
do and the others who are wanting a healing
डू एंड द अदर हु आर वांनिंग अ हीलिंग अ
deep healing she is a she is a great healer
डीप हीलिंग शी इज़ अ शी इज़ अ ग्रेट हीलर
Dhumavati she can actually remove the powerless
धुमावती शी कैन एक्चुअली रिमूव पॉवरटाइज्ड
Conditions in all levels. Material Emotional
कंडीशंस इन ऑल लेवल्स। मटीरियल इमोशनल
Levels you know. So she is a healer. and air
लेवल्स यू नो। सो शी इज़ अ हीलर। एंड एयर
element you know so air element itself is
एलिमेंट यू नो सो एयर एलिमेंट इटसेल्फ इज़
Creates a lot of change. Invoking Her Is
क्रिएट्स अ लॉट ऑफ़ चेंज। इनवोकिंग हर इज़
Like invoking the air element. why you?
लाइक इन्वोकिंग द एयर एलिमेंट। व्हाई यू?
you know it said that when you begin any
यू नो इट सेड दैट व्हेन यू बिगिन एनी
Kind of deity worship. like when you
काइंड ऑफ़ डेटी उपासना। लाइक व्हेन यू
Prefer a particular date, you get trades
प्रेड अ पर्टिकुलर डेटी, यू गेट ट्रेड्स
Off that daty. which is why i think people
ऑफ़ दैट डेटी। व्हिच इज व्हाई आई थिंक पीपल
Fear springs to Dhumavati. Yeah. that will you
फियर प्रिंग टू धुमावती। याह। दैट विल यू
Also became a widow? will you also or that's
आल्सो बिकम अ विडो? विल यू आल्सो या दैट्स
That's the negative bit of conditioning
दैट्स दैट्स द नेगेटिव बिट ऑफ़ कंडीशनिंग
Which is there. that's a negative bit of
व्हिच इज़ देयर। दैट्स अ नेगेटिव बिट ऑफ़
Conditioning Which Is There Which Is Not
कंडीशनिंग व्हिच इज़ देयर व्हिच इज़ नॉट
True. A they are not in human forms.
ट्रू। ए दे आर नॉट इन ह्यूमन फॉर्म्स।
The gods are not in human forms. give and take
दवीज़ आर नॉट इन ह्यूमन फॉर्म्स। दे आर
Huge Energy Portals and Energy Day
ह्यूज एनर्जी पोर्टल्स एंड एनर्जी दे
Create Energy Movement. so the depiction as
क्रिएट एनर्जी मूवमेंट। सो द डिपिक्शन एज़
woman is only symbolic of the
वुमेन इज़ ओनली सिंबॉलिक ऑफ़ द
Characteristics and Elemental Depictions
कैरेक्टरिस्टिक्स एंड एलिमेंटल डिपिक्शन
Radar. The Yellow in Baglamukhi is all about the
रादर। द येलो इन बगलामुखी इज़ ऑल अबाउट द
Fire element. it's not that she is a woman
फायर एलिमेंट। इट्स नॉट दैट शी इज़ अ वुमेन
who likes yellow. It's not like that.
हु लाइक्स येलो। इट्स नॉट लाइक दैट।
similarly devi is the bhuvaneshwari is there
सिमिलरली दवी इज़ द भुवनेश्वरी इज़ देयर
Shoulder She Is Departed With The Red. it's more
शोल्डर शी इज़ डिप्टेड विथ द रेड। इट्स मोर
Symbolic to you know to the Rajas. Rajasic
सिंबॉलिक टू द यू नो टू द रजस। राजसिक
Energy is depicted by red offen. because
एनर्जी इज़ डिपिक्टेड बाइ रेड ऑफेन। बिकॉज़
it it has a lot of attraction and a lot of
इट इट हैज़ अ लॉट ऑफ़ अट्रैक्शन एंड लॉट ऑफ़
Abundance with itself. So, let's go
अबंडेंस विद इन इटसेल्फ। सो, दे आर
Deputed like that. it's not that they are any
डिप्टेड लाइक दैट। इट्स नॉट दैट दे आर एनी
Kind of woman. so even when we say we are
काइंड ऑफ़ वुमेन। सो इवन व्हेन वी से वी आर
Getting a Darshan. suppose i say that i have a
गेटिंग अ दर्शन। सपोज आई से दैट आई हैव अ
Philosophy of Matangi. it's actually a
दर्शन ऑफ़ मातंगी। इट्स एक्चुअली अ
Protection of my mind. you know there is
प्रोटेक्शन ऑफ़ माय माइंड। यू नो देयर इज़
My Energy System and My Mind
माय एनर्जी सिस्टम एंड माय माइंड
Projecting into a Goddess that is so real
प्रोजेक्टिंग इंटू अ देवी दैट इज़ सो रियल
In front of me. so it's my creation
इन फ्रंट ऑफ़ मी। सो इट्स माय क्रिएशन
Basically. we are not coming in any form
बेसिकली। हम शी इज़ नॉट कमिंग इन एनी फॉर्म
Anywhere like that. The energy is supporting.
एनीवेयर लाइक दैट। द एनर्जी इज़ सपोर्टिंग।
Undoubtedly she is supporting which is
अनडाउटेडली शी इज़ सपोर्टिंग व्हिच इज़
Why we say Devi has given me darshan. I
व्हाई वी से देवी हैज़ गिवेन मी दर्शन। आई
Don't say that I have created a philosophy. So
डोंट से दैट आई हैव क्रिएटेड अ दर्शन। सो
Devi has given me a darshan because it's
देवी हैज़ गिवेन मी अ दर्शन बिकॉज़ इट्स
Something that I couldn't do it has happened.
समथिंग दैट आई कुडंट डू इट हैज़ हैपेंड।
How ever it is a projection from your own
हाउ एवर इट्स अ प्रोजेक्शन फ्रॉम योर ओन
pranic system and end when you
प्राणिक सिस्टम एंड एंड व्हेन यू
understand the science of it you understand
अंडरस्टैंड द साइंस ऑफ इट यू अंडरस्टैंड
it very deeply that it's a projection of
इट वेरी डीपली दैट इट्स अ प्रोजेक्शन ऑफ
Your pranic system and the maruls of your
योर प्राणिक सिस्टम एंड थे मरुल्स ऑफ योर
bodies are coming outside and giving you
बॉडी आर कमिंग आउटसाइड एंड गिविंग यू
darshan wow or they are giving you darshan it
दर्शन वाओ या दे आर गिविंग यू दर्शन इट्स
only for your eyes it's a state of being
ओनली फॉर योर आईज इट्स अ स्टेट ऑफ़ बीइंग
Hypertune Again Very Hypertune and Its
हाइपरट्यून अगेन वैरी हाइपरट्यून एंड इट्स
Like a Prasad Hum it's like a reward
लाइक अ प्रसाद हम इट्स लाइक अ रिवॉर्ड
the system that your energy and your
सिस्टम दैट योर एनर्जी एंड योर
Consciousness Inside Is Giving You For You
कॉन्शियसनेस इनसाइड इज़ गिविंग यू फॉर यू
Shor Dedication and Devotion. Like If You Work
शोर डेडिकेशन एंड डिवोशन। लाइक इफ यू वर्क
out long enough and eat cleanly you will see
आउट लॉन्ग इनफ एंड ईट क्लीनली यू विल सी
Abs one day. Yes. Like that. To Trivialize
एब्स वन डे। यस। लाइक दैट। टू ट्रिविलाइज
It. And a very gross level good example.
इट। एंड अ वैरी ग्रॉस लेवल गुड एग्जांपल।
Moving on. or then after or after dhumavati
मूविंग ऑन। या देन आफ्टर या आफ्टर धुमावती
then you have
देन यू हैव
The ah chinnamasta. you know the picture of
द ah चिनमस्ता। यू नो द पिक्चर ऑफ़
Chinnamasta is deputed in the Mahavidya
चिनमस्ता इज़ डिप्टेड इन द महाविद्या
Books. Whatever Few Books We Have. You Know
बुक्स। व्हाटएवर फ्यू बुक्स वी हैव। यू नो
How many. Western Have Written Coincidentally
हाउ मेनी। वेस्टर्न हेव रिटन कोइंसिडेंटली
More Books. On Mahavidyaana Indians. You Know
मोर बुक्स। ऑन महाविद्यान इंडियंस। यू नो
and indian books are all full of experiments and
एंड इंडियन बुक्स आर ऑल फुल ऑफ़ प्रयोग एंड
Everything because the focus is different. give me
एवरीथिंग बिकॉज़ द फोकस इज़ डिफरेंट। दे द
Focus in the Western World is All About
फोकस इन द वेस्टर्न वर्ल्ड इज़ ऑल अबाउट
Research and Inquiry. They gave and they had
रिसर्च एंड इंक्वायरी। दे एंड एंड दे हैव
Not written anything much about experiments.
नॉट रिटेन एनीथिंग मच अबाउट प्रयोग्स।
Indian books have written more about experiment
इंडियन बुक्स हैव रिटन मोर अबाउट प्रयोग
because this is where the application of the
बिकॉज़ दिस इज़ वेयर द एप्लीकेशन ऑफ़ द
Mahavidyas is Conard. I Wood from Conard
महाविद्यास इज़ कॉनर्ड। आई वुड से कॉनर्ड
Because it is not taking into devotion level. So,
बिकॉज़ इज़ नॉट टेकिंग इंटू भक्ति लेवल। सो,
Chinhnamasta is depicted as ah dacapitated.
चिन्हमस्ता इज़ डिपिक्टेड एज़ अह डकैपिटेड।
She's she's got a cut off head, chopped off head.
शी इज़ शीज़ गट अ कट ऑफ़ हेड, चॉकप्ड ऑफ़ हेड।
and she is holding our head in her own in her
एंड शी इज़ होल्डिंग आर हेड इन हर ओन इन हर
on hand oozing out blood and then there are s
ओन हैंड ऊजिंग आउट ब्लड एंड देन देयर आर स
you know fountains of three fountains oozing
यू नो फाउंटेन्स ऑफ थ्री फाउंटेन्स ऊजिंग
out from her they are said to be pingala
आउट फ्रॉम हर द दे दे आर सेड टू बी पिंगला
and the sushmana the energy fountains they are
एंड द सुषमना द एनर्जी फाउंटेंस दे आर
Actually Energy Fountains They Aren't
एक्चुअली एनर्जी फाउ फाउंटेंस दे आर नॉट
blood they are not blood and then they are two
ब्लड दे आर नॉट ब्लड एंड देन दे आर टू
dakinis who are drinking this ah the dakinis
डकिनीज़ हु आर ड्रिंकिंग दिस अह द डकिनीज़
are the cosmic powers and she chinnamasta is
आर द कॉस्मिक पावर्स एंड शी चिनमस्ता इज़
Standing Over a Copulating Couple She
स्टैंडिंग ओवर अ कोपुलेटिंग कपल शी
Standing on a copulating couple in the
स्टैंडिंग ऑन अ कोपुलेटिंग कपल इन द
Puranaz it is written as Rati and Kama. She
पुरानाज़ इट इज़ रिटेन ऐज़ रति एंड कामा। शी
Is standing on this. So basically, the
इज़ स्टैंडिंग ऑन दिस। सो बेसिकली, द
symbolism involved here is that complete
सिंबोलिज़्म इनवॉल्व्ड हियर इज़ दैट कंप्लीट
Control over your ego, cutting off the head in
कंट्रोल ओवर योर ईगो, कटिंग ऑफ़ द हेड इन
All The Mahavidya Cutting Chopping The Head Is
ऑल द महाविद्या कटिंग चोपोिंग द हेड इज़
Like chopping off the head of the ego. End
लाइक चोपिंग द हेड ऑफ़ द ईगो। एंड
Energizing bringing an energy system to
एनर्जाइजिंग ब्रिंगिंग अ एनर्जी सिस्टम टु
Optimize Levels, Winning Over Desire.
ऑप्टिमाइज लेवल, विनिंग ओवर डिजायर।
Standing on the Copilated Couple is Like
स्टैंडिंग ऑन द कोपिलेटेड कपल इज़ लाइक
Saying, she is one over desire. every kind
सेइंग, शी इज़ वन ओवर डिजायर। एव्री काइंड
Of Lust and Desire. so it's a highest
ऑफ़ लस्ट एंड डिज़ायर। सो इट्स अ हाईएस्ट
Attainment. it's a spiritual attainment and
अटेनमेंट। इट्स अ स्पिरिचुअल अटेनमेंट एंड
It corresponds to the Aakash tattva
इट कॉस्पोंड्स टू द आकाश तत्व करेस्पोंड्स
to the ether to which all the other elements are
टू द ईथर टू व्हिच ऑल द अदर एलिमेंट्स आर
Born. Sky, air, fire, you give the earth
बोर्न। आकाश, वायु, अग्नि, आप पृथ्वी दे
We are born to the sky. so she is at the apex
आर बोर्न टू आकाश। सो शी इज़ एट द एपेक्स
of the elemental sequence and at the having
ऑफ द एलिमेंटल सीक्वेंस एंड एट द हैविंग
Attend to that level of detachment cutting cords
अटेंड दैट लेवल ऑफ डिटचमेंट कटिंग कॉर्ड्स
With everything and highest yogic attainment.
विद एवरीथिंग एंड हाईएस्ट योगिक अटेनमेंट।
Chamasta again chinnamasta is utilized as a
चमस्ता अगेन चिनमस्ता इज़ यूटिलाइज़्ड एज़ अ
Therapy. Divine mantra and sadhna is utilized
थेरेपी। दवी मंत्र एंड साधना इज़ यूटिलाइज़
As a therapy. for someone who is in the middle
एज़ अ थेरेपी। फॉर समवन हु इज़ इन द मिडिल
Of a mess. I want to get detached.
ऑफ़ अ मेस। आई वांट्स टू गेट डिट्टाच्ड।
also addictions of all kinds on physical level
अल्सो एडिक्शंस ऑफ़ ऑल काइंड्स फिजिकल लेवल
Addictions, alcoholism, drugs all of this.
एडिक्शंस, अल्कोहलिज्म, ड्रग ऑल ऑफ़ दिस।
Also, ah relationship addictions, you know, all
आल्सो, अह रिलेशनशिप एडिक्शंस, यू नो, ऑल
Kinds of Addiction. To Win Over Desire At
काइंड्स ऑफ़ एडिक्शन। टू विन ओवर डिजायर एट
All levels, physical, emotional and others. donation
ऑल लेवल्स, फिजिकल, इमोशनल एंड अदर। देन
beyond this then we come to bhairavi it's at
बियों्ड दिस देन वी कम टू भैरवी इट्स एट
Pa with Bhairava Bhairavi and Bhairava they are the same
पा विद भैरव भैरवी एंड भैरव दे आर द सेम
they are different the flow you know here is the
दे आर डिफरेंट द प्रवाह यू नो हियर इज़ द
Force of Shiva Jatativi Wrong Flame Flow
फोर्स ऑफ़ शिवा जटातिवी गलत ज्वल प्रवाह
pavi tastle you know this thing says or so
पावि तस्तले यू नो द दिस थिंग सेज़ या सो
Flow is the force of the desert. Maruths R
प्रवाह इज़ द फोर्स ऑफ़ द मरू्स। मरूथ्स आर
Also residing in all seven Chakras. What
आल्सो रेसाइडिंग इन ऑल सेवन चक्रास। व्हाट
Is it not? we will talk about it in another
इज़ नॉट? वी विल टॉक अबाउट इट इन इन अनदर
discussion that we will do with hanuman when
डिस्कशन दैट वी विल डू विद हनुमान व्हेन
I come the next time we will do it. You Know
आई कम द नेक्स्ट टाइम वी विल डू इट। यू नो
so marut is a very big subject which is
सो मरूत इज़ अ वेरी बिग सब्जेक्ट व्हिच इज़
There in our you know in our tradition. So the
देयर इन आवर यू नो इन आवर ट्रेडिशन। सो द
the name of the marut that comes from here is
नेम ऑफ़ द मरूत दैट कम्स फ्रॉम हियर इज़
Flow. Flow is like a fiery force. So
प्रवाह। प्रवाह इज़ लाइक अ फायरी फोर्स। सो
Bhairavi is is you know at this level her. when
भैरवी इज़ इज़ यू नो एट दिस लेवल हर। व्हेन
we say she is it doesn't mean she is residing
वी से शी इज़ इट डजंट मीन शी इज़ रीसाइडिंग
Here in there. No. The Vibrational
हियर इन देयर। नो। द वाइब्रेशनल
The frequencies are parallel.
फ्रीक्वेंसीज़ आर पैरेलल।
corresponding like we have corresponded
करेस्पोंडिंग लाइक वी हैव करस्पोंडिंग
colors corresponding aromas color you know
कलर्स करेस्पोंडिंग एरोमाज़ कलर यू नो
Chakra correspondence is there at so many
चक्रा करेस्पोंडेंस इज़ देयर एट सो मेनी
Levels Flowers that Correspond to the Chakras
लेवल्स फ्लावर्स दैट करस्पोंड टू द चक्राज़
Vegetables and Fruits That Correspond to
वेजिटेबल्स एंड फ्रूट्स दैट करेस्पोंड टू
The Chakras Colours Aromas Hai Na Oils Isi
द चक्राज़ कलर्स एरोमाज़ है ना ऑयल्स इसी
Like in the same way the goddesses are
तरह इन द सेम वे द गॉडेसेस आर
Corresponding to this energy frequency
करेस्पोंडिंग टू दिस एनर्जी फ्रीक्वेंसी
when you understand and look at it from
व्हेन यू अंडरस्टैंड एंड लुक एट इट फ्रॉम
The energy point of view so Bhairavi is like
द एनर्जी पॉइंट ऑफ व्यू सो भैरवी इज़ लाइक
she is seen in the smshana again you know and
शी इज़ शोन इन द स्मशाना अगेन यू नो एंड
Doing Sadhna Fiery Her Face Is Quiet
डूइंग साधना फियरी हर फेस इज़ क्वाइट
Familiar to that of Kali Absolute Braise
फमिलियर टू दैट ऑफ काली अबब्सोल्यूट ब्रेज़
Her hair and body are nude and so is she
हेयर एंड बॉडी इज़ न्यूड एंड सो शी इज़ लाइक
Swami of Bhoots She is like the Curse of All
भूतों की स्वामी शी इज़ लाइक द करेस ऑफ़ ऑल
The Other Worlds and Has All the Powers in Her
द अदर वर्ल्ड्स एंड हैज़ ऑल द पावर्स इन हर
control she is like shiva she is like bhairav
कंट्रोल शी इज़ लाइक शिवा शी इज़ लाइक भैरव
Just like every Bhairav ​​is described Bhairavi
जस्ट लाइक हर भैरव इस डिस्क्राइब्ड भैरवी
is there so much sickness is you not getting over
इज़ हियर सो सिकनेस इज़ यू नो गेटिंग ओवर
sickness she is also the controller of ours
सिकनेस शी इज़ आल्सो द कंट्रोलर ऑफ़ आवर
prana sister system so any issues with the
प्राणा सिस्टर सिस्टम सो एनी इशज़ वि द
Panic System Respiratory Issues Extra
पनिक सिस्टम रेस्पिरेटरी इशज़ एक्सट्रा
Bhairavi's taken care of wherewe can take care
भैरवीज़ टेकन केयर ऑफ वेयरवी कैन टेक केयर
of is used as a mantra is used as a
ऑफ इज़ यूज़्ड एज अ मंत्र इज़ यूज़ एस अ
Therapy in our sect by Gurudevs
थेरेपी इन आवर संप्रदाय इन गुरुदेव्स
Teachings all these Mahavidyas are quite similar
टीचिंग्स ऑल दीज़ महाविद्यास आर टॉट एज़
Healing
हीलिंग
Arts Different Mahavidyas for Different
आर्ट्स डिफरेंट महाविद्यास फॉर डिफरेंट
Healing Streams You Know For Different
हीलिंग स्ट्रीम्स यू नो फॉर डिफरेंट
Kinds of Issues and Problems that People Have
काइंड्स ऑफ इशूज़ एंड प्रॉब्लम्स दैट पीपल
Wood Face White Use White Use Wide
वुड फेस वाइट प्रयोग वाइट प्रयोग वाइड
use wide and red sometimes you know for
प्रयोग वाइड एंड रेड समटाइम्स यू नो फॉर
Prosperity when you have a family, you
प्रोस्पेरिटी व्हेन यू हैव अ फॅमिली, यू
Need sustainability. When you need sustainability,
नीड सस्टेनेंस। व्हेन यू नीड सस्टेनेंस,
You need money and you need facilities. You Know,
यू नीड मनी एंड यू नीड फैसिलिटीज़। यू नो,
So that comes under red. to increase your
सो दैट दैट कम्स अंडर रेड। टू इंक्रीस योर
Business Turnover or You Know How to Dissolve Your Business
बिज़नेस टर्नओवर ऑर टू यू नो डिसॉल्व योर
Financial Obstacles or Two
फाइनेंसियल ऑब्सकल्स ऑर टू
Attain in education and success, more focus and
अटेन इन एजुकेशन और सक्सेस, मोर फ़ोकस एंड
Concentration in your work. Etra. that is all
कंसंट्रेशन इन योर वर्क। एट्रा। दैट इज़ ऑल
The Rad Experiment. Hmm. So, Bhairavi is invoked
रेड प्रयोग। हम्। सो, भैरवी इज इनवोक्ड
for disease, deadly disease and also to get
फॉर डिजीज, डेडली डिजीज एंड आल्सो टू गेट
Rid of Evil Energy and Evil Ah Unseen
रिड ऑफ इविल एनर्जी एंड इवल अह अनसीन
Dangers that come from other dimensions, you
डेंजरस दैट कम फ्रॉम अदर डायमेंशंस, यू
No, so she is invoked for that. can we talk
नो, सो शी इज़ इनवोकड फॉर दैट। कैन वी टॉक
about the unseen what comes from different
अबाउट अनसीन इवैट कम फ्रॉम डिफरेंट
Dimensions a little bit may be
डायमेंशंस अ लिटिल बिट मे बी
Yes over to you? ya my gurudev you know always
यस ओवर टू यू? या माय गुरुदेव यू नो ऑलवेज
said to me that
सेड टू मी दैट
Bring people in faith, aastha, shraddha and
ब्रिंग पीपल इन फेथ, आस्था, श्रद्धा एंड
Love. and it's not important for us to see the
लव। एंड इट्स नॉटेंट फॉर अस टू सी द
Dark. so i love following you know
डार्क। सो आई आई लव फॉलोइंग ह यू नो
Advice
एडवाइस
and having known all the other dimensions that one
एंड हैविंग नोन ऑल द अदर डायमेंशंस दैट वन
can talk about it if it's not going to help
कैन टॉक अबाउट इफ इट्स नॉट गोइंग टू हेल्प
Anyone why to talk about it. Ok. and if
एनीवन व्हाई टू टॉक अबाउट इट। ओके। एंड इफ
It creates fair why to talk about it. I
इट क्रिएट फेयर व्हाई टू टॉक अबाउट इट। आई
can give you a very small example of the
कैन गिव यू अ वेरी स्माल एग्जांपल ऑफ द
Unseen. Very small example. I was doing
अनसीन। वेरी स्माल एग्जांपल। आई वाज़ डूइंग
a black
अ काली
Sadhana and I keep experimenting a lot
साधना एंड आई कीप एक्सपेरिमेंटिंग अ लॉट
v mantras and because i have all the time in
वि मंत्राज़ एंड बिकॉज़ आई हैव ऑल टाइम इन
hand you know so i was experimenting with
हैंड यू नो सो आई वाज़ एक्सपेरिमेंटिंग विथ
A Kali Sadhna Sing On My Sofa Our Everyday
अ काली साधना सिंग ऑन माय सोफा आवर हमेज
is bang on the ganga it's on the bank of ganga
इज़ बैंग ऑन द गंगा इट्स ऑन द बैंक ऑफ़ गंगा
and you can see the
एंड यू कैन सी द
Ganga You Know 70mm Full Panoramic View Of
गंगा यू नो 70 एमएम फुल पैनोरमिक व्यू ऑफ़
The Ganga. So, I was doing my mantra chanting.
द गंगा। सो, आई वाज डूइंग माय मंत्र जपान।
I am looking at the Ganga. and suddenly the thought
आई एम लुकिंग एट द गंगा। एंड सडनली द थॉट
Cross my mind. Oh the AC is on and you
क्रॉस माई माइंड। ओह द एसी इज़ ऑन एंड यू
R city comfortably in this room doing the
आर सिटी कम्फर्टेबली इन दिस रूम डूइंग द
Sadhana. and there are people sitting in the
साधना। एंड देयर आर पीपल सिटींग इन द
Crematorium and doing it. you should be sitting in
स्मशान एंड डूइंग इट। यू शुड बी सिटींग इन
The Smashan and Doing the Sadhana. Mahavidya
द स्मशान एंड डूइंग द साधना। महाविद्या
sadhanas are done a lot of them in crude
साधनाज़ आर डन अ लॉट ऑफ़ देम इन क्रूड
Natural places, Guhia places. You Know
नेचुरल प्लेसेस, गुहिया प्लेसेस। यू नो
Like the Cremation Ground and Caves End
लाइक द क्रिमेशन ग्राउंड और केव्स एंड
River Beds Extra. so i am just
रिवर बेड्स एक्सट्रा। सो आय एम जस्ट
joked with myself and i said you are
जोक्कड विथ माइसेल्फ एंड आय सेड यू आर
Doing Kali Sadhna and in the comfort of a
डूइंग काली साधना एंड इन द कंफर्ट ऑफ़ अ
a sofa and an AC and you should be sitting
सोफा एंड अ एसी एंड यू शुड बी सिटींगिंग
there in so just in the in the ah 60 degrees
देयर इन सो जस्ट इन द इन द अह 60 डिग्रीज़
view of you are hermited down there there is a
व्यू ऑफ़ आर हर्मिटेड डाउन देयर देयर इज़ अ
Chromision Ground Weather Local Villagers Come
क्रोमिशन ग्राउंड वेदर लोकल विलेजर्स कम
And burn the bodies when they're dead. I slept
एंड बर्न द बॉडीज व्हेन दे आर डेड। सो आई
I'm looking there and I'm saying this in my
एम लुकिंग देर एंड आई एम सेइंग दिस इन माय
head and with in a few minutes could be 10
हेड एंड विथ इन अ फ्यू मिनट्स कुड बी 10
15 minutes. I see two three bodies have come
15 मिनट्स। आई सी टू थ्री बॉडीज़ हाव कम
There and they were blessings. give me a kiss
देर एंड दे वर ब्लेसिंग। दे दे पुट दे वर
put on fire and they were blazing it as it was
पुट ऑन फायर एंड दे वर ब्लेजिंग इट वास एज
if goddess is giving me an assurance
इफ गॉडेस इस गिविंग मी के एन अश्योरेंस
that you are okay sitting there and doing it
दैट यू आर ओके सिटींग देयर एंड डूइंग इट
here I am I am showing you the crematorium and
हियर आई एम आई एम शोइंग यू द स्मशान एंड
after these bodies left and my eye because
आफ्टर दीज़ बॉडीज लेफ्ट एंड माय आई बिकॉज़
I was sitting while I was so fascinated
आई वाज़ सिटींग देर आई वाज़ सो फेसिनेटेड
with the hole
विथ द होल
Coincidence after the bodies you know they were
कोइंसिडेंस आफ्टर द बॉडीज़ यू नो वे वर
Burned and these people left al the people left
बर्नड एंड दीज़ पीपल लेफ्ट अल द पीपल लेफ्ट
in the sutler world because you know the orvision is
इन द सटलर वर्ल्ड बिकॉज़ यू नो द ओरविज़न इज़
Very sharp. I can almost sense and see a
वेरी शार्प। आय कैन ऑलमोस्ट सेंस एंड सी अ
Lots of things. i saw a huge crowd
लॉट ऑफ़ थिंग्स। आई सॉ अ ह्यूज क्राउड
Sitting there. Of images sitting there. End
सिटींग देयर। ऑफ़ इमेजेज़ सिटींग देयर। एंड
it was as if there was a there was a cosmic
इट वाज एज़ इफ देयर अ देयर वाज़ अ कॉस्मिक
Acknowledgement for what I was doing. So,
एक्नोलेजमेंट फॉर व्हाट आई वाज डूइंग। सो,
you know when you are doing very subtle things and
यू नो व्हेन यू दे आर वेरी सटल थिंग्स एंड
may sound stupid to people who are very
मे साउंड स्टुपिड टू पीपल हु आर वेरी
Logical. It May Actually Sound Very
लॉजिकल। इट मे एक्चुअली साउंड वैरी
Stupid. so we don't even know these things
स्टुपिड। सो वी डोंट इवन नरट दिस थिंग्स
to a lot of people because it's beyond their reach
टु अ लॉट ऑफ़ पीपल बिकॉज़ इट्स बियन्ड देर
Understanding. And bye became ah ah you know
अंडरस्टैंडिंग। एंड बाय बिकम अह अह यू नो
Stock for laughter or for. so we don't we
स्टॉक फॉर लाफ्टर ओर फॉर। सो वी डोंट वी
don't share this rrrrrrrrr
डोंट शेयर दीज़ आर आर आर आर आर आर आर आर आर
RR Experience. and we take them
आर आर एक्सपीरियंस। एंड वी टेक देम
Seriously. you know so the entire topic of
सीरियसली। यू नो सो द एंटायर टॉपिक ऑफ़
what you said. is there something that is personal
व्हाट यू सेड। इज़ समथिंग दैट इज़ अ पर्सनल
experience for most of the people who would
एक्सपीरियंस फॉर मोस्ट ऑफ़ द पीपल हु वुड
nerd things that somebody saw this and that
नरट थिंग्स दैट समबडी सॉ दिस और दिस सॉ
Dec. and somebody heard this and can know about
दिस। और समबडी हर्ड दिस और कैन नोज़ अबाउट
these realms and all this is personal
दीज़ रेल्म्स एंड ऑल दिस ऑल पर्सनल
Experience and they are truth to them. Give
एक्सपीरियंस एंड दे आर ट्रुथ टू देम। दे
Are truth to them. Yeah. you know how in
आर ट्रुथ टू देम। याह। यू नो हाउ इन
Islam speaks about angels and these
इस्लाम दे स्पीक अबाउट फरिश्ते और इन
Christianity They Speak About Angers.
क्रिश्चियनिटी दे स्पीक अबाउट एंज्स।
What is the Sanatani equivalent of? the one
व्हाट इज द सनातनी इक्विवेलेंट ऑफ? द वन
That is above is Gandharvas. we call them
दैट इज़ अबव इज़ गंधर्वाज़। वी कॉल देम
Gandharvas. Gandharvas are like angels. what the
गंधर्वज़। गंधर्वज़ आर लाइक एंज्स। व्हाट द
The Western World Calls Angels and They Are Ah
वेस्टर्न वर्ल्ड कॉल्स एंज्स एंड दे आर अह
Living Subtle Bodies That Have Primary
लिविंग सटल बॉडीज़ दैट हैव प्राइमरी
Responsibility to Create Ah Heaven On
रिस्पांसिबिलिटी टू क्रिएट अह हेवन ऑन
Meaning. so they support you for all celebration
अर्थ। सो दे सपोर्ट यू फॉर ऑल सेलिब्रेशन
Creativity All Songs Lyrics Everything
क्रिएटिविटी ऑल सॉन्ग्स लिरिक्स एवरीथिंग
is downloaded from the gandharva loka all
इज डाउनलोडेड फ्रॉम द गंधर्व लोका ऑल
Tunes That Come They Come From The Gandharva
ट्यून्स दैट कम दे दे कम फ्रॉम द गंधर्व
if you are an artist one gandharva will
इफ यू आर एन आर्टिस्ट वन गंधर्वा विल
Adopt you and will constantly give you
अडॉप्ट यू एंड विल कांस्टेंटली गिव यू
that's why we get a particular flare or
दैट्स व्हाई वी गेट अ पर्टिकुलर फ्लेयर ओर
particular style of writing or a
पर्टिकुलर स्टाइल ऑफ राइटिंग ओर अ
particular style of painting in a person
पर्टिकुलर स्टाइल ऑफ पेंटिंग इन अ पर्सन
it's not that he can't do it any other way but
इट्स नॉट दैट ही कांट डू इट एनी अदर वे बट
The Gandharva makes him do it that he becomes
द गंधर्व मेक्स हिम डू इट दैट वे बिकम्स
his signature style style you know what i
हि सिग्नेचर स्टाइल स्टाइल यू नो व्हाट आई
Mean what it is music or in art anyone
मीन वेदर इट इज़ म्यूजिक और इन आर्ट एनी
Any other form. so gandharvaaz are there to make
एनी अदर फॉर्म। सो गंधरवाज़ आर देयर टू मेक
Life on Earth is Heavenly and They Support You in
लाइफ ऑन अर्थ हेवनली एंड दे सपोर्ट यू इन
celebration extra extra above that is
सेलिब्रेशन एक्सेट्रा एक्सट्रा अबव दैट इज़
Yakshas And The From Yakshaka Of Kinaraaz V
यक्षक ऑफ किनाराज़ वी से यक्षस एंड द
Realms of your Ancestors and Masters
रेलम्स ऑफ योर एनसेेस्टर्स एंड मास्टर्स
Realms of Ancestors Masters End
रेलम्स ऑफ़ एनसेेस्टर्स मास्टर्स एंड
What the Western World Calls the Archangels
आर्केंजल्स व्हाट द वेस्टर्न वर्ल्ड कॉल्स
Archangels. I am not aware of the
आर्केंजल्स। आई एम नॉट अवेयर ऑफ़ द ऑफ़ द
Islamic Words For This. Ok. The Ark
इस्लामिक वर्ड्स फॉर दिस। ओके। द आर्क
Angels and Masters. so these are like
एंजिल एंड मास्टरर्स। सो दीज़ आर लाइक
Heading Huge Groups of
हेडिंग ह्यूज ग्रुप्स ऑफ़
Gandharvaaz. They guide and they let you know the delegate
गंधर्वाज़। दे गाइड एंड दे यू नो डेलीगेट
Work on Earth. The Leaders of the Girlfriends.
वर्क ऑन अर्थ। दे लीडर्स ऑफ़ द गर्लफ्रेंड।
The leaders of the lower realm. end arc
दे लीडर्स ऑफ ऑफ़ द लोअर रेलम। एंड आर्क
Angel Christopher, Arch Angel. Yes. Michael,
एंजल क्रिस्टोफर, आर्क एंजल। यस। माइकल,
Metatron, All of These. So, they are leading,
मेटाट्रोन, ऑल ऑफ़ दीज़। सो, दे आर लीडिंग,
they are leading and sending the ah down
दे आर लीडिंग एंड सेंडिंग द अह द लोअर
Dec. To help humanity again. what do
दिस। टू हेल्प ह्यूमैनिटी अगेन। व्हाट डू
We call it in Hinduism? yakshas yakshas
वी कॉल इट इन हिंदूज्म? यक्षास यक्षास
Kinaraaj and the Guru Tatva Comes from Here
किनाराज एंड द गुरु तत्व कम्स फ्रॉम हियर
and they all positive most of them are most
एंड दे ऑल पॉजिटिव मोस्ट ऑफ़ देम आर मोस्ट
of them are there is a there is a parallel
ऑफ़ देम आर देयर इज़ अ देयर इज़ अ पैरेलल
Negative Realm I will talk about right now
नेगेटिव रेलम आई विल टॉक अबाउट राइट नाउ
let me finish this first or so the yakshas
लेट मी फिनिश दिस फर्स्ट या सो द यक्षस
and it's an important straight away because
एंड इट्स एन इंपॉर्टेंट स्ट्रेट आर बिकॉज़
all are knowledge wisdom channels through this so if
ऑल आर नॉलेज विज़डम चैनल्स थ्रू दिस सो इफ
you are interested in bhagvat geeta for
यू आर इंटरेस्टेड इन भगवत गीता फॉर
Instance and you have a quest a sincere
इंस्टेंस एंड यू हैव अ क्वेस्ट अ सिंसियर
Quest to Study Adhyaksha and a Master
क्वेस्ट टू स्टडी अ यक्ष क्षा और अ मास्टर
And this master's realm all the ascended
और दिस मास्टर्स रेलम ऑल द असेंडेड
Masters are living here through them the knowledge
मास्टर्स आर लिविंग हियर थ्रू देम द नॉलेज
wisdom past experiences everything is
विज़डम पास्ट एक्सपीरियंसेस एवरीथिंग इज़
available here on earth you know so the channel
अवेलेबल हियर ऑन अर्थ यू नो सो दे चैनल
and through the Gandharvas and through directly
एंड थ्रू द गंधर्वज़ एंड थ्रू डायरेक्ट
Download from channel sometime about what we
चैनल सम टाइम अबाउट व्हाट वी से डाउनलोड
you go into meditation and you download and you
यू गो इन मेडिटेशन एंड यू डाउनलोड एंड यू
have dialogues and you write down something
हैव डायलॉग्स और यू राइट डाउन समथिंग
messages all of this happens from this
मैसेजेस ऑल ऑफ दिस हैप्पेंस फ्रॉम दिस
Relm. Above this is Devas. what we call
रेलम। अबव दिस इज़ देवास। व्हाट वी कॉल
Gods and Goddesses. the highest of the realm
गॉडस एंड गॉडेसेस। द हाईएस्ट ऑफ़ द रेलम
Beyond What Is Pure Consciousness.
बियनड व्हिच इज़ प्युअर कॉन्शियसनेस।
Alright? So, in these medicines you have all the medicines.
ऑलराइट? सो, इन द इन दवाज़ यू हैव ऑल दवाज़।
there are gods and goddesses that you can talk
अम गॉड्स एंड गॉडेसेस दैट यू कैन टॉक
About from any cultures of the world. Give
अबाउट फ्रॉम एनी कल्चरर्स ऑफ़ द वर्ल्ड। दे
Come in the strata. this is the highest
कम इन द स्ट्रेटा। दिस इज़ द हाईएस्ट
Shreeta Closes to the Pure Consciousness.
श्रेटा क्लोजेस टू द प्योर कॉन्शियसनेस।
Divine. Now on the lower side. Human's
परमात्मा। नाउ ऑन द लोअर साइड। ह्यूमन के
Ah above the human these Gandharvas, Yakshas and
अह अबव द ह्यूमन दिस गंधर्वास, यक्षस एंड
Devaz. Below the asuras are there immediately.
देवाज़। बिलो द असुरास आर देयर इमीडिएटली।
And they go parallel. that means the power of the
एंड दे गो पैरेलल। दैट मींस द पावर ऑफ़ द
The Gandharvas and the power of the Asuras is the
गंधर्वाज़ एंड द पावर ऑफ़ द असुराज़ इज़ द
Beans. There are asuras. so asuraz are like
सेम। देयर आर असुराज़। सो असुराज़ आर लाइक
what they call devils in the english
व्हाट दे कॉल डेविल्स इन द इंग्लिश
Western They Call Devils. give the bad
वेस्टर्न दे कॉल डेविल्स। दे द बैड
Spirits. Bad Spirits That Create Just
स्पिरिट्स। बैड स्पिरिट्स दैट क्रिएट जस्ट
The Way Gandhwas Help People to Create
द वे गंधवाज़ हेल्प पीपल टू क्रिएट
Positivity and Positive Creations. The
पॉजिटिविटी एंड पॉजिटिव क्रिएशंस। द
Devils help people to create chaos and
डेविल्स हेल्प पीपल टू क्रिएट केओस एंड
Confusion and War. Ok? so, how does one
कन्फ्यूजन एंड वॉर। ओके? सो, हाउ डज़ वन
Decide whether you've been guided by the devil or
डिसाइड वेदर यू बीन गाइडेड बाय अ डेविल ऑर
Buy a Gandharva? The mind is a barometer. If
बाय अ गंधर्वा? द माइंड इज़ अ बैरोमीटर। इफ
You are in a positive mind and uplifted
यू आर इन अ पॉजिटिव माइंड एंड अपलिफ्टेड
Mind and you are a seeker, you are in mantra japa
माइंड एंड यू अ साधक, यू आर इन मंत्र जपा
and you are conscious and aware of your
एंड यू आर कॉन्शियस एंड अवेयर ऑफ़ योर
actions and thoughts and everything, you
एक्शंस एंड थॉट्स एंड एव्रीथिंग, यू
Automatically connect to the higher level. If You
ऑटोमेटिकली कनेक्ट टू द हायर लेवल। इफ यू
are angry any time, even a good person can
आर एंग्री एनी टाइम, इवन अ गुड पर्सन कैन
Be angry any time. If You're Angry Anyone
बी एंग्री एनी टाइम। इफ यू एंग्री एनी
Time Allow Yourself to Breed Two Kinds
टाइम अलव योरसेल्फ टू ब्रीड टू टू काइंड
Of Marinette in that anger.
ऑफ मैरिनेट इन दैट एंगर।
and you will immediately get a four
और यू यू इमीडिएटली विल गेट अ फोर
Friends That Join Together and Start Talking
फ्रेंड्स दैट जॉइन टुगेदर एंड टॉक स्टार्ट
talking ill about the person about the issue and
टॉकिंग इल अबाउट द पर्सन अबाउट द इशू एंड
you know you are supported it by a lot of people
यू नो यू आर सपोर्ट इट बाइ अ लॉट ऑफ पीपल
that will take you further in another step off
दैट विल टेक यू फर्दर इन अनदर स्टेप ऑफ
that anger is always there so this support system
दैट एंगर ए्सेट्रा सो दिस सपोर्ट सिस्टम
that you get for causing negative chaos on
दैट यू गेट फॉर कॉजिंग नेगेटिव केओसिय ऑन
Earth is given by the asuras they embody
अर्थ इज़ गिवेन बाई द असुरास दे एम्बॉडी
Just Like Gandharvaas Embody Gandharva
जस्ट लाइक गंधर्वास एम्बॉडी गंधर्व
Connects to you when you want to do good
कनेक्ट्स टू यू व्हेन यू वांट टु डू गुड
Work Even If It's a Simple Thing
वर्क इवन इफ इफ इट्स फॉर अ सिंपल थिंग
like you want to party and you want to
लाइक यू वांट टू पार्टी और यू वांट टू
Create celebration at home. you get ideas
क्रिएट सेलिब्रेशन इन होम। यू गेट आइडियाज
From the Gandharvas. Even for Simple
फ्रॉम द गंधर्वज़। इवन फॉर सिंपल
Celebrations for ceremonies. are you married
सेलिब्रेशनंस फॉर सेरेमोनीज़। यू हैव मैरिड
Ceremony, birthday ceremony. Satyanarayana,
सेरेमनी, बर्थडे सेरेमनी। सत्यनारायण,
Putra and all the Gandharvas Gandharvas help you
पुत्र एंड ऑल द गंधर्व गंधर्वज़ हेल्प यू
To create heaven on earth. Similarily, the
टू क्रिएट हेवन ऑन अर्थ। सिमिलरली, द
Asuras help you to create hell on earth.
असुराज़ हेल्प यू टू क्रिएट हेल ऑन अर्थ।
There is a social media platform called
देयर इज़ अ सोशल मीडिया प्लेटफॉर्म कॉल्ड
Reddit. Reddit Contains Forums Related To
रेडिट। रेडिट कंटेन्सस फोरम्स रिलेटेड टू
Topics that are popular in culture. Hmm. Ahhh
टॉपिक्स दैट आर पॉपुलर इन कल्चर। हम्म। अह
and there is a there is an infinite number
एंड देयर इज़ अ देयर इज़ एन इनफाइनाइट नंबर
of forums on Reddit. there is a lot of that
ऑफ़ फोरम्स ऑन Redit। देयर इज़ अ लॉट दैट
Talk about culture positively and there is a
टॉक अबाउट कल्चर पॉजिटिवली एंड देयर इज़ अ
A lot of people talk about it negatively. let me sleep
लॉट दैट टॉक अबाउट इट नेगेटिवली। सो दे
will be one for bollywood, there will be one for
विल बी वन फॉर बॉलीवुड, देयर बी वन फॉर
Social media, there be one for the world of
सोशल मीडिया, देयर बी वन फॉर द वर्ल्ड ऑफ़
Cricket. hmm and of course the commonality in some
क्रिकेट। हम्म एंड ऑफन द कॉमनैलिटी इन सम
on these negative forums is, they approach
ऑन दीज़ नेगेटिव फोरम्स इज, दे अप्रोच
Almost every single topic negatively.
ऑलमोस्ट एव्री सिंगल टॉपिक नेगेटिवली।
Hmm, or. that's a fed that's there
हम्म, या। दैट्स दैट्स अ फेड दैट्स देयर
Work that's a religion. So on some level, the
वर्क दैट्स अ धर्म। सो ऑन सम लेवल, द
realm of the asuras is affecting all this
रेल्म ऑफ़ दी असुरास इज़ अफेक्टिंग ऑल दिस
Ficus religiosa. Of course they are supported guides. You
पीपल। ऑफ़ कोर्स दे आर सपोर्टेड गाइड। यू
no i have a it's important for me
नो आई ह्य हैड अ इट्स इम्पोर्टेन्ट फॉर मी
To give an example here if you permit me.
टु गिव एन एग्जांपल हियर इफ यू परमिट मी।
or I had a Filipino once to come to learn
या आई हैड अ फिलिपिनो वांस टू कम टू लर्न
with me. I do one on one learnings in the
विथ मी। आई डु वन ऑन वन लर्निंग्स इन द
Hermitage. i used to do more that before
हर्मिटेड। आई यूज्ड टु डु मोर डैट बिफोर
Now I have group online sessions happening
नाउ आई हैव ग्रुप ऑनलाइन सेशंस है हपेनिंग
And I do personal coaching now. Income Take Up
एंड आई डु पर्सनल कोचिंग्स नाउ। आय टेक अप
Coaching for Good People Who Want to
कोचिंग्स फॉर गुड पीपल हू वांट टू
Progress. So, I had this Filipina boy
प्रोग्रेस। सो, आई हैड दिस फिलिपिन अ बॉय
who came to study with me and he was in too
हु केम टू स्टडी विथ मी एंड ही वाज़ इन टू
Substance Abuse and Alcoholism and He
सब्सटेंस अब्यूज एंड अल्कोहलिज्म एंड ही
Says mother I don't event. so, he had a
सेज़ मां आई डोंट इवेंट। सो, ही हैड अ
Realization. he had a godly realization
रियलाइज़ेशन। ही हैड अ गॉडली रियलाइज़ेशन
because of which he just gave up everything
बिकॉज़ ऑफ़ व्हिच ही जस्ट गव अप एवरीथिंग
And He Went on a Personal Journey of Becoming
एंड ही वेंट ऑन अ पर्सनल जर्नी ऑफ़ बिकमिंग
A monk. you know it's a very dramatic story
अ मंक। यू नो अ वेरी ड्राटिकल स्टोरी ही
Head. but something that stayed with me in my
हैड। बट समथिंग दैट स्टेड विथ मी इन माय
Mind what he narrated to me. he said that
माइंड व्हाट ही नरेटेड टू मी। ही सेड डैट
every time i would take something if he is you
एव्री टाइम आई वुड टेक समथिंग इफ ही इज़ यू
no consuming anything he says that i would
नो कंस्यूमिंग समथिंग ही सेस ड्यात आई वुड
There are many dark forces behind me and them
सी मेनी डार्क फोर्सेस बिहाइंड मी एंड दे
would you like to put me with so much power
वुड एज़ इफ पुट मी विथ सो मच ऑफ़ पावर ही
Said I used to feel powerful. I used to
सेड आई यूज़्ड टू फील पावरफुल। आई यूज़्ड टू
Feel the Power of the Whole World Is With Me.
फील द पावर ऑफ़ द होल वर्ल्ड इज़ विथ मी।
And they would walk with me. Hee sez. i say the
एंड दे वुड वॉक विथ मी। ही सेज़। आई सेज़ द
The moment I would come out of my this thing and
मोमेंट आई वुड कम आउट ऑफ़ माई दिस थिंग एंड
I felt so powerless. I felt as if I
आई वुड फील सो पावरलेस। आई फेल्ट एज़ इफ आई
could not even stand and walk and things
कुड नॉट इवन स्टैंड एंड वॉक एंड थिंग्स
like that and when i was narrating to him
लाइक दैट एंड व्हेन आई वाज़ नरेटिंग टू हिम
This you know with the choice with the mind and with
दिस यू नो विथ द चॉइस विथ द माइंड एंड विद
Our awareness we can connect to each other the higher
आवर अवेयरनेस वी कैन कनेक्ट टू इदर द हायर
Or the lower it depends on us. so by the way v
ऑर द लोअर इट डिपेंड्स ऑन अस। सो वैसे वी
That he was giving me this example. So the
दैट ही वाज़ गिविंग मी दिस एग्जांपल। सो द
Asuras are parallel i mean as powerful as the
असुरास आर पैरेलल आई मीन एस पावरफुल एस द
Gandharvaaz and then you have just like the
गंधरवाज़ एंड देन यू हैव द जस्ट लाइक द
Yakshas you have ghosts. You know Bhootaaj ​​R Gan.
यक्षस यू हैव भूताज़। यू नो भूताज़ आर गण।
they're like just like the arc angels
दे आर लाइक जस्ट जस्ट लाइक द आर्क एंज्स
you know they are more powerful and they have gan
यू नो दे आर मोर पावरफुल एंड दे हैव गण
with them they have many asuras with them
विथ देम दे हैव मेनी असुरास विथ देम दे
have many people with them that they and so they
हैव मेनी पीपल विथ देम दैट दे एंड सो दे
Affect people who are in negative thoughts for a
अफेक्ट पीपल हु आर इन नेगेटिव थॉट फॉर अ
long time somebody who is in a negative thought
लॉन्ग टाइम समबडी हु इज़ इन अ नेगेटिव थॉट
pattern for a long time some form of
पैटर्न फॉर अ लॉन्ग टाइम सम फॉर्म ऑफ़
Depression and some negative thoughts
डिप्रेशन और सम दे सपोर्ट नेगेटिव थॉट
negative action on earth in their family in
नेगेटिव एक्शन ऑन अर्थ इन देयर फैमिली इन
their relationship they almost like became
देयर रिलेशनशिप दे ऑलमोस्ट लाइक बिकम
Devilish. The People Almost Like to Become Very
डेविलिश। द पीपल ऑलमोस्ट लाइक बिकम वेरी
Devilish. you know so there they are a pa source
डेविलिश। यू नो सो दे आर दे आर अ पा सोर्स
Of power to all negative activities. End
ऑफ़ पावर टू ऑल नेगेटिव एक्टिविटीज़। एंड
then the last of them at power with the gods
देन द लास्ट ऑफ़ देम एट पावर विथ द गॉड्स
Is a vampire. What the Western World Calls
इज़ पिशाच। व्हाट द वेस्टर्न वर्ल्ड कॉल्स
Vampires.
वैंपायर्स।
you know the vampire power is a very very huge
यू नो द पिशाच शक्ति इज़ अ वेरी वेरी ह्यूज
Power. It's a huge power. it's at par
शक्ति। इट्स अ ह्यूज शक्ति। इट्स एट पार
With God. that means it's like a portal of
विथ गॉड। दैट मींस इट्स लाइक अ पोर्टल ऑफ
Energy. Again negative energy. The Universe
एनर्जी। अगेन नेगेटिव एनर्जी। द यूनिवर्स
is equally divided between white and
इज़ इक्वली डिवाइडेड बिटवीन वाइट एंड
Black. It has to be. The game has to go on.
ब्लैक। इट हैज़ टू बी। द गेम हैज़ टू गो ऑन।
so the vampire power it's kind of
सो द पिशाच शक्ति इट इट्स काइंड ऑफ़
Almost like parasitic on someone. if it's
ऑलमोस्ट लाइक पैरासिटिक ऑन समवन। इफ इट इट
makes a person victim and to death it will
मेक्स अ पर्सन विक्टिम एंड टू डेथ इट विल
NOT LEAVE. it rises and it sucks out
नॉट लीव। इट रिसाइड्स एंड इट्स सक्कस आउट
Life. The Three Realms It is Said. that the
प्राणा। द थ्री रेलिम्स इट इज़ सेड। दैट द
the three realms do not have an independent
थ्री रेलम्स डू नॉट हैव अ इंडिपेंडेंट
Source of Prana in the Universe. They Thrive
सोर्स ऑफ़ प्राणा इन द यूनिवर्स। दे थ्राइव
and survive on the prana of living
एंड सर्वाइव ऑन द प्राणा ऑफ़ लिविंग
Beings. so they are all the time searching for
बीइंग्स। सो दे आर ऑल द टाइम सर्चिंग फॉर
someone to
समवन टू
Pylon as a source of energy speaking of the
पायलॉन एस सोर्स ऑफ एनर्जी स्पीकिंग ऑफ़ द
positive highest world you can say that is
पॉजिटिव हाईएस्ट वर्ल्ड यू सेड दैट दैट्स
dawlok dawaz or it wood contain elements of
दवलोक दवाज़ या इट वुड कंटेन एलिमेंट्स ऑफ़
hanuman ji all of our devas all of ours
हनुमान जी ऑल ऑफ़ आवर देवास ऑल ऑफ़ आवर
Dewas
देवास
So the vampire realm is as powerful as Dev Rathal
सो द पिशाच रल्म इज एज पावरफुल एस दव रथल
so these are negative gods yes yes they were
सो दीज़ आर नेगेटिव गॉड्स यस यस वेयर वुड
you play satan in this
यू प्ले सैटन इन दिस
Put it anywhere.
कहीं भी डाल दो।
in our culture who is an example of a
इन आवर कल्चर हु इज एन एग्जांपल ऑफ अ
Vampire? A lot of them are there? Asuras Have
पिशाच? अ लॉट ऑफ़ देम आर देयर? असुरास हैव
been mentioned in purana also we have had so
बीन मेंशंड इन पुराण आल्सो वी हैव हैड सो
many asuras that have been spoken a
मेनी असुरास दैट हैव बीन स्पोकन अ
mahishasura and you know i see those names
महिषासुर एंड यू नो आई व्यू दोज़ नेम्स
Give it quite differently. I find them all
क्वाइट डिफरेंटली दो। आई फाइंड देम ऑल
symbolic of
सिंबॉलिक ऑफ़
Some wrong trait in us. for example you
सम रोंग ट्रेट इन अस। फॉर फॉर इंस्टेंस यू
Have a Jambasur. jambasura is like when
हैव अ जांबासुर। जांबासुर इज़ लाइक व्हेन
You then say that the Jambhasura enters into
यू यन देन दे से द जांभासुर एंटर्स इंटू
Your Mouth and It Makes Your Body Very
योर माउथ एंड इट मेक्स योर बॉडी वेरी
Lazy. So the jambhai word is basically yanning.
लेजी। सो द जांभाई वर्ड इज़ बेसिकली यनिंग।
Many of these asura names are Krodhasur. You
मेनी ऑफ़ दीज़ असुरा नेम्स आर क्रोधासुर। यू
No they have all names associated with negative
नो दे हैव ऑल नेम्स एसोसिएटेड विथ नेगेटिव
Instincts in human beings. so however
वृत्तिज़ इन इन ह्यूमन बीइंग्स। सो हाउएवर
I do believe that ah these two forces are
आई आई डू बिलीव दैट अह दीज़ टू फोर्सेस आर
Coexisting.
कोइज़िस्टिंग।
They are existing as the negative and the
दे आर दे को एकिस्टिंग द नेगेटिव एंड द
Positive and One Must as a Human Being
पॉजिटिव एंड वन मस्ट एज अ ह्यूमन बीइंग
Always make a conscious choice to be in the
ऑलवेज मेक अ कॉन्शियस चॉइस टू बी इन द
higher realms in the above realms how can one
हायर रेलम्स इन द अबोव रेलम्स हाउ कैन वन
do it because you get angry everybody gets
डू इट बिकॉज़ यू गेट एंग्री एवरीबडी गेट्स
angry and irritated and depressed or you know
एंग्री और इरिटेटेड और डिप्रेस्ड ओर यू नो
frustrated this is an invitation for the asura
फ्रस्टेटेड दिस इज़ इनविटेशन फॉर द असुरा
The You Know Kingdom and the Lower Kingdom. So the
यू नो किंगडम एंड द लोअर किंगडम। सो द
The Moment You Catch Yourself Going Into Anyone
मोमेंट यू कैच योरसेल्फ गोइंग इन एनी
Variations of moods immediately start doing
वेरिएशन ऑफ मूड्स इमीडिएटली स्टार्ट डूइंग
Chanted. whatever japa you are doing even if you
जपा। व्हाटएवर जपा यू आर डूइंग इवन इफ यू
For the nay for the heck of it you say Om Namah
फॉर द ने फॉर द हेक ऑफ इट यू से ओम नमः
Shivaya Om Namah Shivaya Even If You Don't Mean It
शिवाय ओम नमः शिवाय इवन इफ यू डोंट मीन इट
it will still connect you to the realm above and
इट विल स्टिल कनेक्ट यू टू द रेलम अबव एंड
Not allowing you to fall down. you know these olden
नॉट अलाउ यू टू फॉल डाउन। यू नो इन ओल्डन
Times People Would Say If You See Something
टाइम्स पीपल वुड से इफ यू सी समथिंग
happening on the road something ah that
हप्पेनिंग ऑन द रोड अन समथिंग अह दैट दैट
one should not see may be some accident or
वन शुड नॉट सी मे बी सम एक्सीडेंट ओर
Anything. Ram Ram Ram Ram Ram Ram Ram Just Say
एनीथिंग। राम राम राम राम राम राम जस्ट से
that and move away people would advise the
दैट एंड मूव अवे पीपल वुड एडवाइस द
Elders who would advise the children just say
एल्डर्स हु वुड एडवाइस द चिल्ड्रन जस्ट से
Ram Ram Ram Ram and move away so don't want
राम राम राम राम एंड मूव अवे सो डोंट वांट
even a visual
इवन अ विजुअल
take a taking us down there you know it
टेक अ टेकिंग अस डाउन देयर यू नो इट्स
like that's so the name of god and and you know
लाइक दैट सो नेम ऑफ गॉड एंड एंड यू नो
chanting chanting namsmaran inside in
चैंटिंग चैंटिंग नामस्मरण इनसाइड इन
Itself is a powerful tool that will take you
इटसेल्फ इज़ अ पावरफुल टूल दैट विल टेक यू
in connection with the higher realms this is
इन कनेक्शन विथ द हायर रेलिम्स दिस इज़
Why a Lot of People Talk About High
व्हाई अ लॉट ऑफ़ पीपल टॉक अबाउट हाई
Frequency Conversion High Versus Low
फ्रीक्वेंसी सी कन्वर्सेशन वर्सेस लो
frequency absolutely yes it's the same
फ्रीक्वेंसी अब्सोलुटली यस इट्स द सेम
thing it's the same thing and lo
थिंग इट्स अ सेम सेम थिंग एंड लो
Frequency need not always be cheap and
फ्रीक्वेंसी नीड नॉट ऑलवेज बी चीप और
dirty it could be even something as simple as
डर्टी इट कुड बी इवन समथिंग एस सिंपल एस
Fear Fear is a Very Innocent Thing Can
फियर फियर इज अ वैरी इनोसेंट थिंग कैन
Grip Anybody But It's Bad
ग्रिप एनीबडी बट इट्स बैड
you know or gossip or gossip gossip fear gossip
यू नो या गॉसिप या गॉसिप गॉसिप फियर गॉसिप
and unnecessary defaming someone you know
एंड अननेसेसरी डिफेमिंग समवन यू नो फमिंग
someones name and just talking for talking
समवनस नेम और जस्ट टॉकिंग फॉर फॉर टॉकिंग
Sake about someone, someone, someone? it's
सेक अबाउट समवन, समवन, समवन? इट्स
Absolutely a low frequency talk. Ok?
अब्सोल्युटली अ लो फ्रीक्वेंसी टॉक। ओके?
Hmm. let's get to high frequency
हम्म। लेट्स गेट टू हाई फ्रीक्वेंसी
Talk. Spoke about Chinasta. Then We Spoke
टॉक। स्पोक अबाउट चिनस्ता। देन वी स्पोक
About Bhairav. Bhairavi. After Bhairavi Is
अबाउट भैरव। भैरवी। आफ्टर भैरवी इज़
Bhuvaneshwari. so she is ruling the entire
भुवनेश्वरी। सो शी इज़ रूलिंग द एंटायर
Sky. She is ruling the entire sky. End
स्काई। शी इज़ रूलिंग द एंटायर स्काई। एंड
there she is manifesting here on earth
देयरफ़ शी इज़ मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग हियर ऑन अर्थ
What Kali, Tara and Shodashi are
व्हाट काली, तारा एंड शोडशी आर
Manifesting in the Hiranyagarbha.
मैनिफ़ेस्टिंग इन द हिरण्यगर्भ।
that means they are planning they are
दैट मींस दे आर प्लानिंग दे आर
Manifesting She Is Actually Grossing
मैनिफेस्टिंग शी इज एक्चुअली ग्रॉसिंग
Grossifying it here making it a reality
ग्रॉसिफाइंग इट हियर मेकिंग इट अ रियलिटी
here on the earth so bhuvaneshwari is ofon
हियर ऑन द अर्थ सो भुवनेश्वरी इज़ ऑफन
Worshipped for Glory Richness Glory
वरशिप्ड फॉर ग्लोरी रिचनेस ग्लोरी
Enhancement in Business Weddings and
एनहांसमेंट इन बिज़नेस वेडिंग्स एंड
Relationships Fertility Child Fertility
रिलेशनशिप्स फर्टिलिटी चाइल्ड फर्टिलिटी
you know all the good things about house hold
यू नो ऑल द गुड थिंग्स अबाउट हाउस होल्ड
Life Society Life Bhuvaneshwari Gives You
लाइफ सोसाइटी लाइफ भुवनेश्वरी गिव्स यू यू
all the abundance what word we use abundance
ऑल द अबंडेंस व्हाट वर्ड वी यूज़ अबंडेंस
in all senses richness the word abundance means
इन ऑल सेंस रिचनेस द वर्ड अबंडेंस मींस
Richness in all senses 360 degree of richness
रिचनेस इन ऑल सेंस 360 डिग्री ऑफ़ रिचनेस
in every sense ok different from
इन एव्री सेंस ओके डिफरेंट फ्रॉम
Kamalatmika or She is different from
कमलात्मिका या शी इज़ डिफरेंट फ्रॉम
Kamalatmika more blessings and and this is
कमलात्मिका मोर ब्लेस्डनेस एंड एंड दिस इज़
more like early hum it is as sel this is
मोर लाइक अर्ली हम इट इज़ वै सल दिस इज़
very early more approachable lakshmi is more
वैरी अर्ली मोर अप्रोचेबल लक्ष्मी इस मोर
approachable that's why she is more famous
अप्रोचेबल दैट्स व्हाई शी मोर फेमस
wow who praises
वाओ हु प्रेज़
So okay we are talking about Bhuvaneshwari?
टू ओके वी आर टॉकिंग अबाउट भुवनेश्वरी?
Yes. who praises tuvaneshwari in north india
हां। हु प्रेज़ टुवनेश्वरी इन नॉर्थ इंडिया
I have seen much of a faith with her butt in the South
आई हैव सीन मच ऑफ़ अ फेथ विद हर बट इन साउथ
india there are many others you have lots of
इंडिया दे आर मेनी अदर यू हैव लॉट ऑफ़
Bhuvaneshwari Temples in South. north india
भुवनेश्वरी टेंपल्स इन साउथ। नार्थ इंडिया
She isn't even known. not many people the common
शी इज़ंट इवन नोन। नॉट मेनी पीपल द कॉमन
Folk. They don't even know the world Bhuvaneshwari?
फोक। दे डोंट इवन नो द वर्ल्ड भुवनेश्वरी?
Should we be stopping the conversation here? And
शुड वी बी स्टॉपिंग द कन्वर्सेशन हियर? और
should we elongate on tara kali maa and
शुड वी एलबोरेट ऑन तारा काली मां एंड
Trishurishi Tripura Sundari.
त्रिशुरीशि त्रिपुर सुंदरी।
or we can so that we do justice to this
या वी कैन सो दैट वी डू जस्टिस टू दिस
talk very briefly speaking about there the
टॉक वेरी ब्रीफली स्पीकिंग अबाउट देयर द
Rulers of the Gunas especially the Shodashi Shi
रूलर्स ऑफ़ द गुनाज़ एस्पेशली द शोडशी शी
has become more famous and Tara has gone more
हैज़ बिकम मोर फेमस एंड तारा हैज़ गॉन मोर
to orient to the Buddhist culture why
टू द ओरिएंट टू द बुद्धिस्ट कल्चर व्हाई
it's just i think something historical
इट्स जस्ट आई थिंक सम हिस्टोरिकल
Geographical reason for which Buddhism had come
ज्योग्राफिकल रीज़न फॉर इट बुद्धिजम हैड कम
into india and you know and then they developed
इंटू इंडिया एंड यू नो एंड देन दे डेवलप्ड
it's not that there is no work done there it
इट्स नॉट दैट देयर इज़ नो वर्क डन देर इट्स
not like that the buddhist saints end
नॉट लाइक दैट द बुद्धिस्ट सेंट्स एंड
Sears
सीियर्स
have worked a lot on done a lot of sadhna on
हैव वर्क्ड अ लॉट ऑन डन अ लॉट ऑफ़ साधना ऑन
Tara and Tantra has as a separate wing of
तारा एंड तंत्रा हैज़ एज़ अ सेपरेट विंग ऑफ़
practice has developed over there with the
प्रैक्टिस हैज़ डेवलप्ड ओवर देयर विथ द
Tara Cult is here in India we have
तारा कल्ट इन इन हियर इन इंडिया वी हैव
Ugratara and Saumya Tara Worshipped Ugratara
उग्रतारा एंड सौम्य तारा वरशिप्ड उग्रतारा
And the saumya tara the ugratara is a very
एंड सौम्य तारा द उग्रतारा इज़ अ वेरी
Fiery version of Kali's you know they say that
फायरी वर्जन ऑफ़ काली का यू नो दे से दैट
Kali is transcended so you are there in
काली इज़ ट्रांसेंडेड सो यू आर देयर इन
Consciousness but Tara is transcending that
कॉन्शियसनेस बट तारा इज़ ट्रांसेंडिंग दैट
Means she is very helpful for you to go to tech
मीन शी इज़ वेरी हेल्पफुल फॉर यू टू गो टेक
You into the higher this thing. So Tara Worship
यू इंटू द हायर दिस थिंग। सो तारा वरशिप
is really very especially in the East and the
इज़ रियली वेरी एस्पेशली इन द ईस्ट एंड द
North East there is a lot of Tara worship
नॉर्थ ईस्ट देयर इज़ अ लॉट ऑफ़ तारा वरशिप
Still going on. we have the tarapith you know
स्टिल गोइंग ऑन। वी हैव द तारापीठ यू नो
Above West Bengal in West Bengal Kolkata.
अबव वेस्ट बंगाल इन वेस्ट बंगाल कोलकाता।
Tarapitha is very famous. It's very nice.
तारापीठ इज़ वेरी फेमस। इट्स वेरी नाइस।
Fiery Tara is worship there. The Gentle Tara Haze
उग्र तारा इज़ वरशिप देयर। सौम्य तारा हैज़
Gone more to Buddhist. I feel it. Ah The One
गॉन मोर टू बुद्धिस्ट। आई फील। अह द वन
Sitting on the Lotus you know the white color Tara.
सिटींग ऑन द लोटस यू नो द वाइट कलर तारा।
She depicts education in Saraswati. she is a
शी डिपेक्ट्स एजुकेशन इन सरस्वती। शी इज़ अ
Tantrik Saraswati. even matangi is a
तांत्रिक सरस्वती। इवन मातंगी इज़ अ
Tantrik Saraswati. The Lower. she is because of
तांत्रिक सरस्वती। द लोअर। शी इज़ बिकॉज़ ऑफ़
Arts, all the arts. This one is more white.
आर्ट्स, ऑल द आर्ट्स। दिस वन इज़ मोर वाइट।
Tara is more white because she opens up
तारा इज़ मोर वाइट बिकॉज़ अह शी ओपन्स
Wisdom. and opens the direction, the right
विज़डम। एंड ओपन्स द डायरेक्शन, द राइट
Steps That You Want to Take in
स्टेप्स दैट यू वांट टू टेक इन
Life. The misunderstanding that people often
लाइफ। द मिसअंडरस्टैंडिंग दैट पीपल ऑफेन
get out of these goddesses is ah out of all the
गेट आउट ऑफ़ दिस देवीज़ इज़ अह आउट ऑफ़ ऑल द
Sadhnaaz. is their mind automatic the condition
साधनाज़। इज़ देयर माइंड ऑटोमेटिक द कंडीशन
The mind automatically goes towards the practical
माइंड ऑटोमेटिकली गोज़ टुवर्ड्स प्रैक्टिकल
Applications in their work and in their
एप्लीकेशन्स इन देयर वर्क एंड इन देयर
Material side. which is not what they are
मटेरियल साइड। व्हिच इज नॉट व्हाट दे आर
made for they are there and that's something
मेड फॉर दे आर देयर देयर एंड दैट्स समथिंग
that you automatically get you don't need to ask
दैट यू ऑटोमेटिकली गेट यू नीड नॉट आस्क
it's something that you will automatically get
इट्स समथिंग दैट यू विल ऑटोमेटिकली गेट यू
need not ask but the focus is being there
नीड नॉट आस्क बट द फोकस बीइंग देयर
Reduces the effect of the blessings we receive
रिड्यूसेस द इफेक्ट ऑफ द ब्लेसिंग्स हम द
the focus should be to embrace
फोकस शुड बी टू एम्ब्रेस
Devi Obviously If the Devi is there is the source
दवी ऑब्वियसली इफ द देवी इज़ देयर द सोर्स
of energy is there you will get everything you
ऑफ एनर्जी इज़ देयर यू विल गेट एवरीथिंग यू
if you say i want to be friend the sun is the
इफ यू से आई वांट टू बी फ्रेंड द सन इज द
The sun is going to be your friend without his rage
सन गोइंग टू बी फ्रेंड यू विदाउट हिज रेज
it is said the glory of the goddess comes to
इट्स इट्स सेड द ग्लोरी ऑफ़ द देवी कम्स टू
You automatically when you become friend with the other one. So
यू ऑटोमेटिकली व्हेन यू बी फ्रेंड दवी। सो
The Focus Is The Take Away From This Podcast
द फोकस इज़ द टेक अवे फ्रॉम दिस पॉडकास्ट
Probably we are me sitting here. thats the love
प्रॉबब्ली वी आर मी सिटींग हियर। दैट द लव
For the goddess is an important aspect
फॉर द गॉडेस इज़ एन इंपॉर्टेंट एस्पेक्ट
That should not be missed out. and focus on
दैट शुड नॉट बी मिस्ड आउट। एंड फोकस ऑन
Siddhis. Focus on Blessings and Focus on
सिद्धिस। फोकस ऑन ब्लेसिंग्स एंड फोकस ऑन
The by products of this blessing. shud
द बाइ प्रोडक्ट्स ऑफ दिस ब्लेसिंग। शुड
Not be focused on. it will you will get that
नॉट बी फोकस्ड ऑन। इट विल यू विल गेट देट
Automatically. you know who really want to
ऑटोमेटिकली। यू नो दोज़ हु रियली वांट टू
worship and they want to experience the goddess
वरशिप एंड दे वांट टू एक्सपीरियंस दवी
Increase your love and seeking for the Goddess
इंक्रीस योर लव एंड सीकिंग फॉर द देवी फॉर
every sec rather than for this sec and that sec
हर सेक रादर देन फॉर दिस सेक एंड दैट सेक
which will automatically come and then black
व्हिच विल ऑटोमेटिकली कम एंड एंड देन काली
The Dark She Is All of Us No You Know
द डार्क शी इज़ ऑल ऑफ ऑल ऑफ़ अस नो यू नो
ramakrishna paramahansa is there so many other kali
रामकृष्ण परमहंस इस देयर सो मेनी अदर काली
Sadhakkas are there ocean of love and compassion she
साधक्कस आर देयर ओशन ऑफ़ लव एंड कंपैशन शी
annihilates everything she finishes the ego
एनहिलेट्स एव्रीथिंग शी फिनिशेस द ईगो
Completely so Kali Bhakti is done real Kali
कंप्लीटली सो काली भक्ति इज़ डन रियल काली
Bhakti is done by sadhak who does who really
भक्ति इज़ डन बाय साधक हु दोज़ हु रियली
want to finish there
वांट टू फिनिश देयर
Ego She She Completely
ईगो शी शी कंप्लीटली
you know it takes you into a transcendence
यू नो इट टेक्स यू इनू अ ट्रांसेंडेड
state of samadhi she samadhi you can say that
स्टेट ऑफ समाधि शी समाधि यू कैन से दैट
Dharana Dhyan Samadhi Dayam That We Spoke About
धारणा ध्यान समाधि दयम दैट वी स्पोक अबाउट
In ten Dharana Dhyana and Samadhi these three
इन दस धारणा ध्यान एंड समाधि दीज़ थ्री
people are capable of
पीपल आर कैपेबल ऑफ़
The three goddesses are capable of doing
डूइंग द थ्री देवीज़ आर कैपेबल ऑफ़ डूइंग
Fair to say that Kali Sadhna works the
फेयर टू से दैट काली साधना वर्क्स द
Fastest in terms of the yes because she is
फास्टेस्ट इन टर्म्स ऑफ़ द यस बिकॉज़ शी शी
is the most your choice doesn't happen people are
इज़ द मोस्ट योर चॉइस डजंट हैपन पीपल आर वै
Scared to Choose Kali
स्केर्ड टू चूज़ काली
sadhana she chooses you she chooses you she will choose you
साधना शी चूज़ यू शी चूज़ यू शी विल चूज़ यू
and it is the fastest because it is the
एंड इट इज़ द फास्टेस्ट बिकॉज़ इट इज़ द
The purest it is. she's gotta know
परेस्ट इट इज़ द प्यरेस्ट। शीज़ गॉट नो
The Conditioning Other Goddesses Have
कंडीशनिंग अदर अदर देवीज़ हैव
Covers. she is covering has been layers of
आवरणस। शी इज़ आवरण हैज़ बीन लेयर्स ऑफ़
Personality Like You Know The Different Chakra
पर्सनालिटी लाइक यू नो द डिफरेंट चक्रा
Personalities As We Speak. but kali is is
पर्सनालिटीज़ एज़ वी स्पोक। बट काली इज इज
Absolutely Nude She Is Unconditioned
अब्सोलुटली न्यूड शी शी इज़ अनकंडीशन
Completely unconditioned she is no cover raw
कंप्लीटली अनकंडीशन शी इज़ नो आवरण रॉ
Energy Raw Energy
एनर्जी रॉ एनर्जी
on what basis does she choose the seeker on the
ऑन व्हाट बेसिस डस शी चूज़ द साधक ऑन द
Basis of your past deeds and past sadhana
बेसिस ऑफ योर पास्ट डीड्स एंड पास्ट साधना
If you've been on a tumultuous path and a
इफ यू हैव बीन ऑन अ टुमल्टस पाथ एंड अ
Steady
स्टेडी
Relentless Known Dying Path She Has Merse and
रिलेंटलेस नोन डाइंग पाथ शी हैस मर्स एंड
she will pick you up
शी विल पिक यू अप
we once hosted someone on the show who was a
वी वंस होस्टेड समवन ऑन द शो हु वास अ
descendants of the
डिसेंडेंट ऑफ द
line of pandits who perform pujas at the
लाइन ऑफ पंडित्स हु परफॉर्म पूजाज एट द
Pashupatinath Temple in Nepal Oh How Amazing
पशुपतिनाथ टेंपल इन नेपाल ओह हाउ अमेजिंग
Incredible Conversation About Shiva And
इनक्रेडिबल कन्वर्सेशन अबाउट शिवा एंड
Rudraksh actually i am not even asking you
रुद्राक्ष एक्चुअली आई एम नॉट इवन आस्क यू
about the garland that you are wearing yes this
अबाउट द माला दैट यू आर वेयरिंग हां दिस
is it called siddha mala it has all the
इज इट्स कॉल्ड सिद्ध माला इट हैज़ ऑल द
you know the faces of the rudraksha you always wear
यू नो फेसेस ऑफ़ द रुद्राक्ष यू ऑलवेज वेयर
this most of the time ok or
दिस मोस्ट ऑफ द टाइम ओके या
that person told me that usually with people
दैट पर्सन टोल्ड मी दैट यूजुअली विथ पीपल
who and up choosing the bhairav ​​path have a
हु एंड अप चूजिंग द भैरव पाथ हैव अ
The Tendency Towards Being
टेंडेंसी टुवर्ड्स बीइंग
destructive could have been in the
डिस्ट्रक्टिव कुड हैव इन द
the past could have been in the past it's a very
पास्ट कुड हैव बीन इन द पास्ट इट्स अ वेरी
Femme Familarity We Call It
फेमि फेमिलैरिटी वी कॉल इट
Familiarity and so that the goddess attracts
फेमिलैरिटी एंड सो दैट गॉडेस अट्रैक्ट्स
you know but benovelence is late with all the
यू नो बट ब्नोवेलेंस इस देर विथ अल द
Goddesses
गॉडेसेस
And She Will Benevolently Transform Even
एंड शी विल बेनोवेलेंटली ट्रांसफॉर्म इवन
that past unconscious is completely washed away
दैट पास्ट अनकॉन्शियस इज कंप्लीटली वाश्ड
of in goddess
ऑफ इन देवी
Devotion of All the People You Come Across in Your
भक्ति ऑफ ऑल द पीपल यू कम अक्रॉस इन योर
on life how do you know that someone is
ओन लाइफ हाउ डू यू नो दैट समवन इज
Likelear Two Step Inu Kali
लाइकलियर टू स्टेप इनू काली
upasana what do you see different about that
उपासना व्हाट डू यू सी डिफरेंट अबाउट दैट
Person
पर्सन
it gets known and it's kind of you
पता चल जाता है एंड इट्स इट्स काइंड ऑफ यू
Know it kind of says energy speaks when
नो इट काइंड ऑफ़ सेज़ एनर्जी स्पीक्स व्हेन
You Work With Energy Energy G Speaks
यू वर्क विथ एनर्जी एनर्जी जी स्पीक्स
There's a voice in your head that tells you.
देयर इज़ अ वॉइस इन योर हेड दैट टेल्स यू।
so, there isn't anyone
सो, देयर आरंट एनी
Physical Am Symptoms. so to say of kali
फिजिकल अम सिम्प्टम्स। सो टू से ऑफ़ काली
devotion but certainly an energy the person
भक्ति बट सटनली एन एनर्जी द एन पर्सन
Energy Wood Speak. for shore those who are getting
एनर्जी वुड स्पीक। फॉर शोर दोज़ हु आर गेट
attracted to kalibhakti or kali
अट्रैक्टेड ड्रॉन टू कालीभक्ति ऑर काली
Pick them up. They are at the epitome of
पिक्स देम अप। दे आर एट द एपिट्रोम ऑफ़
you know kind of de destroying all the
यू नो काइंड ऑफ़ डी डिस्ट्रक्टिंग ऑल द
Conditioning of the World. they are like in a
कंडीशनिंग ऑफ़ द वर्ल्ड। दे आर लाइक इन अ
in a crying mode of bhakti most of the
इन अ क्राइंग मोड ऑफ भक्ति मोस्ट ऑफ दी
have you understood that this is human life that
हैव अंडरस्टुड दैट हे दिस ह्यूमन लाइफ दैट
we know fully conditioned is redundant its
वी नो फुल्ली कंडीशंड इज़ रिडंडेंट इट्स
futile it's all drama and it's all a
फूटाइल इट्स ऑल ड्रामा एंड इट्स ऑल अ
waste of time
वेस्ट ऑफ टाइम
[Laughter]
[हंसी]
Great point to end this episode
ग्रेट पॉइंट टू एंड दिस एपिसोड
Thank you so much Ranveer and I am going
थैंक यू सो मच रणवीर एंड आई आई एम गोइंग
to see you again and again and again i am
टू सी यू अगेन एंड अगेन एंड अगेन आई एम
Going to See Your Audience Again and Again and Again
गोइंग सी योर ऑडियंस अगेन एंड अगेन एंड
again thank you so many lots of love light peace
अगेन थैंक यू सो मच लॉट्स ऑफ लव लाइट पीस
Happiness, Joy and Abundance are Imagable to All
हैप्पीनेस जॉय एंड अबंडेंस इमेजरेबल टू ऑल
Of you. Thank you ma'am. means a lot one last
ऑफ यू। थैंक यू मैम। मीन्स अ लॉट वन लास्ट
request ok and immediately after you are
रिक्वेस्ट ओके एंड इमीडीएटली आफ्टर यू आर
done with what i ask you for we will end
डन विथ व्हाट आई आस्क यू फॉर वी विल एंड
The Episode. but one signing of mantra
दी एपिसोड। बट वन साइनिंग ऑफ़ मंत्र
because i know my guess and i know the way the
बिकॉज़ आई नो माय गेस एंड आई नो द वे दी
The audience is perceiving you. so if you could
ऑडियंस इज़ पर्सिविंग यू। सो इफ यू कुड
just give them one gift ah which they can
जस्ट गिव देम वन गिफ्ट अह व्हिच दे कैन
Play to Themselves. Ok.
प्ले टू देमसेल्व्स। ओके।
Shri Varchasam Ayusham Arogyam Vidhaat Manam
श्री वर्चसम आयुषम आरोग्यम विधात मानम
Mahte Dhanam Dhanyam Pashum Bahu Putra Labham
महते धनम धान्यम पशुम बहु पुत्र लाभम
Shatasvatsaram long life, disease, poverty etc.
शतसवत्सरम दीर्घम आयु ऋण रोग आदि दरिद्र
sin, immortality, fear, grief, mental restlessness, fear
पापक्ष अपमृत्य भय शोक मनस्थापान नंतु मम
Sarvada Ya and Veda Om Mahadev Cha Vidmahe
सर्वदा य एवं वेद ओम महादेव च विद्महे
Vishnu's wife Cha Dhimahi Tanno Lakshmi
विष्णु पत्नी च धीमहि तन्नो लक्ष्मी
Prachodayat Om Shanti
प्रचोदयात ओम शांति
Thank you ma'am. Thank you. that was the episode
थैंक यू मैम। थैंक यू। दैट वास द एपिसोड
For today. Ladies and gentlemen. This
फॉर टुडे। लेडीज एंड जेंटलमैन। दिस
A particular episode was recorded while
पर्टिकुलर एपिसोड वाज़ रिकॉर्डेड अ वाइल
Ego. we have recently recorded one after
एगो। वी हैव रिसेंटली रिकॉर्डेड वन आफ्टर
The Events That Took Place Over the Last Three
द इवेंट्स दैट टूक प्लेस ओवर द लास्ट थ्री
Two four months. Watch out for that episode of Us
टू फोर मंथ्स। वॉच आउट फॉर दैट एपिसोड अस
well. tell us what you feel about all the
वेल। टेल अस व्हाट यू फील अबाउट आल दी
Spiritual Episodes That We Have Been
स्पिरिचुअल एपिसोड्स, दैट वी हैव बीन
Releasing Lately. help us build the
रिलीजिंग लेटली। हेल्प अस बिल्ड द
Podcast Even Better. because this kind of
पॉडकास्ट इवन बेटर। बिकॉज़ दीज़ काइंड ऑफ़
Conversations don't feel like work for me.
कन्वर्सेशन डोंट फील लाइक वर्क फॉर मी।
these are my own genuine questions coming
दीज़ आर माय ओन जेन्युइन क्वेश्चंस कमिंग
out of a place of genuine spiritual
आउट ऑफ अ प्लेस ऑफ़ जेन्युइन स्पिरिचुअल
Inquiry. I would love to know how I can
इंक्वायरी। आई वुड लव टू नो हाउ आई कैन
Improve the experience for you all. Thank you
इंप्रूव द एक्सपीरियंस फॉर यू ऑल। थैंक यू
For listening in. Mother Gnana Subira TRS
फॉर लिसनिंग इन। मां ज्ञान सुबीरा टीआरएस
And the whole team will be back very soon.
एंड द होल टीम विल बी बैक वेरी सून।
[music]
[संगीत]
yes
हो